<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:itunes="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title>Apologetics.com Radio Show</title>
        <link>http://www.apologetics.com</link>
        <description>Challenging believers to think, and thinkers to believe.</description>
        <generator>Feeder 4.3.2(5732); Mac OS X Version 15.0.1 (Build 24A348) https://reinventedsoftware.com/feeder/</generator>
        <docs>http://blogs.law.harvard.edu/tech/rss</docs>
        <language>en-us</language>
        <copyright>Copyright 2021 Apologetics.com, Inc.</copyright>
        <pubDate>Tue, 19 Nov 2024 00:24:23 -0800</pubDate>
        <lastBuildDate>Tue, 19 Nov 2024 00:24:23 -0800</lastBuildDate>
        <image>
            <url>http://apologetics.com/podcast/ADCRadioImage144.jpg</url>
            <title>Apologetics.com Radio Show</title>
            <link>http://www.apologetics.com</link>
            <width>144</width>
            <height>144</height>
        </image>
        <atom:link href="http://www.apologetics.com/podcast/Apologetics.comWeeklyRadioShow.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
        <itunes:author>Harry Edwards, Jason Gallagher, Jonathan Noyes and Leslie Wickman</itunes:author>
        <itunes:subtitle>Challenging believers to think and thinkers to believe.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:summary>The mission of Apologetics.com is to provide cutting-edge resources and training in Christian apologetics to the public through our website and related activities. Challenging believers to think and thinkers to believe.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:image href="http://www.apologetics.com/podcast/adcshowgraphic.png"/>
        <itunes:explicit>false</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:owner>
            <itunes:name>Harry Edwards</itunes:name>
            <itunes:email>harry@apologetics.com</itunes:email>
        </itunes:owner>
        <itunes:keywords>apologetics,truth,christianity,god,faith,Theology,beauty,Jesus,Defense of the Faith,philosophy,goodness,culture,church,Kalam,Biola</itunes:keywords>
        <itunes:category text="Education"/>
        <itunes:type>episodic</itunes:type>
        <item>
            <title>Presidential Providence and the Trump Re-election</title>
            <link>http://www.apologetics.com</link>
            <description><![CDATA[Join host Jason Gallagher as he and author/apologist Mike D’Virgilio discuss Trump’s re-election in the context of God’s providential hand over human affairs. We also unpack Mike’s recent book “Going Back to Find the Way Forward: Trump, A Great Awakening, and the Refounding of America”. Don’t miss this timely conversation on the “red pilling” of America, Babel and the globalist agenda, God’s providence and the great evangelistic and apologetic opportunity that we are in right now. As always, share this with your friends and email feedback to jason@apologetics.com. Grace and peace.]]></description>
            <pubDate>Tue, 19 Nov 2024 00:24:20 -0800</pubDate>
            <enclosure url="https://feeds.soundcloud.com/stream/1961758527-apologeticspodcast-presidential-providence-and-the-trump-re-election.mp3" length="55639461" type="audio/mpeg"/>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2D18E40A-A52B-4AB1-B467-657E9FDA201B</guid>
            <itunes:duration>3477</itunes:duration>
            <itunes:episodeType>full</itunes:episodeType>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>God's Goodness in the Presence of Evil</title>
            <link>https://apologetics.com/god-is-good/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[On this episode of the Apolofetics.com Radio Show, Dr. Harry Edwards leads a discussion on some of the topics found in Matthew Tingblad’s new book titled “Why Did God Do That? Discovering God’s Goodness in the Hard Passages of Scripture.” Joining him in the studio are Matthew Tingblad, author and speaker at Josh McDowell Ministries and Lenny Esposito, founder and president of Come Reason Ministries. In his book, Tingblad claims that many times we fail to see God’s goodness when we discuss issues of theodicy. So how is God’s goodness and providence affirmed in view of the existence of evil? Listen and watch as this group of apologists tackle this question and other related topics.]]></description>
            <pubDate>Mon, 18 Nov 2024 11:25:11 -0800</pubDate>
            <enclosure url="https://feeds.soundcloud.com/stream/1961339903-apologeticspodcast-gods-goodness-in-the-presence-of-evil.mp3" length="128283840" type="audio/mpeg"/>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">E4E4CBCC-1897-4B71-A1A8-BAB2D7BA5636</guid>
            <itunes:duration>3207</itunes:duration>
            <itunes:episodeType>full</itunes:episodeType>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Is it OK for Christians to Celebrate Halloween?</title>
            <link>https://apologetics.com/halloween/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[We’re told that Halloween has demonic origins, a Druid tradition that celebrates evil. But is this true? How are Christians to think about this holiday for which Americans spend billions of dollars? Is it ok to wear a costume, go around the neighborhood trick or treating? Are there “Christian alternatives” to this? Watch as Dr. Harry Edwards, together with Lenny Esposito and Dr. Jacob Daniel, discuss the question: Is it ok for Christians to celebrate Halloween.]]></description>
            <pubDate>Thu, 14 Nov 2024 01:34:59 -0800</pubDate>
            <enclosure url="https://feeds.soundcloud.com/stream/1957931299-apologeticspodcast-is-it-ok-for-christians-to-celebrate-halloween.mp3" length="130354560" type="audio/mpeg"/>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">B5ED21DC-E900-4350-9101-09DB0A91085F</guid>
            <itunes:duration>3258</itunes:duration>
            <itunes:episodeType>full</itunes:episodeType>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>The Exclusivity of Christ</title>
            <link>https://apologetics.com/exclusivity/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[On this episode of the Apologetics.com Radio Show Jon takes on the issue of the exclusivity of Christ. One of the most controversial things you can say today out in the marketplace of ideas is that the only way to God is through Jesus. Often that claim is met with scorn, ridicule, and name-calling. How do we Christians defend the exclusivity of Jesus while also showing why? Listen and learn how we can be better ambassadors for Christ.]]></description>
            <pubDate>Mon, 14 Oct 2024 21:14:44 -0700</pubDate>
            <enclosure url="https://feeds.soundcloud.com/stream/1935057341-apologeticspodcast-the-exclusivity-of-christ.mp3" length="138691503" type="audio/mpeg"/>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">747F6A6E-674B-4093-80D9-1C963B310CD9</guid>
            <itunes:duration>3467</itunes:duration>
            <itunes:episodeType>full</itunes:episodeType>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Christian Contentment</title>
            <link>https://apologetics.com/christian-contentment/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[In the context of our current cultural chaos when there seems to be so much division and discontent, what are we commanded by scripture to pursue? Christian contentment is a virtue that we cultivate in the “School of Christ”. In this podcast hosted by Bob Parucha, we seek to capture the meaning of true contentment as defined by scripture and answer the questions, Why is it called “a rare jewel“? Are we commanded by scripture to pursue this virtue? What mindset do we need to pursue this and what are some of the steps that we can take to pursue it? Grace and peace.]]></description>
            <pubDate>Fri, 23 Aug 2024 10:20:48 -0700</pubDate>
            <enclosure url="https://feeds.soundcloud.com/stream/1902846532-apologeticspodcast-christian-contentment.mp3" length="137378066" type="audio/mpeg"/>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">C1D25AED-B59C-420B-9C55-2A6C47A96DB6</guid>
            <itunes:duration>3434</itunes:duration>
            <itunes:episodeType>full</itunes:episodeType>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>The State of Theology in America</title>
            <link>https://apologetics.com/state-of-theology/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[In a recent survey conducted by Ligonier and Lifeway on the “State of Theology” in America we find out that while almost all evangelicals believe God is a Trinity, a majority of them also believe that Jesus is a created being. How do you hold those contradictory beliefs as a professing Christian? What is the root cause of the theological ignorance in America even amongst  professing Christians? Join host Gallagher and special guest Mark Gould as they discuss these topics and discuss a path forward regarding the current state of American theology. Questions or comments, email jason@apologetics.com]]></description>
            <pubDate>Sat, 03 Aug 2024 17:16:49 -0700</pubDate>
            <enclosure url="https://feeds.soundcloud.com/stream/1888418748-apologeticspodcast-the-state-of-theology-in-america.mp3" length="53013005" type="audio/mpeg"/>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">9FBF94FB-84D2-442E-A3A2-2C11084099D7</guid>
            <itunes:duration>3313</itunes:duration>
            <itunes:episodeType>full</itunes:episodeType>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Beware of Tech's Shaping Forces</title>
            <link>https://apologetics.com/tech/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[There is no doubt, technology makes our lives better. Whatever you need, there's an app for that. But if we're not careful we can be captivated and  trapped, unaware of the destructive impact it has on our lives. Sometimes the negative effects of technology on our lives go undetected until it's too late. On this episode of the Apologetics.com Radio Show, Dr. Harry Edwards, along with Dr. Jacob Daniel and Lenny Esposito discuss the life-diminishing effects of technology and social media.]]></description>
            <pubDate>Thu, 18 Jul 2024 11:20:10 -0700</pubDate>
            <enclosure url="https://feeds.soundcloud.com/stream/1875023400-apologeticspodcast-beware-of-techs-shaping-forces.mp3" length="128442240" type="audio/mpeg"/>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">9F0AED5B-0784-4EF4-BB73-600BE780BBD5</guid>
            <itunes:duration>3211</itunes:duration>
            <itunes:episodeType>full</itunes:episodeType>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Parasitic Christianity: How Dawkins' Atheism Can't Exist Without Jesus</title>
            <link>https://apologetics.com/parasitic-christianity/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[Richard Dawkins, the world’s most famous atheist, has admitted that he is a “Cultural Christian.” What does it mean for him to claim that? Could he simply be enjoying the fruits of Christianity without acknowledging and appreciating its true source? Ideas do have consequences and it appears Dawkins struggles to find a basis for preferring Christianity over Islam for example. On this episode of the Apologetics.com show, Dr. Harry Edwards, along with Dr. Jacob Daniel and Lenny Esposito leads a discussion on the parasitic nature of Dawkins’ Christianity and how for the skeptic may serve as a signal of transcendence.]]></description>
            <pubDate>Sat, 13 Jul 2024 11:25:09 -0700</pubDate>
            <enclosure url="https://feeds.soundcloud.com/stream/1870961496-apologeticspodcast-parasitic-christianity-how-dawkins-atheism-cant-exist-without-jesus.mp3" length="128884800" type="audio/mpeg"/>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">9CD3E196-43AF-4450-96EF-F94C1E058334</guid>
            <itunes:duration>3222</itunes:duration>
            <itunes:episodeType>full</itunes:episodeType>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>The Trump Trial and Political Lawfare</title>
            <link>https://apologetics.com/the-trump-trial-and-political-law-fare/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[In this podcast, Logan and Tony talk about, you guessed it, Donald Trump. How is Trump's conviction unique in American history? What will it do to our political process? Is everything free game now in the political game? Also, what about those Trump and Jesus Memes? You know the ones. All this and more in this episode of Apologetics.com radio.]]></description>
            <pubDate>Thu, 13 Jun 2024 21:39:35 -0700</pubDate>
            <enclosure url="https://feeds.soundcloud.com/stream/1847078457-apologeticspodcast-the-trump-trial-and-political-lawfare.mp3" length="53125018" type="audio/mpeg"/>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">0EB70AA9-4939-4F23-943E-7442D53B6DA3</guid>
            <itunes:duration>3320</itunes:duration>
            <itunes:episodeType>full</itunes:episodeType>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Where Do Human Rights Come From?</title>
            <link>https://apologetics.com/human-rights/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[On this episode of the ADC Radio show, Jason and Tony discuss the genesis of human rights and how critical this question is as it relates to society and human government. Do human rights come from God or from government? Are human rights self evident or are they human inventions? Listen in as we unpack the truth about human rights and equip you to do the same. Please send questions or comments to jason@apologetics.com. Grace and peace.]]></description>
            <pubDate>Wed, 15 May 2024 15:19:37 -0700</pubDate>
            <enclosure url="https://feeds.soundcloud.com/stream/1822827240-apologeticspodcast-where-do-human-rights-come-from.mp3" length="128670932" type="audio/mpeg"/>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">5A186A8C-BBEC-481B-8F56-66A2F86EBEE8</guid>
            <itunes:duration>3216</itunes:duration>
            <itunes:episodeType>full</itunes:episodeType>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>The What, Why, and How of Christian Apologetics</title>
            <link>https://apologetics.com/the-basics/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[On this episode of the Apologetics.com Radio Show, Dr. Harry Edwards, along with Dr. Jacob Daniel and Adam Kazmierski discuss the nature and grounds for defending the truth claims of Christianity. This is especially targeted to those who want to start getting into the discipline of Christian apologetics.]]></description>
            <pubDate>Tue, 07 May 2024 10:06:13 -0700</pubDate>
            <enclosure url="https://feeds.soundcloud.com/stream/1816599999-apologeticspodcast-the-what-why-and-how-of-christian-apologetics.mp3" length="122941440" type="audio/mpeg"/>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">669B309C-104D-426E-B236-AFD70D7E0BF2</guid>
            <itunes:duration>3073</itunes:duration>
            <itunes:episodeType>full</itunes:episodeType>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>The Resurrection of Jesus</title>
            <link>https://apologetics.com/resurrection-of-jesus/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[On this episode of the Apologetics.com Radio Show, Dr. Harry Edwards leads a discussion on the resurrection of Jesus, a historical event that took place nearly two thousand years ago. On the panel are Lenny Esposito and Dr. Jacob Daniel. Together they talk about the solid evidences supporting the resurrection and the failed naturalistic theories that try to explain it away. If Jesus rose from the grave, what does that mean for humanity?]]></description>
            <pubDate>Wed, 03 Apr 2024 08:43:12 -0700</pubDate>
            <enclosure url="https://feeds.soundcloud.com/stream/1791729241-apologeticspodcast-the-resurrection-of-jesus.mp3" length="120577920" type="audio/mpeg"/>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">9ECD63A5-B154-4C93-A8BB-6A1FFF94E9FC</guid>
            <itunes:duration>3014</itunes:duration>
            <itunes:episodeType>full</itunes:episodeType>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Evangelism and the Gospel</title>
            <link>https://apologetics.com/evangelism-and-the-gospel/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[On this episode of the Apologetics.com Radio Show we talk to Julio Negron, founder and director of Wakemup Ministriy (www.wakemupministry.org) about his experiences evangelizing on the streets of New York. On this show Dr. Harry Edwards, Lenny Esposito, and Julio Negron discuss the nature and practical aspects of evangelism, offer fresh insights on what the Gospel is and ways to share the Christian message to unbelievers.]]></description>
            <pubDate>Sat, 30 Mar 2024 16:13:29 -0700</pubDate>
            <enclosure url="https://feeds.soundcloud.com/stream/1788723520-apologeticspodcast-evangelism-and-the-gospel.mp3" length="132277440" type="audio/mpeg"/>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">DD60C2A6-2E2C-4872-93F7-9983009EF2D7</guid>
            <itunes:duration>3306</itunes:duration>
            <itunes:episodeType>full</itunes:episodeType>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Gender Unplugged: The March Toward Sexual Revolution</title>
            <link>https://apologetics.com/gender-unplugged/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[On this episode of the Apologetics.com Radio Show we discuss the nature of today’s sexual revolution, its culture-sapping effects on society, and practical advice for parents whose children struggle to understand gender dysphoria and what it means for them. Much of the content is based on chapter ten of Carl Trueman’s book “The Rise of the Modern Self: Cultural Amnesia, Expressive Individualism, and the Road to Sexual Revolution.” Dr. Harry Edwards leads the discussion along with Dr. Jacob Daniel and Lenny Esposito.]]></description>
            <pubDate>Wed, 13 Mar 2024 16:58:49 -0700</pubDate>
            <enclosure url="https://feeds.soundcloud.com/stream/1773883617-apologeticspodcast-gender-unplugged-the-march-toward-sexual-revolution.mp3" length="50989765" type="audio/mpeg"/>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">3FCB6635-99E5-4A57-9C39-52BA22300726</guid>
            <itunes:duration>3186</itunes:duration>
            <itunes:episodeType>full</itunes:episodeType>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>How Can Christians Change Culture</title>
            <link>https://apologetics.com/christians-change-culture/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[For far too long Christians have prioritized living separate from the world, compartmentalizing their lives into two spheres–the sacred vs. the secular. However living this way disregards Jesus’ admonition to be salt and light in the world. But how can a Christian be “salty” and be a source of light if he or she hides behind a false understanding of what it means to be in the world but not of it. Watch as Dr. Harry Edwards leads a discussion on this topic with radio co-host Lenny Esposito and special guest Pastor Jason Kim.]]></description>
            <pubDate>Thu, 29 Feb 2024 12:49:08 -0800</pubDate>
            <enclosure url="https://feeds.soundcloud.com/stream/1761496794-apologeticspodcast-how-christians-can-change-culture.mp3" length="130006080" type="audio/mpeg"/>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">D3E593ED-3637-4946-81EA-F5E65FCDFE76</guid>
            <itunes:duration>3250</itunes:duration>
            <itunes:episodeType>full</itunes:episodeType>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>HeGetsUs, But Do We Get Him: Prerequisites to Pre-Evangelism</title>
            <link>https://apologetics.com/hegetsus/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[The 2024 Super Bowl aired an ad titled #HeGetsUs. This was seen live by over 100 million viewers and was created with the purpose of introducing people to the person of Jesus Christ, the historical Jesus of the Bible. Did they succeed? With all the public chatter surrounding this, some good and some bad, Drs. Harry Edwards, Jacob Daniel, and Lenny Esposito offer their views on this cultural phenomenon that is #HeGetsUs.]]></description>
            <pubDate>Mon, 26 Feb 2024 22:39:26 -0800</pubDate>
            <enclosure url="https://feeds.soundcloud.com/stream/1759026675-apologeticspodcast-hegetsus-but-do-we-get-him-prerequisites-to-pre-evangelism.mp3" length="129628800" type="audio/mpeg"/>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">E920AB60-AEB7-4740-BE20-345192E940EE</guid>
            <itunes:duration>3240</itunes:duration>
            <itunes:episodeType>full</itunes:episodeType>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Does the Church Have a Role in Shaping Culture?</title>
            <link>https://apologetics.com/church-shapes-culture/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[In the West today there seems to be an indifference with regard to the role Christians play in shaping culture. Aren't Christians aliens in this world, passively waiting for Christ's return to make all things new? Or rather, are followers of Jesus called to transform this world for Christ, bring heaven to earth as we say in the Lord's Prayer? On this episode of the Apologetics.com Radio Show, Dr. Harry Edwards, along with Dr. Jacob Daniel and Lenny Esposito discuss the role Christians play in shaping culture.]]></description>
            <pubDate>Wed, 21 Feb 2024 20:24:55 -0800</pubDate>
            <enclosure url="https://feeds.soundcloud.com/stream/1754485182-apologeticspodcast-does-the-church-have-a-role-in-shaping-culture.mp3" length="53011852" type="audio/mpeg"/>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">30623E36-5129-42CD-ABC1-8919A85E5EAA</guid>
            <itunes:duration>3313</itunes:duration>
            <itunes:episodeType>full</itunes:episodeType>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Discussing Morality and Ethics with Non-Believers</title>
            <link>https://apologetics.com/morality-and-ethics/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[In this episode of the ADC Radio Show we join Jason and Tony as they discuss how to have conversations with atheists or unbelievers. Listen in as they discuss various distinctives of the “moral argument for God’s existence” and how to handle objections to various points in the argument. Please send any comments or questions to jason@apologetics.com. Grace and peace.]]></description>
            <pubDate>Tue, 13 Feb 2024 17:26:15 -0800</pubDate>
            <enclosure url="https://feeds.soundcloud.com/stream/1746506544-apologeticspodcast-discussing-morality-and-ethics-with-non-believers.mp3" length="130039748" type="audio/mpeg"/>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">93DDD6BA-7A09-46AB-B73D-DDDDECA4752A</guid>
            <itunes:duration>3250</itunes:duration>
            <itunes:episodeType>full</itunes:episodeType>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Should a Christian Go To A Gay Wedding?</title>
            <link>https://apologetics.com/gay-wedding/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[On this episode of the Apologetics.com Radio Show, Jon and Eric discuss the recent comments made by influential pastor, Alistair Begg regarding whether or not a Christian should attend a gay or trans wedding. Should a Christian go to a gay wedding? How do we address this issue with a fellow Christian who disagrees with you? This and more on the Apologetics.com Radio Show.]]></description>
            <pubDate>Thu, 08 Feb 2024 19:11:23 -0800</pubDate>
            <enclosure url="https://feeds.soundcloud.com/stream/1741742976-apologeticspodcast-should-a-christian-go-to-a-gay-wedding.mp3" length="133576728" type="audio/mpeg"/>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">629876F8-587A-43AF-9A5D-15FE8D5E943D</guid>
            <itunes:duration>3339</itunes:duration>
            <itunes:episodeType>full</itunes:episodeType>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>What Role Does Christian Scholarship Play in the Church?</title>
            <link>https://apologetics.com/christian-scholarship/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>C.S. Lewis said “To be ignorant and simple now -- not to be able to meet the enemies on their own ground -- would be to throw down our weapons, and to betray our uneducated brethren who have, under God, no defense but us against the intellectual attacks of the heathen. Good philosophy must exist, if for no other reason, because bad philosophy needs to be answered.”</p>

<p>On this episode Dr. Harry Edwards leads a discussion with Dr. Jacob Daniel and Lenny Esposito on the importance of Christian scholarship in the service of the church. Here we make the case for it, explain why the church has abdicated the role of being experts in the arts and sciences, and a way forward to recapture a love for knowledge in the church.</p>
]]></description>
            <pubDate>Tue, 06 Feb 2024 12:04:22 -0800</pubDate>
            <enclosure url="https://feeds.soundcloud.com/stream/1739668992-apologeticspodcast-what-role-does-christian-scholarship-play-in-the-church.mp3" length="127608960" type="audio/mpeg"/>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">926CD3D4-514B-4D0C-AFC6-9932BD1D1545</guid>
            <itunes:duration>3190</itunes:duration>
            <itunes:episodeType>full</itunes:episodeType>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Is the Tide of Unbelief Receding?</title>
            <link>https://apologetics.com/unbelief-receding/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[On this episode of the Apologetics.com Radio Show we review Justin Brierley's new book The Surprising Rebirth of Belief in God: Why New Atheism Grew Old and Secular Thinkers Are Considering Christianity Again. We also cover the excellent review of it by Dr. Peter Harris who guests on the show.]]></description>
            <pubDate>Fri, 02 Feb 2024 08:29:29 -0800</pubDate>
            <enclosure url="https://feeds.soundcloud.com/stream/1734857448-apologeticspodcast-is-the-tide-of-unbelief-receding.mp3" length="129884160" type="audio/mpeg"/>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">AD36F0C0-2AF2-4C2B-A3CB-64C30DEF041C</guid>
            <itunes:duration>3247</itunes:duration>
            <itunes:episodeType>full</itunes:episodeType>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>What Happens When You Adopt Relativism?</title>
            <link>https://apologetics.com/what-happens-when-you-adopt-relativism/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[The October 7, 2023 attack on Israel by Hamas has shed a light on what it means to tell the truth. Leaders, including presidents of elite universities across America have had to come to the painful realization that not stating what a thing is brings disastrous consequences, i.e. antisemitism, violence, redefinition of truth, etc. Listen as Harry Edwards, Tony Costello, and Lenny Esposito discuss what happens when a society embraces relativism.]]></description>
            <pubDate>Mon, 15 Jan 2024 21:30:37 -0800</pubDate>
            <enclosure url="https://feeds.soundcloud.com/stream/1718715354-apologeticspodcast-what-happens-when-you-adopt-relativism.mp3" length="128145348" type="audio/mpeg"/>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">0CAEC706-2B61-437F-BDAA-58C52EB64016</guid>
            <itunes:duration>3203</itunes:duration>
            <itunes:episodeType>full</itunes:episodeType>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Artificial Intelligence for the Glory of God</title>
            <link>https://apologetics.com/artificial-intelligence/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[Join Jason and Daniel as they discuss artificial intelligence and how we can and why we ought to use it for the glory of God and the good of humanity.  Throughout the show, Jason and Daniel discuss the great opportunity that lies ahead of us with AI and they seek to dispel some of the myths and misunderstandings around this technology. While blending together practical application and biblical truth, tune in and learn how great of an opportunity lies right in front of us and why we ought to be interested in leveraging this technology sooner rather than later. Grace and peace. Questions or comments:  jason@apologetics.com]]></description>
            <pubDate>Mon, 15 Jan 2024 10:47:37 -0800</pubDate>
            <enclosure url="https://feeds.soundcloud.com/stream/1717305807-apologeticspodcast-artificial-intelligence-for-the-glory-of-god.mp3" length="128819307" type="audio/mpeg"/>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">F729B17D-1D33-493D-B39F-39C3D5B77901</guid>
            <itunes:duration>3220</itunes:duration>
            <itunes:episodeType>full</itunes:episodeType>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Essential Apologetics - The Problem of Evil</title>
            <link>https://apologetics.com/essential-apologetics-the-problem-of-evil/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[If God is good, why is there evil and suffering in the world? Join Jason, Tony and Daniel as they discuss the age old problem of evil and various ways to approach the question. Logically, presuppositionally, philosophically, and emotionally; the problem of evil is no problem at all for the Triune God of Scripture. Grace and Peace.]]></description>
            <pubDate>Fri, 29 Dec 2023 09:57:57 -0800</pubDate>
            <enclosure url="https://feeds.soundcloud.com/stream/1703039712-apologeticspodcast-essential-apologetics-the-problem-of-evil.mp3" length="132549593" type="audio/mpeg"/>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">4DE1E4BB-6735-4FD8-B328-5683636AFC20</guid>
            <itunes:duration>3313</itunes:duration>
            <itunes:episodeType>full</itunes:episodeType>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>The Church: Culture Warrior or Culture Makers?</title>
            <link>https://apologetics.com/the-church-culture-warriors-or-culture-makers/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[In this episode deacon Daniel Adrean of Branch of Hope Orthodox Presbyterian Church in Torrance, California discusses what Bible-believing Christians as individuals, families, and churches at every level must think, say, and do about the culture and society our Lord has placed them in - does God's Word teach us about these things and our duties about them? Please prayerfully listen and consider according to Scripture alone...]]></description>
            <pubDate>Fri, 29 Dec 2023 09:49:30 -0800</pubDate>
            <enclosure url="https://feeds.soundcloud.com/stream/1703018193-apologeticspodcast-the-church-culture-warriore-or-culture-makers.mp3" length="131960270" type="audio/mpeg"/>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">95358FA2-4FD6-4D61-8EEC-7C50736AB3D7</guid>
            <itunes:duration>3299</itunes:duration>
            <itunes:episodeType>full</itunes:episodeType>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>What Does the Bible Say About Suicide?</title>
            <link>https://apologetics.com/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[Join Jon as he seeks to address one of the most difficult issues in our culture today, suicide. Why do people contemplate suicide? Does the Bible ever address suicide? Can a Christian die by suicide and still go to heaven? What can we do to help? These are just some of the questions asked and answered.]]></description>
            <pubDate>Wed, 08 Nov 2023 17:45:28 -0800</pubDate>
            <enclosure url="https://feeds.soundcloud.com/stream/1660302873-apologeticspodcast-what-does-the-bible-say-about-suicide.mp3" length="146381952" type="audio/mpeg"/>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">05331BD9-36CF-4754-9A36-45E240E4D684</guid>
            <itunes:duration>3659</itunes:duration>
            <itunes:episodeType>full</itunes:episodeType>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Israel and Hamas Need the Gospel</title>
            <link>https://apologetics.com/israel-and-hamas/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[Join Jason and Tony as they unpack what is driving and fueling the hatred seen in the recent attacks upon Israel by Hamas. As they unpack some of the ideology behind the terrorism the need for gospel truth is highlighted along with developing a heart of compassion for our Muslim and Jewish neighbors. In the end, only the gospel has the power to being true healing and true peace to Jerusalem. May you be encouraged in your proclamation to the world around you.]]></description>
            <pubDate>Mon, 16 Oct 2023 14:32:25 -0700</pubDate>
            <enclosure url="https://feeds.soundcloud.com/stream/1642309290-apologeticspodcast-israel-and-hamas-need-the-gospel.mp3" length="125930164" type="audio/mpeg"/>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2108F79C-06DF-4AD7-82D0-273483A7315F</guid>
            <itunes:duration>3148</itunes:duration>
            <itunes:episodeType>full</itunes:episodeType>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>What is Biblical Manhood?</title>
            <link>https://apologetics.com/manhood/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[Join Eric and Jon along with special guest, Andrew Kisumba on this episode of the Apologetics.com Radio Show. Listen as they explore what it means to be a man according to biblical principles. Part of the conversation is focused on highlighting some of the cultural issues having to do with manhood.]]></description>
            <pubDate>Thu, 12 Oct 2023 21:28:24 -0700</pubDate>
            <enclosure url="https://feeds.soundcloud.com/stream/1639261401-apologeticspodcast-what-is-biblical-manhood.mp3" length="131144205" type="audio/mpeg"/>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">CB13E78B-37E2-491B-A7A2-684B66B0F1A2</guid>
            <itunes:duration>3278</itunes:duration>
            <itunes:episodeType>full</itunes:episodeType>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>What Role Does Faith Play in Politics?</title>
            <link>https://apologetics.com/politics-2/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>Coming on the heels of the recent Republican debate, Americans are once again animated by the issues that affect their lives and the prospect for a better future. As members of this republic we are all involved and responsible for what happens in this nation, what laws are passed, and what policies are adopted that enhance "life, liberty, and the pursuit of happiness." </p>

<p>Christians happily engage in politics and are concerned about the direction the country is headed, especially when it comes to moral issues. However, there appears to be an increasing number of churches that are confused about the role faith plays in politics. On this episode of the Apologetics.com, we try to answer the question: What role does faith play in politics? We also engage the topic of whether there is any virtue in voting for the lesser of two evils; why it's legitimate to include the subject of politics in the art and science of Christian Apologetics.</p>
]]></description>
            <pubDate>Sat, 26 Aug 2023 21:44:35 -0700</pubDate>
            <enclosure url="https://feeds.soundcloud.com/stream/1601959899-apologeticspodcast-what-role-does-faith-play-in-politics.mp3" length="132548548" type="audio/mpeg"/>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">D2ADCA36-1DD2-47D5-B309-BD7B4394F15A</guid>
            <itunes:duration>3313</itunes:duration>
            <itunes:episodeType>full</itunes:episodeType>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>A Personal Story of Redemption</title>
            <link>https://apologetics.com/redemption/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[Join Jon and Chris with special guest Carlo on this episode of the Apolofgetics.com Radio Show. Hear Carlo's personal story of redemption, having been saved out of drug addiction and crime. The hosts then discuss how parents can help influence their kids for Christ.]]></description>
            <pubDate>Tue, 22 Aug 2023 08:54:33 -0700</pubDate>
            <enclosure url="https://feeds.soundcloud.com/stream/1598721198-apologeticspodcast-a-personal-story-of-redemption.mp3" length="52327652" type="audio/mpeg"/>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">0AD755C7-C074-4FEB-8FBF-E9BCF6CAFF41</guid>
            <itunes:duration>3270</itunes:duration>
            <itunes:episodeType>full</itunes:episodeType>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Why Do We Hate Our Bodies?</title>
            <link>https://apologetics.com/body/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[There appears to be an all-out war against our bodies to fully subject them to the Will and fantasies of our minds. If it’s the hope for a bureaucratic state to raise our children, our desire for technology to “fix” nature, our dependence on augmented reality and media, our total denial that we should live healthy lives, or the massive social experiment of transgenderism in remaking the body in the image of our minds, we are beset on all fronts for accepting our body for what it is. Using Yukio Mishima as a foil, Logan Zeppieri and Anthony Costello consider the “language and logic” of the body and what Christian theology provides us as an answer to the dissolution of one of our most divine and precious gifts from God—our body.]]></description>
            <pubDate>Fri, 04 Aug 2023 18:26:50 -0700</pubDate>
            <enclosure url="https://feeds.soundcloud.com/stream/1583656475-apologeticspodcast-why-do-we-hate-our-bodies.mp3" length="51577754" type="audio/mpeg"/>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">C16A6725-64FC-4299-8DEB-B182A43BC3D8</guid>
            <itunes:duration>3223</itunes:duration>
            <itunes:episodeType>full</itunes:episodeType>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Should Christians Be Afraid of AI?</title>
            <link>https://apologetics.com/ai/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[On this episode of the Apologetics.com Radio show we dive into the fascinating world of artificial intelligence. We’re going to embark on an extraordinary journey exploring the cutting-edge developments and transformative impact of AI on our lives. From self-driving cars to virtual assistants, AI is revolutionizing industries and reshaping the way we live, work, and interact. Our experts will help us unravel the mysteries behind machine learning, neural networks, and algorithms that power AI systems. Tonight, we’ll discuss some of the ethical considerations, the future implications, and engage with leading experts to gain invaluable insights into this rapidly evolving field. So fasten your seatbelts and get ready to unlock the secrets of AI here on the Apologetics.com show. It’s time to demystify the magic of artificial intelligence and empower ourselves with knowledge.]]></description>
            <pubDate>Mon, 26 Jun 2023 11:15:29 -0700</pubDate>
            <enclosure url="https://feeds.soundcloud.com/stream/1550545924-apologeticspodcast-should-christians-be-afraid-of-ai.mp3" length="136170164" type="audio/mpeg"/>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">6AF605F5-7E42-4F29-B738-4B7880DC5693</guid>
            <itunes:duration>3404</itunes:duration>
            <itunes:episodeType>full</itunes:episodeType>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>The New Left and the Politicization of Sex</title>
            <link>https://apologetics.com/freud-and-marx/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[On this episode of the Apologetics.com Radio Show, Harry Edwards and Lenny Esposito discuss the origin and nature of the Freud and Marxist project of reducing individuals and societies to purely sex objects.]]></description>
            <pubDate>Fri, 09 Jun 2023 13:46:49 -0700</pubDate>
            <enclosure url="https://feeds.soundcloud.com/stream/1535453323-apologeticspodcast-the-new-left-and-the-politicization-of-sex.mp3" length="134709397" type="audio/mpeg"/>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">28EDAA67-CEE9-48C1-8EE0-9AE7564A3D60</guid>
            <itunes:duration>3367</itunes:duration>
            <itunes:episodeType>full</itunes:episodeType>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Recognizing Cultic Counterfeit Teachings</title>
            <link>https://apologetics.com/cults/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[On this episode of the Apologetics.com Radio Show, Dr. Harry Edwards along with Dr. Jacob Daniel and Lenny Esposito, lead a discussion on Christian cults, how to spot and avoid counterfeit Christian teachings. Our special guest is Cynthia Hampton from Women in Apologetics will share from experience the dangers associated with cultic beliefs.]]></description>
            <pubDate>Thu, 01 Jun 2023 13:07:28 -0700</pubDate>
            <enclosure url="https://feeds.soundcloud.com/stream/1528134403-apologeticspodcast-recognizing-cultic-counterfeit-teachings.mp3" length="138575519" type="audio/mpeg"/>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">1B0082E9-049B-44A5-B78E-E9F3DB56A330</guid>
            <itunes:duration>3464</itunes:duration>
            <itunes:episodeType>full</itunes:episodeType>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Sigmund Freud, Civilization, and Sex</title>
            <link>https://apologetics.com/sigmund-freud/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[In this episode of the Apologetics.com Radio Show, Dr. Harry Edwards, together with Dr. Jacob Daniel and Lenny Esposito, leads a discussion on exposing the lesser known ideas of Sigmund Freud and how it became imbedded in the West's social imaginary or Sittlichkeit.]]></description>
            <pubDate>Wed, 19 Apr 2023 11:19:25 -0700</pubDate>
            <enclosure url="https://feeds.soundcloud.com/stream/1496307997-apologeticspodcast-sigmund-freud-civilization-and-sex.mp3" length="141964123" type="audio/mpeg"/>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">B13F7DD4-9E9B-4817-A757-A33C86B0EFD5</guid>
            <itunes:duration>3549</itunes:duration>
            <itunes:episodeType>full</itunes:episodeType>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>The Faith of Our Founders: Natural Law and What Made America Great</title>
            <link>https://apologetics.com/what-made-america-great/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[What was the faith of America's founding fathers? While most of the founders were personally Christians, the question that vexed them most was upon what foundation was the Political State to be built. If Christ was the foundation of the Church, then was He also the foundation of the body politic, to include its particular laws and institutions of governance? The answer was not so simple, even in their day, when everyone was some kind of Christian. In this episode, Tony Costello (MA Theology, Talbot School of Theology) talks with Logan Zeppieri of the Claremont Institute and Darren Guerra, professor of Political Science at Biola University, to discuss what the founders believed was the best foundation for government: Natural Law.]]></description>
            <pubDate>Thu, 30 Mar 2023 11:37:28 -0700</pubDate>
            <enclosure url="https://feeds.soundcloud.com/stream/1481302915-apologeticspodcast-the-faith-of-our-founders-natural-law-and-what-made-america-great.mp3" length="137214017" type="audio/mpeg"/>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">CCFE929A-2959-4F1C-A64D-FE37AFB6E63F</guid>
            <itunes:duration>3430</itunes:duration>
            <itunes:episodeType>full</itunes:episodeType>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>He Gets Us, The Jesus Revolution, and Lonnie Frisbee</title>
            <link>https://apologetics.com/jesus-revolution/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[In this episode, Jason and Tony take a look at some recent TV and Film media that have sparked conversations about Jesus. With “revivals” floating around our current cultural landscape we take a look at the “He Gets Us” campaign from the 2023 Super Bowl ads and ask whether it’s a solidly biblical platform or not. We also discuss the Jesus Revolution main character, Lonnie Frisbee, and some of the struggles he lived through and sins that haunted him behind the scenes. All this and more on this episode of the ADC Radio Show. Send questions  or comments to jason@apologetics.com.]]></description>
            <pubDate>Mon, 13 Mar 2023 10:31:06 -0700</pubDate>
            <enclosure url="https://feeds.soundcloud.com/stream/1468079470-apologeticspodcast-he-gets-us-the-jesus-revolution-and-lonnie-frisbee.mp3" length="137354034" type="audio/mpeg"/>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">325FEA2D-CF61-480B-A544-90E297102EA4</guid>
            <itunes:duration>3433</itunes:duration>
            <itunes:episodeType>full</itunes:episodeType>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>The Ascent of Porn and the Descent of Culture</title>
            <link>https://apologetics.com/porn/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[In this episode of the Apologetics.com Radio, Dr. Harry Edwards, together with Dr. Jacob Daniel and Lenny Esposito, leads a discussion on the harmful effects of porn and the damage it brings to society. The question that must be asked is: How did we get from having the Rolling Stones change the lyrics of “Let’s Spend the Night Together” to “Let’s Spend Some Time Together” in order to perform on the The Ed Sullivan Show to Miley Cyrus sex act with a microphone at the Glastonbury Festival?]]></description>
            <pubDate>Fri, 03 Mar 2023 09:19:34 -0800</pubDate>
            <enclosure url="https://feeds.soundcloud.com/stream/1460623621-apologeticspodcast-the-ascent-of-porn-and-the-descent-of-culture.mp3" length="136530654" type="audio/mpeg"/>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">BB77E4EA-0270-4170-98BF-4D55104C073A</guid>
            <itunes:duration>3413</itunes:duration>
            <itunes:episodeType>full</itunes:episodeType>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>The Emergence of Plastic People: Can We Make and Remake Personal Identity at Will?</title>
            <link>https://apologetics.com/plastic-people/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[In this episode of the Apologetics.com Radio Show, Dr. Harry Edwards, along with Dr. Jacob Daniel and Lenny Esposito, leads a discussion on understanding one of the most striking characteristics of what it means to be human today: that an individual can make and remake personal identity at will.]]></description>
            <pubDate>Thu, 23 Feb 2023 09:44:41 -0800</pubDate>
            <enclosure url="https://feeds.soundcloud.com/stream/1454125330-apologeticspodcast-the-emergence-of-plastic-people-can-we-make-and-remake-personal-identity-at-will.mp3" length="54706576" type="audio/mpeg"/>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2B6CB3E6-1F3A-47F2-A085-1F1589A3FC90</guid>
            <itunes:duration>3419</itunes:duration>
            <itunes:episodeType>full</itunes:episodeType>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Atheist Turns to Christianity</title>
            <link>https://apologetics.com/atheist/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[On this episode of the Apologetics.com Radio Show, Jon Noyes talks about three reasons why the Christian worldview is the best explanation for the way the world really is. He shares three "bumps" into reality he experienced that caused him to reevaluate his atheism and ultimately led him to believe the Christian story of reality.]]></description>
            <pubDate>Tue, 21 Feb 2023 16:30:04 -0800</pubDate>
            <enclosure url="https://feeds.soundcloud.com/stream/1452605734-apologeticspodcast-atheist-turns-to-christianity.mp3" length="137113707" type="audio/mpeg"/>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">16A81B60-8C52-45B2-90F3-1BA564DDA078</guid>
            <itunes:duration>3427</itunes:duration>
            <itunes:episodeType>full</itunes:episodeType>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Biblical Authority and the Genesis Foundations</title>
            <link>https://apologetics.com/biblical-authority/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[Much of the church has said that the earthly things in Genesis can be incorrect while the rest of the spiritual truths in Scripture can be trusted. Jesus doesn’t give us that luxury and says it ultimately amounts to a contradiction.  “If I have told you about things that happen on earth and you don’t believe, how will you believe if I tell you about things of heaven?” John 3:12. The psalmist adds, “If the foundations be destroyed, what can the righteous do.” Join Jason and Daniel as they discuss the importance of biblical authority and how our understanding of Genesis impacts pretty much everything. jason@apologetics.com.]]></description>
            <pubDate>Mon, 13 Feb 2023 16:22:12 -0800</pubDate>
            <enclosure url="https://feeds.soundcloud.com/stream/1446333004-apologeticspodcast-biblical-authority-and-the-genesis-foundations.mp3" length="137866034" type="audio/mpeg"/>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">5BD17031-C415-428C-B8BF-D121FB5AD138</guid>
            <itunes:duration>3446</itunes:duration>
            <itunes:episodeType>full</itunes:episodeType>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Treeology: The Significance of Trees in God's Creation</title>
            <link>https://apologetics.com/trees/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[On this episode of the Apologetics.com Radio Show, host Jon Noyes along with Eric and Dan discuss the importance of Trees. God loves trees and interestingly, trees are the most mentioned living entity in the Bible, outside of God/Jesus and humans.  Trees can survive without humans, but humans cannot survive without trees. Trees play substantial roles in the metanarrative (creation, fall, redemption, restoration) of the Bible.  Trees are also associated with many of the major events and prominent characters in the Bible.  We are commanded to be good stewards of God's creation of which trees hold much significance.]]></description>
            <pubDate>Sun, 12 Feb 2023 06:56:40 -0800</pubDate>
            <enclosure url="https://feeds.soundcloud.com/stream/1445308165-apologeticspodcast-treeology-the-significance-of-trees-in-gods-creation.mp3" length="136907862" type="audio/mpeg"/>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">86CC55F0-48A7-4CDA-84AA-F60B032B7845</guid>
            <itunes:duration>3422</itunes:duration>
            <itunes:episodeType>full</itunes:episodeType>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Inerrancy, Authority, and Sufficiency: How Our View of Scripture Impacts Everything</title>
            <link>https://apologetics.com/inerrancy-authority-and-sufficiency-of-scripture/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[Perhaps you have heard someone say there is no Christian way to change a diaper or to be a plumber. Nothing could be further from the truth. There is a Christian way to do absolutely everything in life and how you understand this is directly related to your view of scripture. Join Jason and Daniel as they discuss these things and show how abandoning inerrancy, authority or sufficiency has led to terrible consequences for our culture today and why we need to get back to  a biblical view of the scriptures. Be sure to share with those you love and if you have questions or comments you can email jason@apologetics.com with questions.]]></description>
            <pubDate>Fri, 20 Jan 2023 17:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
            <enclosure url="https://feeds.soundcloud.com/stream/1429016182-apologeticspodcast-inerrancy-authority-and-sufficiency-how-our-view-of-scripture-impacts-everything.mp3" length="136311225" type="audio/mpeg"/>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">909ECC38-15E4-487F-B50A-8B7AF2EDE7C3</guid>
            <itunes:duration>3407</itunes:duration>
            <itunes:episodeType>full</itunes:episodeType>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Thinking Christianly in a Post-Christian Culture</title>
            <link>https://apologetics.com/post-christian-culture/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[It seems like everywhere you turn today you can find a story of corruption, injustice or immorality that is being championed by our culture. How do we engage with the world around us without getting caught up in a worldly shouting match. Listen in as we discuss different ways Christians can be faithful to the Kingdom of God right where God has you and shine the light of Christ in the world. Send questions or comments to jason@apologetics.com.]]></description>
            <pubDate>Mon, 12 Dec 2022 11:27:04 -0800</pubDate>
            <enclosure url="https://feeds.soundcloud.com/stream/1401267268-apologeticspodcast-thinking-christianly-in-a-post-christian-culture.mp3" length="136258981" type="audio/mpeg"/>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">CC490F81-9BE7-4FDB-8ECA-8643DB9DBC18</guid>
            <itunes:duration>3406</itunes:duration>
            <itunes:episodeType>full</itunes:episodeType>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>True Biblical Justice</title>
            <link>https://apologetics.com/justice/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[On this episode of the Apologetics.com Radio Show, radio host Jon Noyes talks about the cultural understanding of justice. He offers a short critique of critical theory while exploring where it falls short and offering a better standard, true biblical justice.]]></description>
            <pubDate>Tue, 22 Nov 2022 08:58:46 -0800</pubDate>
            <enclosure url="https://feeds.soundcloud.com/stream/1388347063-apologeticspodcast-true-biblical-justice.mp3" length="135739666" type="audio/mpeg"/>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">C2C7E0E6-9E3E-4068-93D3-000E269578F5</guid>
            <itunes:duration>3393</itunes:duration>
            <itunes:episodeType>full</itunes:episodeType>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Unacknowledged Legislators</title>
            <link>https://apologetics.com/unacknowledged-legislators/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[In this episode of the Apologetics.com Radio Show, Dr. Harry Edwards, together with Dr. Jacob Daniel and Lenny Esposito, discuss chapter four of Carl Trueman's book &quot;The Rise and Triumph of the Modern Self&quot; in which the author pins some of the West's current cultural issues to the lesser known works of the Poets of the Romantic era. We will talk about some of the shaping ideas of Wordsworth, Shelley, and Blake and how they have forged a culture of self determination and emotivism.]]></description>
            <pubDate>Fri, 04 Nov 2022 14:45:22 -0700</pubDate>
            <enclosure url="https://feeds.soundcloud.com/stream/1376516791-apologeticspodcast-unacknowledged-legislators.mp3" length="63761721" type="audio/mpeg"/>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">4BC08B24-6D88-4234-BDB3-691BB5CD9004</guid>
            <itunes:duration>3188</itunes:duration>
            <itunes:episodeType>full</itunes:episodeType>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Should Nationalists be Christian?</title>
            <link>https://apologetics.com/patriotism/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>With the 2022 midterms on the cusp, “Christian Nationalism” is again the political scape goat and featured entree for mass media.</p>

<p>In this episode of the Church and State Report, Logan Zeppieri and Ben Wager take a slight spin to the Christian Nationalism debate by discussing, “Should Nationalists be Christian?” This discussion address questions regarding rhetorical ambiguity, the relationship between “who we are” and “what we do”, the importance of government as a Christian vocation, and why Christians are called to be patriots.</p>
]]></description>
            <pubDate>Tue, 01 Nov 2022 08:36:08 -0700</pubDate>
            <enclosure url="https://feeds.soundcloud.com/stream/1373911744-apologeticspodcast-should-nationalists-be-christian.mp3" length="134571470" type="audio/mpeg"/>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">CC1F6701-456A-474D-9259-230BBA126B86</guid>
            <itunes:duration>3364</itunes:duration>
            <itunes:episodeType>full</itunes:episodeType>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Humanity, Reality, and Contradiction</title>
            <link>https://apologetics.com/humanity-reality-and-contradiction/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>Subjective Truth vs. Objective Humanity
<br />Is the real world merely a universe of facts about physical things, or are values and meanings objectively real as well?  Can we separate our view of humanity from our view of reality?  How subjective is moral truth?  In this broadcast Jon and Joel discuss the relationship between materialism and the advance of moral relativism in our culture with respect to the inherent contradictions of a godless worldview.</p>
 
<p>“His mind slid away into the labyrinthine world of doublethink. To know and not to know, to be conscious of complete truthfulness while telling carefully constructed lies, to hold simultaneously two opinions which cancelled out, knowing them to be contradictory and believing in both of them, to use logic against logic, to repudiate morality while laying claim to it . . . to forget whatever it was necessary to forget, then to draw it back into memory again at the moment when it was needed, and then promptly to forget it again: and above all, to apply the same process to the process itself.”
<br />   – George Orwell, 1984
<br />“Fearing the LORD is the very foundation of wisdom, and knowing the Holy One amounts to insight.”
<br />    – Proverbs 9:10
<br />“His invisible attributes, His eternal power and divinity in particular, have been made clearly evident from the creation of the world, being recognized by the created beings, leaving them without excuse.  Being thus aware of God, you see, they gave Him neither the glory nor gratitude due Him as God, but instead were rendered useless in their reasoning and their hearts were further clouded with nonsense.”
<br />    – Romans 1:20-21</p>
]]></description>
            <pubDate>Thu, 20 Oct 2022 12:00:58 -0700</pubDate>
            <enclosure url="https://feeds.soundcloud.com/stream/1366959100-apologeticspodcast-humanity-reality-and-contradiction.mp3" length="54707412" type="audio/mpeg"/>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">52319CC3-5145-4493-A6B4-27D924E40068</guid>
            <itunes:duration>3419</itunes:duration>
            <itunes:episodeType>full</itunes:episodeType>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>The God Who is Clearly Seen</title>
            <link>https://apologetics.com/god-is-seen/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[On this show we take a presuppositional look at how all men everywhere are subject to the laws which govern creation. As subjects to the physical laws all around them, all men come face to face everyday with the eternal power and divine nature of God (Romans 1:20). Learn how to stand firm on the truth of God’s revelation while pressing the inescapable self-revelation of God in nature. To this end the Christian will be equipped with the spiritual weapons that are mighty for the pulling down of every reasoning that exalts itself against God.]]></description>
            <pubDate>Mon, 10 Oct 2022 20:42:05 -0700</pubDate>
            <enclosure url="https://feeds.soundcloud.com/stream/1360513807-apologeticspodcast-the-god-who-is-clearly-seen.mp3" length="54102207" type="audio/mpeg"/>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">359BBF51-16F9-44D4-8F0C-A1288CEFA0F5</guid>
            <itunes:duration>3381</itunes:duration>
            <itunes:episodeType>full</itunes:episodeType>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>The Science of Knowing God</title>
            <link>https://apologetics.com/the-science-of-knowing-god/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[If all men are without excuse because of the creation that we live in, then scientists and those who cling to science as their “savior” and arbiter of truth are without excuse to a maximum degree. The goal of tonight’s show is to unpack that thesis and show exactly why scientists those who believe so ardently in science are without excuse.]]></description>
            <pubDate>Thu, 22 Sep 2022 08:39:24 -0700</pubDate>
            <enclosure url="https://feeds.soundcloud.com/stream/1347531256-apologeticspodcast-the-science-of-knowing-god.mp3" length="54664839" type="audio/mpeg"/>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">EB896083-2FC2-4D45-BD01-D523EE6D17E9</guid>
            <itunes:duration>3374</itunes:duration>
            <itunes:episodeType>full</itunes:episodeType>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Confessing Christ and Four Key Questions For Self Examination</title>
            <link>https://apologetics.com/confessing-christ/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[In the context of todays confusing messages about what it means to be a Christian, Bob Parucha and Michael Robirds discuss 4 fundamental questions Christians can ask themselves to confirm that they are being faithful as followers of Christ. Church membership and its importance is also discussed.]]></description>
            <pubDate>Thu, 22 Sep 2022 08:37:39 -0700</pubDate>
            <enclosure url="https://feeds.soundcloud.com/stream/1346786776-apologeticspodcast-confessing-christ-and-four-key-questions-for-self-examination.mp3" length="54508045" type="audio/mpeg"/>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">DBF0F704-B1A6-49EB-960C-6F0660EC6244</guid>
            <itunes:duration>3406</itunes:duration>
            <itunes:episodeType>full</itunes:episodeType>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>The Other Genevan</title>
            <link>https://apologetics.com/modern-self-2/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[On this episode of the Apologetics.com Radio, Dr. Harry Edwards, together with Lenny Esposito and Dr. Jacob Daniel discuss the major ideas of Jean-Jacques Rousseau which have laid the foundation for much of the self-centered, emotive, and blame-shifting behaviors of society in the West today. This discussion is based on chapter 3 of Carl Trueman's book "The Rise and Triumph of the Modern Self: Cultural Amnesia, Expressive Individualism, and the Road to Sexual Revolution"]]></description>
            <pubDate>Thu, 08 Sep 2022 11:54:31 -0700</pubDate>
            <enclosure url="https://feeds.soundcloud.com/stream/1340237569-apologeticspodcast-the-other-genevan.mp3" length="64036529" type="audio/mpeg"/>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">CFAD8E16-05AA-4C28-A835-5DD151BA1CA2</guid>
            <itunes:duration>3201</itunes:duration>
            <itunes:episodeType>full</itunes:episodeType>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Resacralizing a Third World Culture</title>
            <link>https://apologetics.com/resacralize-a-third-world-culture/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[How do we turn a secularized culture from godlessness to one that recognizes the supernatural and the transcendent? It's a wide chasm between spiritual apathy and Christianity, but can we move society closer to acknowledge the failed ideas that thwarts human flourishing and see that the only way forward is to trust the redeeming work of Christ which leads to true peace and happiness? Listen as we continue to discuss chapter 2 of Carl Trueman's "The Rise and Triumph of the Modern Self: Cultural Amnesia, Expressive Individualism, and the Road to Sexual Revolution."]]></description>
            <pubDate>Fri, 26 Aug 2022 14:28:39 -0700</pubDate>
            <enclosure url="https://feeds.soundcloud.com/stream/1332032875-apologeticspodcast-resacralizing-a-third-world-culture.mp3" length="64042798" type="audio/mpeg"/>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">6B1D9BE3-D61B-461E-8675-9557BA40A24B</guid>
            <itunes:duration>3202</itunes:duration>
            <itunes:episodeType>full</itunes:episodeType>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Should Pastors Be Fired for Supporting Abortion?</title>
            <link>https://soundcloud.com/apologeticspodcast/should-pastors-be-fired-for-supporting-abortion?utm_source=clipboard&amp;utm_medium=text&amp;utm_campaign=social_sharing</link>
            <description><![CDATA[In this episode on the Church and State Report, Logan and Ben discuss whether pastors should be fired for supporting abortion and what we should be doing about it.]]></description>
            <pubDate>Thu, 04 Aug 2022 11:44:49 -0700</pubDate>
            <enclosure url="https://feeds.soundcloud.com/stream/1318015747-apologeticspodcast-should-pastors-be-fired-for-supporting-abortion.mp3" length="54419020" type="audio/mpeg"/>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">DE3C8D59-AC33-4664-ACF6-581DFA91B32F</guid>
            <itunes:duration>3401</itunes:duration>
            <itunes:episodeType>full</itunes:episodeType>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Jesus is the Way, the Truth, and the Life: Why the Dobbs Decision is Only the Beginning</title>
            <link>https://soundcloud.com/apologeticspodcast/jesus-is-the-way-the-truth-and-the-life-why-the-dobbs-decision-is-only-the-beginning?utm_source=clipboard&amp;utm_medium=text&amp;utm_campaign=social_sharing</link>
            <description><![CDATA[Why is the recent Supreme Court ruling about the Constitution in relation to what is commonly called abortion significant? What does it mean to truly be a pro-life culture and civilization? What further work must be done? Join your host, Daniel Adrean, who is blessed to be a deacon of the supporting sponsor Branch of Hope Orthodox Presbyterian Church in Torrance, as he seeks to answer these questions (and more) and as he labors to lay a Biblical foundation for God’s creation of all humans, human dignity and personhood, just versus unjust violence, and more!]]></description>
            <pubDate>Thu, 04 Aug 2022 11:41:49 -0700</pubDate>
            <enclosure url="https://feeds.soundcloud.com/stream/1317957097-apologeticspodcast-jesus-is-the-way-the-truth-and-the-life-why-the-dobbs-decision-is-only-the-beginning.mp3" length="53598566" type="audio/mpeg"/>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">6FD7F1D9-FD41-45A1-AA82-7419F43569C1</guid>
            <itunes:duration>3349</itunes:duration>
            <itunes:episodeType>full</itunes:episodeType>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>What Is Human Dignity?</title>
            <link>https://apologetics.com/dignity/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[In this episode of the Apologetics.com Radio Show Dr. Harry Edwards interviews Dr. Jacob Daniel on what it means to posses human dignity.]]></description>
            <pubDate>Tue, 26 Jul 2022 11:43:00 -0700</pubDate>
            <enclosure url="https://feeds.soundcloud.com/stream/1312279483-apologeticspodcast-what-is-human-dignity.mp3" length="102483746" type="audio/mpeg"/>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">1AA97E66-D6E9-452B-B5EA-31234CB5C1B2</guid>
            <itunes:duration>3155</itunes:duration>
            <itunes:episodeType>full</itunes:episodeType>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Objective Truth in the Abortion Discussion</title>
            <link>https://apologetics.com/objective-truth-in-the-abortion-discussion/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[On this episode of the Apologetics.com Show, Jon Noyes discusses the importance of objective truth in the abortion discussion. He entertains callers on this important and timely topic.]]></description>
            <pubDate>Thu, 21 Jul 2022 08:43:43 -0700</pubDate>
            <enclosure url="https://feeds.soundcloud.com/stream/1309281505-apologeticspodcast-objective-truth-in-the-abortion-discussion.mp3" length="55377818" type="audio/mpeg"/>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">9385EFB8-9ED7-46ED-A4E2-488AC05F02C8</guid>
            <itunes:duration>3461</itunes:duration>
            <itunes:episodeType>full</itunes:episodeType>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Apologetics Lessons from the Book of Acts</title>
            <link>https://apologetics.com/acts/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[The book of Acts is an inspired historical record of the early church as they went about preaching the gospel wherever they went. As they did this, it necessarily led to them engaging in the apologetic endeavor. Join Jason Gallagher and Daniel Adrean as they discuss everyday evangelistic principles from the Book of Acts that lead directly to apologetic principles you can use as you engage the world around you. Contact Jason at www.apologetics.com with questions or comments.]]></description>
            <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jun 2022 13:49:18 -0700</pubDate>
            <enclosure url="https://feeds.soundcloud.com/stream/1293161767-apologeticspodcast-apologetics-lessons-from-the-book-of-acts.mp3" length="52322536" type="audio/mpeg"/>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">46AA02B3-1C53-4FCC-A150-A6E326DAF713</guid>
            <itunes:duration>3270</itunes:duration>
            <itunes:episodeType>full</itunes:episodeType>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Science Displays the Attributes of God</title>
            <link>https://apologetics.com/attributes-of-god/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[Have you ever met someone who says “I only believe in what I can see or touch?” of those who say “I believe in science” not religion. In this show, learn how you can use the discoveries of Science to prove the invisible attributes of God and the immaterial nature of the world around us. If you have questions or comments, please contact Jason at www.apologetics.com]]></description>
            <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jun 2022 13:46:17 -0700</pubDate>
            <enclosure url="https://feeds.soundcloud.com/stream/1293156223-apologeticspodcast-science-displays-the-attributes-of-god.mp3" length="55259118" type="audio/mpeg"/>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">A58BC6A3-90B3-468E-819B-1933BA04098C</guid>
            <itunes:duration>3453</itunes:duration>
            <itunes:episodeType>full</itunes:episodeType>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Biblical Concept of Humanity in Post-Christian Culture</title>
            <link>https://apologetics.com/humanity/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>How is the current generation moving away from the Biblical conception of humanity?  Join Jon, Eric, Joel, and special guest hip hop artist Joe Salant as they talk human exceptionalism, contemporary culture, and mankind as purposefully created being.  
<br />“Then God said, 'Let Us make humanity in Our image, according to Our likeness, and let them have dominion...' ”
<br />  —  Genesis 1:26   
<br />“For although they were aware of God, they refused Him the the glory due Him as God and refused Him gratitude as well; so they became meaningless in their rationales and got lost in the darkness of their foolish hearts.”
<br />  — Romans 1:21</p>
]]></description>
            <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jun 2022 12:01:13 -0700</pubDate>
            <enclosure url="https://feeds.soundcloud.com/stream/1285032595-apologeticspodcast-biblical-concept-of-humanity-in-post-christian-culture.mp3" length="138065609" type="audio/mpeg"/>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">502EE25E-7C7F-4B8F-AF38-03FFA25EA63C</guid>
            <itunes:duration>3451</itunes:duration>
            <itunes:episodeType>full</itunes:episodeType>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>The Rise and Triumph of the Modern Self [Part 1]</title>
            <link>https://apologetics.com/modern-self/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[In this episode Dr. Harry Edwards leads a discussion with Lenny Esposito and Dr. Jacob Daniel on the first chapter of Carl Trueman's book &quot;The Rise and Triumph of the Modern Self.&quot; Specifically we cover the Philip Rieff's cultural development beginning with what he calls the Political Man, then on to the Religious Man, to the Economic Man, and finally onto the Psychological Man.]]></description>
            <pubDate>Sun, 05 Jun 2022 18:23:57 -0700</pubDate>
            <enclosure url="https://feeds.soundcloud.com/stream/1281690964-apologeticspodcast-the-rise-and-triumph-of-the-modern-self-part-1.mp3" length="100574367" type="audio/mpeg"/>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">DEB04F44-71DB-4778-B77C-EB65760DBE40</guid>
            <itunes:duration>3078</itunes:duration>
            <itunes:episodeType>full</itunes:episodeType>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Abortion: What Is It and Why Does It Matter?</title>
            <link>https://apologetics.com/abortion/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>Abortion is dominating the political landscape again with a leaked draft of a Supreme Court decision.   Join Jon, Eric, Chris and Joel as they discuss what abortion is from theological and cultural perspectives.  
<br />“They spilled innocent blood— the blood of their own sons and daughters—sacrificing them to the idols of Canaan. And so the land became polluted with blood.”
<br />  —  Psalm 106:38</p>
]]></description>
            <pubDate>Tue, 10 May 2022 16:47:00 -0700</pubDate>
            <enclosure url="https://feeds.soundcloud.com/stream/1265842918-apologeticspodcast-abortion-what-is-it-and-why-does-it-matter.mp3" length="55779059" type="audio/mpeg"/>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">1FB69427-C3F0-493D-A05A-E58F0E54532F</guid>
            <itunes:duration>3486</itunes:duration>
            <itunes:episodeType>full</itunes:episodeType>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Jesus Defeats Death</title>
            <description><![CDATA[Listen as Jon Noyes discusses the resurrection account according to Mark and the implication Jesus' defeat of death has for your life now.]]></description>
            <pubDate>Sat, 16 Apr 2022 14:24:31 -0700</pubDate>
            <enclosure url="https://feeds.soundcloud.com/stream/1251480001-apologeticspodcast-jesus-defeats-death.mp3" length="55187229" type="audio/mpeg"/>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">9B533E6C-EC1C-4D9F-BA08-5192419A2471</guid>
            <itunes:duration>3449</itunes:duration>
            <itunes:episodeType>full</itunes:episodeType>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Death and Resurrection: Their Roles in Biblical Faith and Apologetics</title>
            <description><![CDATA[In this episode of the Apologetics.com radio show, sponsored by Branch of Hope Orthodox Presbyterian Church in Torrance, California, daniel adrean, who is profoundly blessed to be a deacon in the sponsoring church, discusses what role death and resurrection plays both in the Biblical Christian faith itself and in its defense.]]></description>
            <pubDate>Sat, 16 Apr 2022 14:22:22 -0700</pubDate>
            <enclosure url="https://feeds.soundcloud.com/stream/1251471949-apologeticspodcast-death-and-resurrection-their-roles-in-biblical-faith-and-apologetics.mp3" length="53954667" type="audio/mpeg"/>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">D6336340-F954-48EA-802C-8B573036F8A7</guid>
            <itunes:duration>3372</itunes:duration>
            <itunes:episodeType>full</itunes:episodeType>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>The Case for Postmillennialism [Part 2 of 2]</title>
            <link>http://www.apologetics.com</link>
            <description><![CDATA[Listen as Jon and Chris continue their conversation about postmillennialism. On this episode they discuss why eschatology matters with some callers on the show.]]></description>
            <pubDate>Sat, 19 Mar 2022 09:29:53 -0700</pubDate>
            <enclosure url="https://feeds.soundcloud.com/stream/1235186527-apologeticspodcast-the-case-for-postmillennialism-part-2-of-2.mp3" length="55392029" type="audio/mpeg"/>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">46A6AB33-AC7A-4EB2-9A9F-50BCCF3232E9</guid>
            <itunes:duration>3461</itunes:duration>
            <itunes:episodeType>full</itunes:episodeType>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>The Case for Postmillennialism [Part 1 of 2]</title>
            <link>http://www.apologetics.com</link>
            <description><![CDATA[On this episode of the Apologetics.com Radio Show Jon and Chris talk about eschatology and begin making the case for postmillennialism. They also take listener questions.]]></description>
            <pubDate>Sat, 19 Mar 2022 09:27:47 -0700</pubDate>
            <enclosure url="https://feeds.soundcloud.com/stream/1235183797-apologeticspodcast-the-case-for-postmillennialism-part-1-of-2.mp3" length="57015800" type="audio/mpeg"/>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">B60FFD18-19EA-473B-9B69-054C3AE3D75C</guid>
            <itunes:duration>3563</itunes:duration>
            <itunes:episodeType>full</itunes:episodeType>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Addressing Barriers to Christianity</title>
            <link>https://apologetics.com/podcasts/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[On this show Dr. Harry Edwards leads a discussion addressing internal and external barriers to Christianity, i.e., anti-intellectualism, scientism, POE, etc. On the panel are Dr. Jacob Daniel.]]></description>
            <pubDate>Thu, 03 Mar 2022 08:00:06 -0800</pubDate>
            <enclosure url="https://feeds.soundcloud.com/stream/1225660249-apologeticspodcast-addressing-barriers-to-christianity.mp3" length="105555718" type="audio/mpeg"/>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">6B8FC96C-51A3-4CF9-9C49-A891299ABF4A</guid>
            <itunes:duration>3257</itunes:duration>
            <itunes:episodeType>full</itunes:episodeType>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Free Speech, Censorship, and The Defense of the Scriptures</title>
            <link>http://www.apologetics.com</link>
            <description><![CDATA[Speech, both oral and written, are at the heart of God's Character and Nature. God spoke the world into existence and He continues to uphold creation by the power of His Word today. Jesus, the Second Person of the Trinity, is the Word Become Flesh and He is also the Truth. With that in view, why do we find ourselves surrounded by a myriad of fake news, misinformation, censorship, and conspiracy theories. Has the enemy, who has been distorting truth and God's Word since the beginning just continuing his old tricks? Is confusion the natural state of things in a nation that has walked away from the God of Truth? Join Jason and Daniel as they look at our current cultural landscape and seek to put these questions in proper perspective according to Scripture. We pray you are blessed as you seek to bring hope and truth to the world around you!]]></description>
            <pubDate>Mon, 21 Feb 2022 20:35:43 -0800</pubDate>
            <enclosure url="https://feeds.soundcloud.com/stream/1220252569-apologeticspodcast-free-speech-censorship-and-the-defense-of-the-scriptures.mp3" length="54915555" type="audio/mpeg"/>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">C6A33196-FA2F-4319-9DD8-0690E4C249BC</guid>
            <itunes:duration>3432</itunes:duration>
            <itunes:episodeType>full</itunes:episodeType>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>A United Church: The Ultimate Apologetic</title>
            <link>http://www.apologetics.com</link>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>What is the “unity of the faith” that Paul refers to in his letter to the Ephesians (4:16)? Join Jon, Eric, and Joel discuss the New Testament scriptures about what Francis Schaeffer called “the Final Apologetic” in which the world sees the undeniable truth of the gospel in a church unified in love and truth.</p>

<p>“From [Messiah as head] the whole body, fitted and held together by every ligament’s support, grows and builds itself up in love through the work of each individual part.”
<br />-- Eph. 4:13</p>

<p>“I also have given them that glory which You gave Me, so that they may be one, as We are one--I in them, and You in Me--that they may be completed into oneness, so that the world may know ...”
<br />-- John 17:22-23a</p>
]]></description>
            <pubDate>Tue, 08 Feb 2022 09:33:10 -0800</pubDate>
            <enclosure url="https://feeds.soundcloud.com/stream/1212190216-apologeticspodcast-a-united-church-the-ultimate-apologetic.mp3" length="54901763" type="audio/mpeg"/>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">3FA02DB4-5E37-4EB0-997D-CF378170AE23</guid>
            <itunes:duration>3431</itunes:duration>
            <itunes:episodeType>full</itunes:episodeType>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>How To Reach Generation Z With The Gospel</title>
            <link>http://www.apologetics.com</link>
            <description><![CDATA[In this episode of the Apologetics.com Radio Show, Dr. Harry Edwards, along with Lenny Esposito and Jonathan Noyes discuss the special traits that make up Generation Z. Then we talk through ways to reach them with the Gospel.]]></description>
            <pubDate>Thu, 03 Feb 2022 14:19:30 -0800</pubDate>
            <enclosure url="https://feeds.soundcloud.com/stream/1209392299-apologeticspodcast-how-to-reach-them-with-the-gospel.mp3" length="62598749" type="audio/mpeg"/>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">82B4996B-33FC-4E7E-B05A-92FF5B0F2173</guid>
            <itunes:duration>3130</itunes:duration>
            <itunes:episodeType>full</itunes:episodeType>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Conscience: Our Moral Compass</title>
            <link>http://www.apologetics.com</link>
            <description><![CDATA[In this episode of the Apologetics.com Show Dr. Harry Edwards, together with Dr. Jacob Daniel and Lenny Esposito discuss C.S. Lewis' Moral Argument, its objective nature and universality. We also cover the good Christianity has brought to the world and rebuttals to skeptics who claim it has done more harm than good, i.e. Crusades, Inquisition, etc.]]></description>
            <pubDate>Tue, 25 Jan 2022 22:12:51 -0800</pubDate>
            <enclosure url="https://apologeticscom.s3.amazonaws.com/RadioShows/220122_conscience.mp3" length="50623135" type="audio/mpeg"/>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">BC45142C-78D2-4363-8E34-BA806EA345D6</guid>
            <itunes:duration>3164</itunes:duration>
            <itunes:episodeType>full</itunes:episodeType>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>BabylonBee and Musk: A Case for Apologetics</title>
            <link>https://apologetics.com/babylonbee-and-musk/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[In this episode of the Apologetics.com Radio Show, Dr. Harry Edwards leads a discussion on the interview BablyonBee did with Elon Musk in December of 2021. Some of the topics covered are what Mr. Musk called the “God of Spinoza” when asked if he believed in God and other missed opportunities for further apologetics conversations. One example of a major mishandling of an apologetics moment was Musk’s response to an invitation to “accept Christ.” His response was that he liked Jesus’ teachings and proceeded to enumerate those virtues that are good to follow. Listen to find out how BabylonBee bungled an opportune apologetics moment, and what Christians can learn from the interaction.]]></description>
            <pubDate>Mon, 17 Jan 2022 11:06:43 -0800</pubDate>
            <enclosure url="https://apologeticscom.s3.amazonaws.com/RadioShows/220115_musk.mp3" length="55429227" type="audio/mpeg"/>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">7F8AF7CA-1BC7-4EF2-9391-ABDE978337CE</guid>
            <itunes:duration>3464</itunes:duration>
            <itunes:episodeType>full</itunes:episodeType>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Astro Engineer Explains the Star of Bethlehem</title>
            <link>http://www.apologetics.com</link>
            <description><![CDATA[Listen as Jon Noyes talks to Dr. Leslie Wickman about the Star of Bethlehem. What was it? When did it appear? And other related questions that might tell us more about the celestial phenomenon that led the wise men to the place where Jesus was born.]]></description>
            <pubDate>Mon, 20 Dec 2021 16:38:22 -0800</pubDate>
            <enclosure url="https://apologeticscom.s3.amazonaws.com/RadioShows/211218_xmas.mp3" length="54601668" type="audio/mpeg"/>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">AC3DA4A8-75A8-451B-858B-81823C6A3BB1</guid>
            <itunes:duration>3413</itunes:duration>
            <itunes:episodeType>full</itunes:episodeType>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Proclaiming the True Christ of Christmas</title>
            <link>https://apologetics.com/proclaiming-the-true-christ-in-christmas/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[Billions of people celebrate Christmas in some form but many have no idea just how significant it really is. On this show, we will be sharing how to effectively navigate conversations and clearly communicate the gospel with those who hold a variety of false views about Jesus Christ. Jason and Tony have been sharing the gospel on the streets of Los Angeles for over a decade and you will definitely learn some new and effective ways of confirming and defending the gospel and the deity of Jesus Christ. We encourage you to share with those you love and send any questions you have to feedback@apologetics.com.]]></description>
            <pubDate>Sat, 18 Dec 2021 09:01:10 -0800</pubDate>
            <enclosure url="https://apologeticscom.s3.amazonaws.com/RadioShows/211211_xmas.mp3" length="54665616" type="audio/mpeg"/>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">4254FB6E-99B2-48ED-BDAD-83F373C56D2E</guid>
            <itunes:duration>3417</itunes:duration>
            <itunes:episodeType>full</itunes:episodeType>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Debunking Popular Christmas Myths</title>
            <link>https://apologetics.com/christmas-myths/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>Did three kings follow the star to a newborn Jesus in a stable in December? Is that in the Bible? Join Jon, Chris and, Joel as they discuss and debunk popular Christmas myths surrounding the birth of Jesus and His early days in Bethlehem.</p>

<p>“A Savior, Who is Messiah the Lord, was born for you today in the city of David. This will be the sign for you: You will find the baby swaddled and cribbed in a feeding trough.”</p>

<p>Luke 2:11-12</p>
]]></description>
            <pubDate>Tue, 07 Dec 2021 11:07:19 -0800</pubDate>
            <enclosure url="https://apologeticscom.s3.amazonaws.com/RadioShows/211204_xmas.mp3" length="55477313" type="audio/mpeg"/>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">D7E7C9F7-847D-45A3-8A16-00E486AEA309</guid>
            <itunes:duration>3467</itunes:duration>
            <itunes:episodeType>full</itunes:episodeType>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Ethos-Logos: The Starting Points and Posture of Apologetics</title>
            <link>http://www.apologetics.com</link>
            <description><![CDATA[In this episode of the Apologetics.com Radio Show, Dr. Harry Edwards, Dr. Jacob Daniel, and Lenny Esposito discuss the important and critical role reason plays in the art and science of defending the truth claims of Christianity. Specifically, they cover C.S. Lewis' four facets of rationality that make a pure naturalistic worldview untenable.]]></description>
            <pubDate>Wed, 01 Dec 2021 08:54:43 -0800</pubDate>
            <enclosure url="https://apologeticscom.s3.amazonaws.com/RadioShows/211127_ethoslogos_lq.mp3" length="55334789" type="audio/mpeg"/>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">3CF18CBE-4152-4F7B-96A7-E9C73B9241DF</guid>
            <itunes:duration>3458</itunes:duration>
            <itunes:episodeType>full</itunes:episodeType>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Covenental Apologetics</title>
            <link>https://apologetics.com/blog/2cor521/covenental/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[In this show, we discuss the topic of Covenantal Apologetics and its relationship to both believers and unbelievers. Covenantal apologetics seeks to bring Van Til’s presuppositional methodology into a more accessible and practical context. Join Jason Gallagher and special guest Grant Spear as they survey Dr. Scott Oliphint’s book “Covenantal Apologetics” and interact with a caller regarding Covenantal Apologetics relationship to the Trinity.]]></description>
            <pubDate>Tue, 23 Nov 2021 20:20:39 -0800</pubDate>
            <enclosure url="https://apologeticscom.s3.amazonaws.com/RadioShows/211113_covenantapol_aws.mp3" length="54954446" type="audio/mpeg"/>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">96567E3E-42F1-401F-9BFA-70FFBE409EBD</guid>
            <itunes:duration>3434</itunes:duration>
            <itunes:episodeType>full</itunes:episodeType>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>The Protestant Reformation</title>
            <link>http://www.apologetics.com</link>
            <description><![CDATA[On this episode of the Apologetics.com Radio show, Dr. Harry Edwards leads a discussion on a general overview of the Protestant Reformation in 1517 and some of the ideas and practices that resulted from it. Jon Noyes and Jason Gallagher join in studio for a conversation around this important and significant historical event.]]></description>
            <pubDate>Wed, 03 Nov 2021 10:22:35 -0700</pubDate>
            <enclosure url="https://apologeticscom.s3.amazonaws.com/RadioShows/211030_aws_reformation.mp3" length="54954446" type="audio/mpeg"/>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">4F88CB22-7AC3-4459-B814-620C25596C74</guid>
            <itunes:duration>3434</itunes:duration>
            <itunes:episodeType>full</itunes:episodeType>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Imagination: The Bridge Between Perception and Reason</title>
            <link>https://apologetics.com/blog/harry/imagination/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[On this episode of the Apologetics.com, Dr. Harry Edwards, Dr. Jacob Daniel, and Lenny Esposito discuss the primary role imagination plays in the art and science of defending the truth claims of Christianity to a culture that lacks the plausibility structure that allows for God’s existence. Dr. Paul Gould in his book “Cultural Apologetics” encourages the believer to “…demonstrate that the best explanation for why we make architecture and jokes, sculptures and gardens, stories and mythical creatures is because we bear the image of a God who is the master creator, comedian, and storyteller.” Imagination is a pointer to God.]]></description>
            <pubDate>Wed, 27 Oct 2021 06:34:50 -0700</pubDate>
            <enclosure url="https://apologeticscom.s3.amazonaws.com/RadioShows/211023aws_imagination.mp3" length="27217629" type="audio/mpeg"/>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">8BCDAE5D-6E2F-45FE-8994-8FF3B26461AD</guid>
            <itunes:duration>3402</itunes:duration>
            <itunes:episodeType>full</itunes:episodeType>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Back on the Dining Table: Religion and Politics</title>
            <link>https://apologetics.com/podcasts/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>In this episode of the Apologetics.com Radio Show, Dr. Jacob Daniel, Dr. Harry Edwards, and special guest Logan Zeppieri the proper role religion in general, Christianity in particular play in civil government and politics. Here we talk about some of the harmful effects of a society who has been socialized into avoiding civil discussions around the subjects of religion and politics, especially how those two relate to each other. Some of the ideas covered here are:
<br />– What it means to “Render unto Caesar the things that are Caesar’s, and unto God the things that are God’s.”
<br />– the Reformation and it’s connection to the U.S. Constitution.
<br />– the challenge of living in a pluralistic society.
<br />– Two Kingdoms doctrine.
<br />– other related topics.</p>

<p>For the notes, go to https://apologetics.com/blog/harry/back-on-the-dinner-table-religion-and-politics/</p>
]]></description>
            <pubDate>Mon, 18 Oct 2021 21:48:08 -0700</pubDate>
            <enclosure url="https://apologeticscom.s3.amazonaws.com/RadioShows/211026_government64kbits.mp3" length="30413763" type="audio/mpeg"/>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">A6D0F4BA-02A1-4CEE-A40B-F321001FB46E</guid>
            <itunes:duration>3801</itunes:duration>
            <itunes:episodeType>full</itunes:episodeType>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Are We Reaping What We've Sown? Discussing our Reason for Hope in the Midst of Trying Times</title>
            <link>https://apologetics.com/blog/2cor521/hope/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[Is increased sin, darkness and evil, God's plan for the future? Or is it simply the logical outworking of a people and nation who has abandoned God's Law and Precepts? Join Jason and Tony as they discuss this topic with the backdrop of Deuteronomy 28 in view. The related topic of the "End Times" definitely comes into this discussion and we interact with callers along these lines. For follow up, email Jason at jason@apologetics.com.]]></description>
            <pubDate>Mon, 11 Oct 2021 15:30:09 -0700</pubDate>
            <enclosure url="https://apologeticscom.s3.amazonaws.com/RadioShows/211009_endtimes.mp3" length="27217629" type="audio/mpeg"/>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">B0AE5566-A54D-4D0B-92D3-128B8939D668</guid>
            <itunes:duration>3402</itunes:duration>
            <itunes:episodeType>full</itunes:episodeType>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>The Embattled Church: Sinners, Saints, and Charlatans</title>
            <link>https://apologetics.com/resources-2/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>85% of young adults today say one of the reasons they do not go to church is because of the hypocrisy of believers. It’s a valid defeater of Christianity. Why would an unbeliever change his or her behavior when adherents of Christianity themselves do not abide by their own standards. It’s easy and convenient to dismiss the accusation as a red herring, as some Christian apologists do. This approach however only further adds distance to those we are genuinely seeking God.</p>

<p>On this show, Dr. Harry Edwards, Dr. Jacob Daniel and special guest Anthony Costello discuss their approach to this challenge infused with a conversation around C.S. Lewis’ last few chapters of Mere Christianity in which he seeks to provide wisdom on the problem of Christian hypocrisy.</p>
]]></description>
            <pubDate>Mon, 04 Oct 2021 08:53:42 -0700</pubDate>
            <enclosure url="https://apologeticscom.s3.amazonaws.com/RadioShows/211002_hypocrisy.mp3" length="27134455" type="audio/mpeg"/>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">3789BE69-A70D-4D89-A2CF-B7E54F8FEA74</guid>
            <itunes:duration>3391</itunes:duration>
            <itunes:episodeType>full</itunes:episodeType>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Reenchantment: Capturing the Imagination for Christ</title>
            <link>https://apologetics.com/resources-2/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[One of the reasons today's society has a tough time believing in God is because it has lost its ability to imagine the idea of transcendence, something beyond the natural world. For the skeptic nothing exists beyond the five senses. If it cannot be directly observed or tested in the lab, it does not exist. This commitment to naturalism to a great extent frustrates one's ability to discover truth, putting limits to acquiring knowledge, much less knowledge about God. In this episode Dr. Jacob Daniel and Dr. Harry Edwards with special guest Logan Zeppieri discuss ways to help our modern society explore the plausibility of the supernatural as a pointer to God.]]></description>
            <pubDate>Tue, 28 Sep 2021 08:47:05 -0700</pubDate>
            <enclosure url="https://apologeticscom.s3.amazonaws.com/RadioShows/210925_reenchantment.mp3" length="28216342" type="audio/mpeg"/>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">47396244-D8A3-4A43-9643-1E374B8EC288</guid>
            <itunes:duration>3527</itunes:duration>
            <itunes:episodeType>full</itunes:episodeType>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Deconversion Part 2</title>
            <link>https://apologetics.com/podcasts/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[On this episode of the Apologetics.com Radio Show, Jon, Chang, and Chris continue the conversation about the popular trend of reconversions. There has been a wave of famous Christians walking away from their faith (Josh Harris, John Steinguard, Rhett and Link, etc.) Why are they reconverting? What can we say to our friends who are wrestling with their faith? There are just some of the questions we talk about on this episode.]]></description>
            <pubDate>Mon, 20 Sep 2021 17:17:26 -0700</pubDate>
            <enclosure url="https://apologeticscom.s3.amazonaws.com/RadioShows/210918_deconversion2.mp3" length="54857459" type="audio/mpeg"/>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">BD882CED-0B3C-4AEE-A91E-30B5E34D3E14</guid>
            <itunes:duration>3429</itunes:duration>
            <itunes:episodeType>full</itunes:episodeType>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Christianity and the Arts</title>
            <link>https://apologetics.com/blog/jnoyes/christianity-and-the-arts/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[Listen to Jon, Eric, and special guest Chris Jenkins as they have a conversation about the arts and entertainment from a Christian worldview.]]></description>
            <pubDate>Sat, 11 Sep 2021 17:30:18 -0700</pubDate>
            <enclosure url="https://apologeticscom.s3.amazonaws.com/RadioShows/210911_arts.mp3" length="55120794" type="audio/mpeg"/>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">0F324D65-603A-4DBB-9FB0-7AB84C7DCC6A</guid>
            <itunes:duration>3445</itunes:duration>
            <itunes:episodeType>full</itunes:episodeType>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Urban Apologtics Book Review Ch. 1: Restoring Black Dignity</title>
            <link>https://apologetics.com/blog/2cor521/urban-apologetics-book-review-ch-1-restoring-black-dignity/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[In this show we begin our review of Pastor Eric Mason’s new book Urban Apologetics. This book is packed with practical and relevant information as it relates to reaching the black community with the gospel. Join us as we dig into Chapter 1: Restoring Black Dignity and take calls from our listeners.]]></description>
            <pubDate>Sat, 10 Jul 2021 14:31:42 -0700</pubDate>
            <enclosure url="https://apologeticscom.s3.amazonaws.com/RadioShows/210710_urbanapologetics.mp3" length="55901103" type="audio/mpeg"/>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">7CABA28A-FC92-4FD0-920D-042D7910AF0C</guid>
            <itunes:duration>3494</itunes:duration>
            <itunes:episodeType>full</itunes:episodeType>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Disenchantment: The Emptying of the World</title>
            <link>https://apologetics.com/blog/harry/disenchantment-the-emptying-of-the-world/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[On this episode of the Apologetics.com Radio, Dr. Harry Edwards along with Lenny Esposito discuss what it means to live in a disenchanted world. They cover the basic philosophical genealogy and causes that brought about society’s disregard for the supernatural and an adoption of a purely naturalistic worldview.]]></description>
            <pubDate>Sat, 28 Aug 2021 14:07:42 -0700</pubDate>
            <enclosure url="https://apologeticscom.s3.amazonaws.com/RadioShows/210828_disenchantment.mp3" length="55017119" type="audio/mpeg"/>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">595C2E95-2C84-4267-9B9A-E5B1052B5464</guid>
            <itunes:duration>3438</itunes:duration>
            <itunes:episodeType>full</itunes:episodeType>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Problem of Evil</title>
            <link>https://apologetics.com/podcasts/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>Join Jon and Eric as they consider the issues with believing in an all-powerful and benevolent Being Who allows bad things to happen.</p>

<p>“For as high as the heavens extend above the ground, so are my ways beyond your ways, and my thoughts beyond your thoughts.”
<br />Isaiah 55:9</p>
]]></description>
            <pubDate>Sat, 07 Aug 2021 09:45:26 -0700</pubDate>
            <enclosure url="https://apologeticscom.s3.amazonaws.com/RadioShows/210807_poe.mp3" length="55382436" type="audio/mpeg"/>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">C07AEB16-4678-47B1-BB10-A3E47D02A777</guid>
            <itunes:duration>3461</itunes:duration>
            <itunes:episodeType>full</itunes:episodeType>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Urban Apologetics Part 2: All White Everything</title>
            <link>http://www.apologetics.com</link>
            <description><![CDATA[In this show we review chapter 2 of the book “Urban Apologetics” by Eric Mason which addresses the idea of whitewashed Christianity. In it we explore the definition of whitewashing and how it relates to God’s command for us to be truth tellers. Tune in to discover some of the foundational issues behind whitewashing and what an appropriate Christian response should be to this issue.]]></description>
            <pubDate>Sat, 04 Sep 2021 17:46:12 -0700</pubDate>
            <enclosure url="https://apologeticscom.s3.amazonaws.com/RadioShows/210904_urbanapologetics2.mp3" length="27312715" type="audio/mpeg"/>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">5EBCAD9C-8AF7-4176-9B1C-897BC81570C3</guid>
            <itunes:duration>3414</itunes:duration>
            <itunes:episodeType>full</itunes:episodeType>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Made in the Image of God vs CRT and Identity Politics</title>
            <link>https://www.apologetics.com</link>
            <description><![CDATA[Bob Parucha and Michael Robert discuss the implications and meaning of the biblical concept of being made in the image of God. Frances Schaeffer’s and Voddie Baucham’s works are discussed comparing these with current ideology of CRT and its implications for human value and meaning.]]></description>
            <pubDate>Sat, 14 Aug 2021 10:19:28 -0700</pubDate>
            <enclosure url="https://apologeticscom.s3.amazonaws.com/RadioShows/210814_crt.mp3" length="27098719" type="audio/mpeg"/>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">0E65D22F-299F-4D06-B078-5FA95AED0C37</guid>
            <itunes:duration>3387</itunes:duration>
            <itunes:episodeType>full</itunes:episodeType>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Deconversion</title>
            <link>https://www.apologetics.com</link>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>Jon, Eric, and Joel discuss what to make of the current phenomenon of deconversion experiences in the light of the scriptures.</p>

<p>"Beloved, although I made every effort to write to you about the salvation we share​, I felt it necessary to write and urge you to contend earnestly for the faith ..." 
<br />  -- Jude 1:3</p>
]]></description>
            <pubDate>Mon, 19 Jul 2021 09:27:05 -0700</pubDate>
            <enclosure url="https://apologeticscom.s3.amazonaws.com/RadioShows/210703_deconversion.mp3" length="55583036" type="audio/mpeg"/>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">5CD0399A-85F7-4B25-8B97-34EB553A2A5E</guid>
            <itunes:duration>3474</itunes:duration>
            <itunes:episodeType>full</itunes:episodeType>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Reengineering Society: How CRT is Aiming for our Children</title>
            <link>https://harryedwards.com/podcast/reengineering-society-how-crt-is-aiming-for-our-children/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[Listen as Anthony Costello, Dr. Jacob Daniel and Dr. Harry Edwards discuss the basic tenets of Critical Race Theory and how a progressive agenda is shaping the identity of a younger generation in the United States.]]></description>
            <pubDate>Mon, 28 Jun 2021 18:47:49 -0700</pubDate>
            <enclosure url="http://apologeticscom.s3.amazonaws.com/RadioShows/210626_crtandkids.mp3" length="54266465" type="audio/mpeg"/>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">6520A2A3-AEFE-472F-BA21-12B002BCE4EA</guid>
            <itunes:duration>3392</itunes:duration>
            <itunes:episodeType>full</itunes:episodeType>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Bible Translations and the Most Powerful Apologetic</title>
            <link>https://apologetics.com/radio/?sermon_id=311</link>
            <description><![CDATA[On this episode of the Apologetics.com Radio Show, Dr. Harry Edwards leads a discussion with Jon Noyes and Jason Gallagher on a couple of apologetics topics which include Bible translations and evangelism.]]></description>
            <pubDate>Sat, 05 Jun 2021 15:17:57 -0700</pubDate>
            <enclosure url="https://apologeticscom.s3.amazonaws.com/RadioShows/210529_allhost.mp3" length="55924091" type="audio/mpeg"/>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">3B386AF3-F361-463A-8077-D62B57C0C74C</guid>
            <itunes:duration>3498</itunes:duration>
            <itunes:episodeType>full</itunes:episodeType>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Evangelism and Our Most Powerful Apologetic</title>
            <link>https://apologetics.com/radio/?sermon_id=310</link>
            <description><![CDATA[Join host Jason Gallagher and Tony Yu as they discuss the nuts and bolts of evangelism and how it impacts our apologetics. You won't want to miss the apologetic tool that Charles Spurgeon called our most able "auxiliary" and how you can bring it into your apologetic approach.]]></description>
            <pubDate>Fri, 04 Jun 2021 13:34:27 -0700</pubDate>
            <enclosure url="http://apologeticscom.s3.amazonaws.com/RadioShows/210508_gallagher.mp3" length="56530550" type="audio/mpeg"/>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">9F49FACB-73AB-4C54-9070-324C6606B4D4</guid>
            <itunes:duration>3533</itunes:duration>
            <itunes:episodeType>full</itunes:episodeType>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>How Reasonable Is It To "Trust the Science?"</title>
            <link>https://apologetics.com/radio/?sermon_id=309</link>
            <description><![CDATA[We've all heard the admonishment to "trust the science" in various situations. But is demanding faith in science while dismissing faith in religion truly rational? In this episode, Lenny Esposito tackles the distinctions between faith, belief, and knowledge and  offers specific examples of where the tenets of the Christin faith not only proved more accurate than the invocation of science in t the last century, but also more humane.]]></description>
            <pubDate>Thu, 03 Jun 2021 12:38:21 -0700</pubDate>
            <enclosure url="http://apologeticscom.s3.amazonaws.com/RadioShows/210522_beliefs.mp3" length="54668980" type="audio/mpeg"/>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">D2B62A46-C8C7-466B-89D4-FFF7EACA0945</guid>
            <itunes:duration>3417</itunes:duration>
            <itunes:episodeType>full</itunes:episodeType>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>God's Word: Bible Translations and Resources</title>
            <link>https://apologetics.com/radio/?sermon_id=308</link>
            <description><![CDATA[This week on the show Host Jon Noyes has friend and former host Steve Van Keulen back on the show to talk about Bibles and Steve's Youtube Channel. What the differences are between english translations are as well as different types of Study Bibles and tools we can use to learn and grow in our faith.]]></description>
            <pubDate>Sat, 08 May 2021 06:57:29 -0700</pubDate>
            <enclosure url="http://apologeticscom.s3.amazonaws.com/RadioShows/210501_bible.mp3" length="55073147" type="audio/mpeg"/>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">B10CF81D-E764-4F70-BEA2-EEB1931BD054</guid>
            <itunes:duration>3442</itunes:duration>
            <itunes:episodeType>full</itunes:episodeType>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Nationalism vs. Globalism: A Christian Response</title>
            <link>http://apologetics.com/radio/?sermon_id=307</link>
            <description><![CDATA[On this episode, Dr. Harry Edwards leads a discussion on a growing trend among believers in the West called Christian nationalism and its rival, globalism. The show seeks to define these two types of allegiances and the implications for holding each view within the Christian context. On the panel are Dr. Jacob Daniel of Heritage Counsel and Mr. Lenny Esposito of Come Reason Ministries.]]></description>
            <pubDate>Sat, 01 May 2021 09:53:08 -0700</pubDate>
            <enclosure url="http://apologeticscom.s3.amazonaws.com/RadioShows/210424_nationalism.mp3" length="54145695" type="audio/mpeg"/>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">5AB8D857-F17E-45B8-A6AE-3CB7362A6248</guid>
            <itunes:duration>3384</itunes:duration>
            <itunes:episodeType>full</itunes:episodeType>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Good Friday</title>
            <link>http://apologetics.com/radio/?sermon_id=306</link>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>Jon, Eric, and Joel talk about the reality of the supernatural, the power of the Resurrection, and the historical trustworthiness of the Resurrection narrative in the Gospels.</p>

<p>"... we weren't taken in by cleverly imagined tales when we informed you of the wonder and tangible presence of our Lord Messiah Jesus, but we spoke as eyewitnesses of His splendor."
<br />-- 2 Peter 1:16</p>]]></description>
            <pubDate>Thu, 22 Apr 2021 16:54:23 -0700</pubDate>
            <enclosure url="http://apologeticscom.s3.amazonaws.com/RadioShows/210403goodfriday.mp3" length="53955524" type="audio/mpeg"/>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">391F7929-1445-44D1-9F7E-7C736F5FCD0F</guid>
            <itunes:duration>3372</itunes:duration>
            <itunes:episodeType>full</itunes:episodeType>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>The Islam Worldview: Is It True? Is It Good? Is It Beautiful?</title>
            <link>http://apologetics.com/radio/?sermon_id=305</link>
            <description><![CDATA[This week Apologetics.com teams up with Women In Apologetics and Laura Zifer Powell to discuss the Islamic worldview. Laura is a graduate of Duke University and Denver Seminary where she developed a passion for spreading the knowledge and hope of Christ. She’s traveled to nearly 30 countries to do just that. She now serves as an apologist with Women in Apologetics and specializes in Islam and ministering to Muslims. Join hosts Jon Noyes and Leslie Wickman as they explore the ins and outs of Islam.]]></description>
            <pubDate>Wed, 21 Apr 2021 16:31:00 -0700</pubDate>
            <enclosure url="http://apologeticscom.s3.amazonaws.com/RadioShows/210417_muslim.mp3" length="55667484" type="audio/mpeg"/>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">AF1A0736-28BF-49EF-B877-283139A32F54</guid>
            <itunes:duration>3479</itunes:duration>
            <itunes:episodeType>full</itunes:episodeType>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Christianity: Cross-Examined</title>
            <link>http://apologetics.com/radio/?sermon_id=304</link>
            <description><![CDATA[Bob Parucha interviews Ken Samples about his upcoming book Christianity: Cross-Examined.]]></description>
            <pubDate>Fri, 16 Apr 2021 16:14:48 -0700</pubDate>
            <enclosure url="http://apologeticscom.s3.amazonaws.com/RadioShows/210410_samples.mp3" length="54811504" type="audio/mpeg"/>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">74C5E315-D578-4761-8BEF-CE0DB1DFA8F9</guid>
            <itunes:duration>3425</itunes:duration>
            <itunes:episodeType>full</itunes:episodeType>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>