<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:itunes="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd"><channel><title>Sermons of Dr. Martyn Lloyd-Jones</title><link>https://www.mljtrust.org/</link><description>The MLJ Trust presents original audio recordings of the sermons of Dr. Martyn Lloyd-Jones (1899-1981). Dr. Lloyd-Jones was a Welsh minister who preached and taught in the Reformed tradition. He is considered by many evangelical leaders today to be an authority on biblical truth and the sufficiency of Scripture. Dr. Lloyd-Jones’ principal ministry was at Westminster Chapel, in central London, from 1939-1968, where he delivered multi-year expositions on books of the bible such as Romans, Ephesians and the Gospel of John.</description><atom:link href="https://www.mljtrust.org/sermons/podcast/" rel="self"/><language>en</language><copyright>© MLJ Trust</copyright><lastBuildDate>Sun, 01 Mar 2026 00:00:00 -0500</lastBuildDate><itunes:subtitle/><itunes:author>MLJ Trust</itunes:author><itunes:summary>The MLJ Trust presents original audio recordings of the sermons of Dr. Martyn Lloyd-Jones (1899-1981). Dr. Lloyd-Jones was a Welsh minister who preached and taught in the Reformed tradition. He is considered by many evangelical leaders today to be an authority on biblical truth and the sufficiency of Scripture. Dr. Lloyd-Jones’ principal ministry was at Westminster Chapel, in central London, from 1939-1968, where he delivered multi-year expositions on books of the bible such as Romans, Ephesians and the Gospel of John.</itunes:summary><itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit><itunes:category text="Religion &amp; Spirituality"><itunes:category text="Christianity"/></itunes:category><itunes:owner><itunes:name>Martyn Lloyd-Jones</itunes:name><itunes:email>info@mljtrust.org</itunes:email></itunes:owner><itunes:image href="https://www.mljtrust.org/static/images/mlj-podcast-1404.jpg"/><item><itunes:image href="https://www.mljtrust.org/static/images/mlj-podcast-1404.jpg"/><title>God's Goodness and Severity</title><link>https://www.mljtrust.org/sermons/book-of-romans/gods-goodness-and-severity/</link><description>Romans 11:18-22 — In previous passages, Paul has explained that because of the Jews’ unbelief, the Gentiles were granted belief through Christ. In Romans 11:18–22, Paul now warns the Gentiles against any boasting because of their new standing and salvation. There is no place for pride in a Christian’s life and Paul warns that any such feelings would cause one to suffer. In this sermon on Romans 11:18–22 titled “God’s Goodness and Severity,” Dr. Martyn Lloyd-Jones explains that the best corrective against pride is to know God, and the truth and character of God. The greatest lack would be a lack of the knowledge of God. This lack would show in one’s doctrine and view of sin, and would lead to a lack of fear of the Lord. In his closing, Dr. Lloyd-Jones also pauses to reflect on the goodness and severity of God in Romans 11:22. God is true in all of His characteristics and He is fully known in each of those character traits. One cannot say that God is good without acknowledging His severity. One cannot dwell only on the wrath of God without showing the love of God. The truest example of this is Christ on the cross. May the Christian never boast in themselves, but instead boast in Christ and all that He has done for them.</description><pubDate>Sun, 01 Mar 2026 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.mljtrust.org/sermons/book-of-romans/gods-goodness-and-severity/</guid><enclosure length="97319011" type="audio/mpeg" url="https://media.blubrry.com/mljsermons/sermons.mljtrust.org/3282-gods-goodness-and-severity.mp3"/></item><item><itunes:image href="https://www.mljtrust.org/static/images/mlj-podcast-1404.jpg"/><title>Pride</title><link>https://www.mljtrust.org/sermons/book-of-romans/pride/</link><description>Romans 11:18-22 — Why is pride so dangerous? What about pride undermines the gospel and leads people into self-deception and deceit? In this sermon on Romans 11:18–22 titled “Pride,” Dr. Martyn Lloyd-Jones preaches on the need to learn God’s word so as to fight against pride. Pride undermines the gospel because it makes people focus on themselves and their own works, justifying themselves. According to Dr. Lloyd-Jones, the great sin of many of the Jewish people who wanted to return to the law was the sin of pride. They sought to find salvation in their own identity and works but this is wholly opposed to the message of Jesus. Jesus Christ tells that one must forsake any chance of saving themselves. He tells that no works can makes one right before God. Pride makes the person look at what they do for their worth; Jesus makes them look to Him to find worth. Paul warns the church of his day about the danger of falling away from the gospel and looking to works to justify oneself. This is still a temptation for many Christians and for this reason, believers must always flee from self-righteousness and look to Jesus Christ and what He has done as Jesus alone saves.</description><pubDate>Sat, 28 Feb 2026 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.mljtrust.org/sermons/book-of-romans/pride/</guid><enclosure length="94335035" type="audio/mpeg" url="https://media.blubrry.com/mljsermons/sermons.mljtrust.org/3281-pride.mp3"/></item><item><itunes:image href="https://www.mljtrust.org/static/images/mlj-podcast-1404.jpg"/><title>None Should Boast</title><link>https://www.mljtrust.org/sermons/book-of-romans/none-should-boast/</link><description>Romans 11:18-22 — Now that Christ has come, what is the relationship between Jews and Gentiles? This is the question Dr. Martyn Lloyd-Jones seeks to answer in this sermon on Romans 11:18–22 titled “None Should Boast.” Christ Jesus has come and instituted the new covenant – the fulfilment of all of God’s Old Testament covenants. In the new covenant, there is no longer a distinction between Jew and Gentile, for all are made one by believing in Christ and in His death, burial, and resurrection. Paul makes it clear that the Jews have not been rejected in total, but only those Jews who do not believe in Jesus Christ. Dr. Lloyd-Jones points out that it is a mistake to think that the Gentiles are part of the new covenant because of anything they have done. Paul goes on to make it perfectly clear that salvation is always by grace and grace alone. Nothing either Jews or Gentiles can do can ever make them part of the people of God. It is by the grace of God given in His Son Jesus Christ that anyone can know God and love Him. Gentiles have no ground for boasting because it is all the grace of God and not human works or merit.</description><pubDate>Fri, 27 Feb 2026 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.mljtrust.org/sermons/book-of-romans/none-should-boast/</guid><enclosure length="85467960" type="audio/mpeg" url="https://media.blubrry.com/mljsermons/sermons.mljtrust.org/3280-none-should-boast.mp3"/></item><item><itunes:image href="https://www.mljtrust.org/static/images/mlj-podcast-1404.jpg"/><title>The Olive Tree</title><link>https://www.mljtrust.org/sermons/book-of-romans/the-olive-tree/</link><description>Romans 11:16-17 — In this sermon on Romans 11:16–17 titled “The Olive Tree,” Dr. Martyn Lloyd-Jones discusses what or who is the olive tree and the relationship of the Jews to the Gentiles within God’s economy of salvation. Learn of the importance to understand what Paul means in Romans 11 and the tendency to lean towards the two extremes—to make too much or too little of this relationship. What is meant by this “olive tree”? Who are the children of the promise? Listen as Dr. Martyn Lloyd-Jones dives into explaining who are the true spiritual people of God. There is a spiritual nation that surpasses the natural. Understand from where the roots of this olive tree are derived. There is a continuity that binds the Old and New Testaments: “There is only one way of salvation and it has always been the same one.” See that salvation is not a matter of nationality but of being grafted into God’s people. What does it mean that the Jews have a “special” yet not “separate” position? Rejoice that both Jews and Gentiles will be joint heirs and partake in the promised blessings of God.</description><pubDate>Thu, 26 Feb 2026 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.mljtrust.org/sermons/book-of-romans/the-olive-tree/</guid><enclosure length="96798518" type="audio/mpeg" url="https://media.blubrry.com/mljsermons/sermons.mljtrust.org/3279-the-olive-tree.mp3"/></item><item><itunes:image href="https://www.mljtrust.org/static/images/mlj-podcast-1404.jpg"/><title>The Terms Defined</title><link>https://www.mljtrust.org/sermons/book-of-romans/the-terms-defined/</link><description>Romans 11:16-17 — In Romans 11:16–17, Paul provides more evidence of why the rejection of Israel was not final. Israel's stumbling was only temporary and because of their fall, the gentiles have received salvation. Paul explains that Israel's belief will be like coming to life from death. In this passage, he uses two illustrations to explain the Jews’ and the Gentiles’ relationship to the truth. In this sermon on Romans 11:16–17 titled “The Terms Defined,” Dr. Martyn Lloyd-Jones breaks down both illustrations and defines the words and context of the words. In essence, if one is part of the whole, and the whole is holy, then they, too, are also holy. Dr. Lloyd-Jones points out that the term “holy” does not always mean sinless, but it means set apart by God. Some parts of the "dough" or "branches" (as used in the illustrations) have been cut off, but can once again be grafted in and take the blessings of the whole. God has the power to remove something once and for all, but He can also graft a part back into the whole. This is what will be done with the Jews. It will be a glorious day when all of Christ’s followers and those who believe the true gospel will be raised up and reunited with the whole.</description><pubDate>Wed, 25 Feb 2026 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.mljtrust.org/sermons/book-of-romans/the-terms-defined/</guid><enclosure length="83310105" type="audio/mpeg" url="https://media.blubrry.com/mljsermons/sermons.mljtrust.org/3278-the-terms-defined.mp3"/></item><item><itunes:image href="https://www.mljtrust.org/static/images/mlj-podcast-1404.jpg"/><title>Life From the Dead</title><link>https://www.mljtrust.org/sermons/book-of-romans/life-from-the-dead/</link><description>Romans 11:13-15 — What is the future of the Jewish nation? According to Dr. Martyn Lloyd-Jones in this sermon on Romans 11:13–15 titled “Life From the Dead,” one does not have to wonder since God prophesied through the apostle Paul that there will be a great day when Israel is saved. While they may have stumbled, this was only temporary in order that the gospel might go to all the nations of the Gentiles. God has promised that there will come a day when the dead come to life; that is, when the spiritually dead Israelites receive the gospel of Jesus Christ and believe in Him. All Christians ought to pray and seek the day when God moves and causes a great revival amongst the people of Israel. Furthermore, Paul warns Gentile Christians from becoming prideful and boastful towards the Jewish people, for both Jew and Gentile are justified by faith in Christ as a gift from God. How should this message change the way Christians live now? Christians ought to seek to evangelize the people of Israel because they know that there will be a day when God causes a great revival amongst them. The church ought to pray and eagerly await the day when God fulfills His promise and brings many national Israelites into the church of Jesus Christ.</description><pubDate>Tue, 24 Feb 2026 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.mljtrust.org/sermons/book-of-romans/life-from-the-dead/</guid><enclosure length="83956922" type="audio/mpeg" url="https://media.blubrry.com/mljsermons/sermons.mljtrust.org/3277-life-from-the-dead.mp3"/></item><item><itunes:image href="https://www.mljtrust.org/static/images/mlj-podcast-1404.jpg"/><title>Apostle to the Gentiles</title><link>https://www.mljtrust.org/sermons/book-of-romans/apostle-to-the-gentiles/</link><description>Romans 11:13-15 — In this sermon on Romans 11:13–15 titled “Apostle to the Gentiles,” Dr Martyn Lloyd-Jones works through the teaching of Paul to the Gentiles. Different interpretations of these controversial words by Paul are examined and the various out-workings of each are addressed. He explains the difference between translation and interpretation. Paul preaches as an apostle to the Gentiles and he emphasizes this office, perhaps with an ultimate and ulterior motive for the salvation of the Jews. Dr. Lloyd-Jones addresses these questions along with the false notions that surround both the Jew and the Gentile. Evangelism, teaching, and warning are all essential to Paul’s word to these people and for today’s believers. Is the gospel different for Jew and Gentile? Listeners are encouraged to be diligent in study and see the full blessing that God has offered through Christ, embracing the word of God and the hope of the gospel that is now available for every human, no matter the race, gender, or ethnicity. Salvation has been purchased through the blood of Christ for the purification of more than just the Jews.</description><pubDate>Mon, 23 Feb 2026 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.mljtrust.org/sermons/book-of-romans/apostle-to-the-gentiles/</guid><enclosure length="88781475" type="audio/mpeg" url="https://media.blubrry.com/mljsermons/sermons.mljtrust.org/3276-apostle-to-the-gentiles.mp3"/></item><item><itunes:image href="https://www.mljtrust.org/static/images/mlj-podcast-1404.jpg"/><title>Lessons from the Jews</title><link>https://www.mljtrust.org/sermons/book-of-romans/lessons-from-the-jews/</link><description>Romans 11:11-12 — What can we learn from the apostle Paul’s teachings on the Jewish people? In this sermon on Romans 11:11–12 titled “Lessons from the Jews,” Dr. Martyn Lloyd-Jones says that Christians have much to learn from Paul about the church, themselves, and the gospel. He says that this prophesy will take place in the future. Paul believed that there would be a great revival amongst the people of Israel when they come to know Jesus Christ. The reason why the Jews rejected the gospel was in order that the truth of Christ might go to the Gentiles. The church must understand that oftentimes God uses rejection to actually further the proclamation of the gospel. The church must trust in God and in His goodness, believing that He will accomplish all He intends. The future restoration of Israel ought to cause Christians to lay aside prejudice and evil feelings toward the Jewish people, and they ought to love them and bring the gospel to them. Christ Jesus is the only means of salvation for both Jew and Gentile. The church is to proclaim this message of forgiveness and mercy to all people until Christ returns in glory.</description><pubDate>Sun, 22 Feb 2026 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.mljtrust.org/sermons/book-of-romans/lessons-from-the-jews/</guid><enclosure length="88522261" type="audio/mpeg" url="https://media.blubrry.com/mljsermons/sermons.mljtrust.org/3275-lessons-from-the-jews.mp3"/></item><item><itunes:image href="https://www.mljtrust.org/static/images/mlj-podcast-1404.jpg"/><title>Riches of the Gentiles</title><link>https://www.mljtrust.org/sermons/book-of-romans/riches-of-the-gentiles/</link><description>Romans 11:11-12 — According to the apostle Paul, why are the Jewish people permitted to stumble? In this sermon on Romans 11:11–12 titled “Riches of the Gentiles,” Dr. Martyn Lloyd-Jones takes up this difficult question. He says that ultimately God allowed the Jewish people to stumble and reject the gospel of Jesus Christ in order that the gospel might go to all the nations. Because they rejected the gospel, the early church spread the gospel from the land of Israel and it went to the whole world. At the same time, Paul himself was Jewish by birth and a believer of Christ. This shows that not all Jews rejected Jesus. What of the future of the Jewish people? Dr. Lloyd-Jones says that in the future there will be a great revival among the nation of Israel and many will come to a true knowledge of Jesus and His gospel. They will put their faith in their long-awaited Messiah. The apostle Paul argues that just as it was a blessing to the Gentiles that Israel stumbled over the gospel, it will be an even greater blessing when the people of Israel believe and come into the church of Jesus Christ.</description><pubDate>Sat, 21 Feb 2026 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.mljtrust.org/sermons/book-of-romans/riches-of-the-gentiles/</guid><enclosure length="94120798" type="audio/mpeg" url="https://media.blubrry.com/mljsermons/sermons.mljtrust.org/3274-riches-of-the-gentiles.mp3"/></item><item><itunes:image href="https://www.mljtrust.org/static/images/mlj-podcast-1404.jpg"/><title>An Overview of Romans 11:11-32</title><link>https://www.mljtrust.org/sermons/book-of-romans/stumbling-of-the-jews/</link><description>Romans 11:11-32 — Paul has been teaching about the Jews and how as a nation they have blatantly rejected the gospel. In this portion of Romans, Paul is now stating what the real position of the Jews is and how that relates to the Gentiles. In this sermon on Romans 11:11–12 titled “Stumbling of the Jews,” Dr. Martyn Lloyd-Jones explains that the Jews stumbled so that the Gentiles could come to salvation. Not only was their stumbling permitted by God, he also inflicted them with blindness so that the Gentiles could have the opportunity to believe. This rejection of the Jews gave the blessings to the Gentiles. So have the Jews been cast away forever? Paul says that they have not. They have in turn seen the blessings of the gentiles and have been provoked to jealousy. This causes them to think twice and consider the gospel that the Lord has given.</description><pubDate>Fri, 20 Feb 2026 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.mljtrust.org/sermons/book-of-romans/stumbling-of-the-jews/</guid><enclosure length="92673287" type="audio/mpeg" url="https://media.blubrry.com/mljsermons/sermons.mljtrust.org/3273-stumbling-of-the-jews.mp3"/></item><item><itunes:image href="https://www.mljtrust.org/static/images/mlj-podcast-1404.jpg"/><title>Imprecatory Psalms</title><link>https://www.mljtrust.org/sermons/book-of-romans/psalms-2/</link><description>Romans 11:7-10 — Why are there imprecatory Psalms in the Bible? This is the question that Dr. Martyn Lloyd-Jones takes up in this sermon on Romans 11:7–10 titled “Psalms.” He says that Scripture never teaches that God creates evil or sin but He does create the consequences of the sinful actions of humans. When Scripture speaks of God visiting judgement upon evil, one should not think that this is God doing something evil but He is punishing the wicked for their evil deeds. The same thing is true in the case of David when he prays for God to judge the wicked. This is not David being vindictive, but rather it is him asking that God act in accordance with His character to protect the righteous and punish the wicked. For God is holy and just; He cannot even look upon evil doers. This is seen in the highest form when Jesus died upon the cross at Calvary. There, God’s justice was fully manifested in His judgement upon sin in Christ but His mercy also was displayed in saving sinners. This is the great truth that God is both the just and the justifier. There is truly no unrighteousness with God.</description><pubDate>Thu, 19 Feb 2026 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.mljtrust.org/sermons/book-of-romans/psalms-2/</guid><enclosure length="96986760" type="audio/mpeg" url="https://media.blubrry.com/mljsermons/sermons.mljtrust.org/3272-psalms-2.mp3"/></item><item><itunes:image href="https://www.mljtrust.org/static/images/mlj-podcast-1404.jpg"/><title>Judicial Blindness</title><link>https://www.mljtrust.org/sermons/book-of-romans/judicial-blindness/</link><description>Romans 11:7-10 — The passages in Scripture that refer to God hardening someone’s heart or blinding them to the truth can be confusing. This can be a troubling passage and topic for many people because it often leads to more questions than answers. In this sermon on Romans 11:7–11 titled “Judicial Blindness,” Dr. Martyn Lloyd-Jones provides helpful answers and a good starting point for people wrestling through this issue. Dr. Lloyd-Jones refers to this blinding as a “judicial blindness” where God ceases striving. There are many instances recorded in Scripture where God removed His control and allowed negative things to happen so that people would learn. Yet there is a step beyond this when sometimes God is even said to harden someone’s heart. Those who are hardened and blinded are unable to do or believe anything outside of their current state. Is this a punishment or is it at random? Dr. Lloyd-Jones provides his opinion for how this progresses — in short, that disobedience against God leads naturally to the hardening of the person’s heart. Ultimately, he says, the doctrine of election makes sense of this topic that can be so difficult to navigate. Listen as he guides the listener through this challenging passage.</description><pubDate>Wed, 18 Feb 2026 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.mljtrust.org/sermons/book-of-romans/judicial-blindness/</guid><enclosure length="90671663" type="audio/mpeg" url="https://media.blubrry.com/mljsermons/sermons.mljtrust.org/3271-judicial-blindness.mp3"/></item><item><itunes:image href="https://www.mljtrust.org/static/images/mlj-podcast-1404.jpg"/><title>Blessings Become a Curse</title><link>https://www.mljtrust.org/sermons/book-of-romans/blessings-become-a-curse/</link><description>Romans 11:7-10 — How can something that the Lord created as a blessing become a curse? In this sermon on Romans 11:7–10 titled “Blessings Become a Curse,” Dr. Martyn Lloyd-Jones answers this question by preaching from the words of Paul when he refers to the law and the people of Israel. Paul acknowledges that the Jews were earnest and genuine in their search for salvation but they went about it in the wrong way. The passage says that those who were elect did in fact obtain it but that the Lord hardened the others. Israel was blinded and God gave them the spirit of slumber regarding the true message of the gospel. Dr. Lloyd-Jones explains the passage by saying that the very blessing of the word of God, the law, was once a blessing but became a curse to the Jews. They had the wrong thinking about so many things and despite their best efforts, they still did not truly know Christ and did not receive salvation. The only way to receive this blessing is by faith. Dr. Lloyd-Jones also explains in great detail several other Old Testament passages which show the ignorance of the Jewish people and how they did not understand the gospel.</description><pubDate>Tue, 17 Feb 2026 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.mljtrust.org/sermons/book-of-romans/blessings-become-a-curse/</guid><enclosure length="25773579" type="audio/mpeg" url="https://media.blubrry.com/mljsermons/sermons.mljtrust.org/3270-blessings-become-a-curse.mp3"/></item><item><itunes:image href="https://www.mljtrust.org/static/images/mlj-podcast-1404.jpg"/><title>A Remnant According to Grace</title><link>https://www.mljtrust.org/sermons/book-of-romans/according-to-grace/</link><description>Romans 11:1-6 — In this sermon on Romans 11:1-6 titled “A Remnant According to Grace,” Dr. Martyn Lloyd-Jones continues his exposition of the apostle Paul's answer to his rhetorical question "Has God rejected His people?" (Rom 10:1). The apostle, after having discussed the first proof that God has not rejected His people - the case of his own conversion - now turns to a second example from history; the case of Elijah. During the reign of wicked King Ahab and Jezebel, Elijah fears he is the only faithful one left in Israel and that all hope for God’s church is lost. Elijah cries out to God in alarm asking why it seems as though God has forsaken him and Israel. God responds by telling him that he has not forsaken him or Israel but that He has saved seven thousand for himself. Another instance Dr. Jones brings out in his sermon is when God brought Lot out of Sodom and Gomorrah before he destroyed it. Some conclusions that Dr. Lloyd-Jones draws from this passage is that “we must learn to face every situation in life in a Scriptural manner.” Secondly, Dr. Jones also brings out the idea that we should never get involved too personally in such matters of the church; we must not sulk under our Juniper tree like Elijah and “let the devil persuade you that the church is yours. The church isn’t yours, but it is God’s.” Lastly, Dr. Lloyd-Jones persuades us to remember that even if the whole world is against us, we must not go along with the crowd, no matter the numbers. Thus, God’s purposes are sure and we must not worry. God will always keep His remnant.</description><pubDate>Mon, 16 Feb 2026 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.mljtrust.org/sermons/book-of-romans/according-to-grace/</guid><enclosure length="99752227" type="audio/mpeg" url="https://media.blubrry.com/mljsermons/sermons.mljtrust.org/3269-according-to-grace.mp3"/></item><item><itunes:image href="https://www.mljtrust.org/static/images/mlj-podcast-1404.jpg"/><title>Did God Reject His People?</title><link>https://www.mljtrust.org/sermons/book-of-romans/did-god-reject-his-people/</link><description>Romans 11:1-4 — Has God cast away the Jewish people? After several passages concerning the fate of the Jewish nation, in this sermon on Romans 11:1–4 titled “Did God Reject His People?” Dr. Martyn Lloyd-Jones unfolds how Paul asks this question and then follows his answers with several pieces of evidence. Paul says that there is no way the Lord has cast out His chosen people because Paul himself is an Israelite. Paul is saying this not just as a nationalist or proselyte, but he shows his historical lineage which proves he is of Jewish descent. It is possible that some Jews will be saved because Paul was saved. There are a large majority of Jews that do not believe the true gospel. God did not cast them all away because He foreknew them. This means that God foreordained them and knew that they would be believing Christians. The Jews were a group of people that God took special interest in and had a special affection for. Israel was set apart by God for a purpose. If God cast them out, this would mean that God changed His mind and  Christians know that the Lord does not change His mind as it is not part of His character.</description><pubDate>Sun, 15 Feb 2026 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.mljtrust.org/sermons/book-of-romans/did-god-reject-his-people/</guid><enclosure length="96151655" type="audio/mpeg" url="https://media.blubrry.com/mljsermons/sermons.mljtrust.org/3268-did-god-reject-his-people.mp3"/></item><item><itunes:image href="https://www.mljtrust.org/static/images/mlj-podcast-1404.jpg"/><title>An Introduction to Romans 11</title><link>https://www.mljtrust.org/sermons/book-of-romans/introduction-2/</link><description>Romans 11:1-36 — In this sermon on Romans 11:1–36 titled An Introduction to Romans 11,” Dr. Martyn Lloyd-Jones urges the listener to lay aside prejudices and traditions and to come to God’s word in an attitude of reverence. All Scripture is the very word of God. The major themes of this chapter are salvation, faith, and the people of Israel. While there are many differing interpretations of this passage, we still must never approach Scripture in an overly intellectual manner that causes only debates and divisions. God’s word is given to build up the church and strengthen the believer’s faith. Paul is concerned that the church in Rome and, by inclusion, all Christians should come to a proper understanding of God and His salvation that He has given in Christ. Dr. Lloyd-Jones addresses questions such as what is the relation between Jew and Gentile, what is the future of the Jewish people, and what does it mean to be justified by faith? All these questions have immense significance for the Christian life and the life of the church. Christianity and theology is not simply about abstract intellectual ideas but it is about knowing God.</description><pubDate>Sat, 14 Feb 2026 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.mljtrust.org/sermons/book-of-romans/introduction-2/</guid><enclosure length="86246830" type="audio/mpeg" url="https://media.blubrry.com/mljsermons/sermons.mljtrust.org/3267-introduction-2.mp3"/></item><item><itunes:image href="https://www.mljtrust.org/static/images/mlj-podcast-1404.jpg"/><title>Learning the Lessons from Israel’s History</title><link>https://www.mljtrust.org/sermons/book-of-romans/learning-the-lessons/</link><description>Romans 10:18-21 — How could it be that the foolish and ignorant Gentiles would predominately receive the gospel, whereas God’s chosen people, the Jews, would predominately reject the gospel? Dr. Martyn Lloyd-Jones has been tracing the apostle Paul’s argument through Romans, seeking to answer this query following the inspired text of Scripture itself. In this sermon on Romans 10:18–21 titled “Learning the Lessons,” he transitions from exposition to application of the many exegetical principles he has established in earlier messages. Dr. Lloyd-Jones notes the important role in the personal application of Scripture, which many of the Jews in Paul’s day missed. Furthermore, he traces the history of the church as illustrative of “dead orthodoxy” that abandons the Lord Jesus Christ and persecutes His church. The answer to such alarming tendency of so-called “Christians” persecuting the church is a posture of self-examination and returning to the ultimate authority – the word of God. Dr. Lloyd-Jones asks the church to remain open to the scrutiny of Scripture, remaining humble before it and others, while rightly handling the whole of the Bible. Listen to this vital message from Dr. Martyn Lloyd-Jones as he cautions the church to take serious the tragedy of the Jews, not merely as a historical interest, but more importantly as a means of God’s grace in the life of His people.</description><pubDate>Fri, 13 Feb 2026 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.mljtrust.org/sermons/book-of-romans/learning-the-lessons/</guid><enclosure length="96477302" type="audio/mpeg" url="https://media.blubrry.com/mljsermons/sermons.mljtrust.org/3266-learning-the-lessons.mp3"/></item><item><itunes:image href="https://www.mljtrust.org/static/images/mlj-podcast-1404.jpg"/><title>Tragedy of the Jews</title><link>https://www.mljtrust.org/sermons/book-of-romans/tragedy-of-the-jews/</link><description>Romans 10:18-21 — As it pertains to human knowledge, human understanding, or human works, the Jews of Paul’s day would be in a position of entire advantage. Yet the majority of Jews, as Paul laments in Romans, did not obey the gospel. Why? Moreover, what does it mean that Paul cites Scripture against the Jews calling them “disobedient” and “gainsaying”? In this sermon on Romans 10:18–21 titled “Tragedy of the Jews,” Dr. Martyn Lloyd-Jones grounds the tragedy of the Jews in God’s sovereign election and their prejudice against the Lord Jesus Christ. Salvation belongs to the Lord, as Dr. Lloyd-Jones reminds the listener. The way of salvation from old covenant to the new covenant is determined by the sovereign grace of God. The “whosoever” of salvation is tied to “whosoever” as God determines, whether that is predominantly Jews or predominantly Gentiles. But Dr. Lloyd-Jones leaves room for human responsibility as well. Many of the Jews in the first century were simply set against the gospel. Jesus experienced this in His earthly ministry with the Pharisees as did Paul in his ministry. Listen as Dr. Lloyd-Jones tackles the topic of divine sovereignty and human responsibility and as Paul explained the tragedy of the Jews, Dr. Lloyd-Jones calls the church to self-examination and praise in the sovereign election of God.</description><pubDate>Thu, 12 Feb 2026 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.mljtrust.org/sermons/book-of-romans/tragedy-of-the-jews/</guid><enclosure length="101381367" type="audio/mpeg" url="https://media.blubrry.com/mljsermons/sermons.mljtrust.org/3265-tragedy-of-the-jews.mp3"/></item><item><itunes:image href="https://www.mljtrust.org/static/images/mlj-podcast-1404.jpg"/><title>The Gospel and the Jews</title><link>https://www.mljtrust.org/sermons/book-of-romans/the-gospel-and-the-jews/</link><description>Romans 10:18-21 — Why is the Jewish nation now outside the kingdom of God? In this sermon on Romans 10:18–21 titled “The Gospel and the Jews,” Dr. Martyn Lloyd-Jones analyzes and confirms that it is not because the Jews lack hearing or because there is a lack of plain teaching to them. Paul has made three things very clear thus far in Romans: the way of salvation, the inclusion of the Gentiles, and the exclusion of the Jews. The Jews did in fact receive very clear teaching about this from Moses and other prophets. Moses even explicitly said that the kingdom of God would be taken from the Jewish nation and given to a nation bearing fruit. So if the Jews have heard and received teaching, what are the reasons they are no longer in the kingdom? It was due to their false views on salvation. They thought of it in terms of their nation and the fact that they were circumcised. They had a false confidence in their flesh, holding onto their family lineage, and the fact that they had the Scriptures of the Lord. That proved to be their stumbling block. God requires that believers be not only hearers of the law but also doers of the law.</description><pubDate>Wed, 11 Feb 2026 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.mljtrust.org/sermons/book-of-romans/the-gospel-and-the-jews/</guid><enclosure length="83521673" type="audio/mpeg" url="https://media.blubrry.com/mljsermons/sermons.mljtrust.org/3264-the-gospel-and-the-jews.mp3"/></item><item><itunes:image href="https://www.mljtrust.org/static/images/mlj-podcast-1404.jpg"/><title>The Case of the Jews</title><link>https://www.mljtrust.org/sermons/book-of-romans/the-case-of-the-jews/</link><description>Romans 10:18-21 — Did the apostle Paul really claim that the gospel had been proclaimed throughout the world? What could he have meant by such a statement? What about the Jews and how can he claim that the majority of Jews have not obeyed the gospel? Did most of them hear the gospel preached? Some would protest and think that Paul was obviously mistaken. In this sermon on Romans 10:18–21 titled “The Case of the Jews,” Dr. Martyn Lloyd-Jones looks at the connection between the Old Testament anticipation of the coming Messiah and the large-scale rejection of Jesus Christ by the Jews and also during Paul’s day. By interpreting Scripture with Scripture, Dr. Lloyd-Jones demonstrates how the Jewish people should have known about the suffering Messiah from their own Scriptures. The New Testament often assumes the clarity of the gospel in the Old Testament and yet there is a blindness to the clear teaching. The gospel from the apostle Paul was not a message that should be hidden from the masses. There was no hint of a “mystery religion” where only a select few knew the right details in order to be “initiated.” Dr. Lloyd-Jones contends that God was taking the gospel message through appointed apostles, prophets and preachers so that it would be heard by everyone, everywhere.</description><pubDate>Tue, 10 Feb 2026 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.mljtrust.org/sermons/book-of-romans/the-case-of-the-jews/</guid><enclosure length="83004498" type="audio/mpeg" url="https://media.blubrry.com/mljsermons/sermons.mljtrust.org/3263-the-case-of-the-jews.mp3"/></item><item><itunes:image href="https://www.mljtrust.org/static/images/mlj-podcast-1404.jpg"/><title>Faith and Joy</title><link>https://www.mljtrust.org/sermons/book-of-romans/faith-and-joy/</link><description>Romans 10:16-17 — What is the Christian’s reaction to the gospel? In this sermon from Romans 10:16–17 titled “Faith and Joy,” Dr. Martyn Lloyd-Jones declares the first action of a Christian is to obey. There is a difference between people who merely hear the gospel and those who take action from it. Some listen and forget and some listen and do. He declares that this is the primary reaction to the gospel. The secondary reaction is joy. Dr. Lloyd-Jones raises a powerful question: if Christians are supposed to be lights in this world, why are so many caught up in their own problems and gloom? He says that Christians should be the happiest people on earth. He gives examples of some of the most joyous people in the New Testament: the Philippian jailor, the shepherd who found his sheep, and the woman who washed Christ’s feet. These are all people who, in different ways, heard the good news and responded appropriately. Dr. Lloyd-Jones reminds that Christians have great cause to rejoice as they have been forgiven of much sin and are promised an eternal inheritance with God. Dr. Lloyd-Jones concludes that in light of those joyous New Testament believers, perhaps Christians today should reevaluate their reaction to the gospel and reconsider the life they’ve been given.</description><pubDate>Mon, 09 Feb 2026 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.mljtrust.org/sermons/book-of-romans/faith-and-joy/</guid><enclosure length="91089273" type="audio/mpeg" url="https://media.blubrry.com/mljsermons/sermons.mljtrust.org/3262-faith-and-joy.mp3"/></item><item><itunes:image href="https://www.mljtrust.org/static/images/mlj-podcast-1404.jpg"/><title>Faith and Obedience</title><link>https://www.mljtrust.org/sermons/book-of-romans/faith-and-obedience/</link><description>Romans 10:16-17 — In Romans 10:16–17, Paul explains that for a person to come to faith, they must hear the good news. But what comes after receiving faith? In this sermon on Romans 10:16–17 titled “Faith and Obedience,” Dr. Lloyd-Jones answers this question affirmatively by pointing to the early church in Paul’s time. After faith, a change was expected in the believers. They could no longer participate in idol worship or immoral rituals. Dr. Lloyd-Jones says that they must submit themselves to the gospel with obedience. A good test to see whether or not a person really has faith is to look at their actions. Are they changed after believing or do they give, as Dr. Lloyd-Jones calls it, “intellectual assent”? These are people who merely acknowledge the gospel as the truth but do nothing to back it up. They never left behind worldly habits and practices. But Dr. Lloyd-Jones points out that as James said, faith without works is dead. Obedience shows faith and faith encourages obedience. In closing this sermon on obedience, he extends the message of salvation, reminding believers and unbelievers alike of the joy found within.</description><pubDate>Sun, 08 Feb 2026 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.mljtrust.org/sermons/book-of-romans/faith-and-obedience/</guid><enclosure length="88087071" type="audio/mpeg" url="https://media.blubrry.com/mljsermons/sermons.mljtrust.org/3261-faith-and-obedience.mp3"/></item><item><itunes:image href="https://www.mljtrust.org/static/images/mlj-podcast-1404.jpg"/><title>Hearing of Faith</title><link>https://www.mljtrust.org/sermons/book-of-romans/hearing-of-faith/</link><description>Romans 10:16-17 — How is a person saved? Is it through just hearing the gospel or is it through faith? The debate is a theological divide in the Christian church. In this sermon on Romans 10:16–17 titled “Hearing of Faith,” Dr. Martyn Lloyd-Jones gives firm biblical grounding in salvation that comes not just by hearing, but by faith in Christ and His sacrifice on the cross. Dr. Lloyd-Jones says that there are two types of hearing: hearing that falls on the ears and hearing that moves a person to believe. Quoting the words of Isaiah, he reveals that this has always been the case. Not every person who hears believes. It was the same in the Old Testament, the New Testament, and today. Dr. Lloyd-Jones points out that this is an example of divine inspiration in Scripture. In a relatable “church goer” example, Dr. Lloyd-Jones reviews the elements needed for a person to hear the gospel with faith. That person’s heart must be opened by God and they must then trust in Christ’s redeeming death on the cross. To convey this incredible truth, Dr. Lloyd-Jones draws on other examples from the New Testament that embody and proclaim this faith today.</description><pubDate>Sat, 07 Feb 2026 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.mljtrust.org/sermons/book-of-romans/hearing-of-faith/</guid><enclosure length="96471269" type="audio/mpeg" url="https://media.blubrry.com/mljsermons/sermons.mljtrust.org/3260-hearing-of-faith.mp3"/></item><item><itunes:image href="https://www.mljtrust.org/static/images/mlj-podcast-1404.jpg"/><title>The Preacher's Message, Part 2</title><link>https://www.mljtrust.org/sermons/book-of-romans/the-preachers-message-2/</link><description>Romans 10:14-17 — In his sermon on Romans 10:14–17 titled “The Preacher’s Message (2),” Dr. Martyn Lloyd-Jones talks about the great joy believers have within the gospel. Reading from this Scripture passage, he reminds the listener of the basics of the good news and how it should inspire Christians. He says that preaching is God’s chief appointed role for sharing the gospel to the congregation and unbelievers. Because of this responsibility, it’s important for preachers to integrate the good news into their message. Dr. Lloyd-Jones offers this suggestion with a warning to the congregation: do not grow tired of hearing the gospel. It is easy for Christians to forget the amazing power bestowed by God to those who believe. Dr. Lloyd-Jones takes an opportunity to remind Christians of what they have in Christ. He says that God gave His Son for the forgiveness of sins simply because He is rich in mercy and grace, as seen in Ephesians 2. Dr. Lloyd-Jones expounds upon the daily intercession Christ takes for Christians at the right hand of the Father. He goes on to describe the groaning of the Holy Spirit that prays when believers don’t know what to pray for. With these incredible privileges, Dr. Lloyd-Jones concludes with a call to obey the gospel and take joy in the promises within.</description><pubDate>Fri, 06 Feb 2026 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.mljtrust.org/sermons/book-of-romans/the-preachers-message-2/</guid><enclosure length="92603048" type="audio/mpeg" url="https://media.blubrry.com/mljsermons/sermons.mljtrust.org/3259-the-preachers-message-2.mp3"/></item><item><itunes:image href="https://www.mljtrust.org/static/images/mlj-podcast-1404.jpg"/><title>The Preacher's Message, Part 1</title><link>https://www.mljtrust.org/sermons/book-of-romans/the-preachers-message-1/</link><description>Romans 10:14-17 — In his sermon on Romans 10:14–17 titled “The Preacher’s Message (1),” Dr. Martyn Lloyd-Jones tackles an important question: what are preachers supposed to preach? Drawing from Paul’s writing in this passage, he reminds that preaching is God’s primary purpose for delivering the gospel. How is a person supposed to judge if a pastor is exercising good preaching? Dr. Lloyd-Jones devises a test. If the message does not bring “glad tidings,” it should probably be reconsidered. The good news is called the good news for a reason, he says. The incredible salvation believers have through the grace of God is cause for celebration. Dr. Lloyd-Jones gives three common examples of people preaching without the gospel’s joy. He says to be wary of people saying Christians are supposed to bring the kingdom; the kingdom is already coming. He says to look out for people who preach strictly on Christ’s morals as morals are not God’s grace.  He also says to beware of preachers who tell the congregation to put their faith in the church; the church is not the avenue to salvation. With that, Dr. Lloyd-Jones concludes his sermon in stating that the one true faith believers have is in Jesus Christ and the joy that comes with it.</description><pubDate>Thu, 05 Feb 2026 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.mljtrust.org/sermons/book-of-romans/the-preachers-message-1/</guid><enclosure length="85515695" type="audio/mpeg" url="https://media.blubrry.com/mljsermons/sermons.mljtrust.org/3258-the-preachers-message-1.mp3"/></item><item><itunes:image href="https://www.mljtrust.org/static/images/mlj-podcast-1404.jpg"/><title>Called to Preach, Part 2</title><link>https://www.mljtrust.org/sermons/book-of-romans/called-to-preach-2/</link><description>Romans 10:14-17 — In the sermon on Romans 10:14–17 titled “Called to Preach (2),” Dr. Lloyd-Jones elaborates on the qualities that make a good preacher. He dives into an equally important discussion: how does a person know if he’s called to preach? Reading from this passage, he answers this question by reiterating the biblical definition of a preacher. He says that a preacher is one of God’s ordained ways to spread the good news, for how can people believe without first hearing? But how does a person know if he’s being called? Dr. Lloyd-Jones says that person may feel a pressure they cannot shake, an inclination toward a certain notion. Second, he says that the person must feel a burden for the souls of men and women. It is not enough for a man to want to speak in front of the congregation. This person must also care deeply about the spirits of those to whom he ministers. Lastly, in accordance with the person’s burden for the souls of men and women, the man must be willing to preach the gospel. He must live for it, Dr. Lloyd-Jones says. He must be willing to preach the facts of the good news: Christ’s redemptive death on the cross and the incredible salvation that comes through faith.</description><pubDate>Wed, 04 Feb 2026 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.mljtrust.org/sermons/book-of-romans/called-to-preach-2/</guid><enclosure length="86943902" type="audio/mpeg" url="https://media.blubrry.com/mljsermons/sermons.mljtrust.org/3257-called-to-preach-2.mp3"/></item><item><itunes:image href="https://www.mljtrust.org/static/images/mlj-podcast-1404.jpg"/><title>Called to Preach, Part 1</title><link>https://www.mljtrust.org/sermons/book-of-romans/called-to-preach-1/</link><description>Romans 10:14-17 — In the first part of his sermon on Romans 10:14–17 titled “Called to Preach (1),” Dr. Martyn Lloyd-Jones answers an important question: what makes a preacher? As he curates a biblical list that describes an ideal pastor, Dr. Martyn Lloyd-Jones declares the first reason for preaching. Quoting from Romans, he reads, “And how can they believe in whom they have not heard?” The primary reason for preaching is to herald the good news to those who have not heard. As Paul wrote, people cannot believe in something unless they’re told of it. The second reason for preaching, he says, is because a person is called. Dr. Lloyd-Jones gives a number of New Testament examples of people being called to preach the good news. Chiefly, he cites Christ’s calling of the disciples. Lastly, he reminds the listener how important it is for a preacher to be appointed by the congregation. He again quotes passages from the New Testament where the church selected and prayed over certain people to bring the message locally and abroad. A person cannot appoint himself to preach. He must be given the responsibility by the church body. Dr. Lloyd-Jones concludes by saying that these three points are essential to preaching and the great opportunity to share the promise of Christ.</description><pubDate>Tue, 03 Feb 2026 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.mljtrust.org/sermons/book-of-romans/called-to-preach-1/</guid><enclosure length="92005464" type="audio/mpeg" url="https://media.blubrry.com/mljsermons/sermons.mljtrust.org/3256-called-to-preach-1.mp3"/></item><item><itunes:image href="https://www.mljtrust.org/static/images/mlj-podcast-1404.jpg"/><title>Why Preaching?</title><link>https://www.mljtrust.org/sermons/book-of-romans/why-preaching/</link><description>Romans 10:14-17 — Why does the Christian church gather weekly to hear a message when each person could be at home reading from the Bible? In his sermon on Romans 10:14–17 titled “Why Preaching?” Dr. Martyn Lloyd-Jones addresses this question as he delivers a message about the importance of preaching as it is God’s chief way for the gospel to be heard. Reading is right and good for the knowledgeable Christian, but for someone newly touched by the Holy Spirit, the words of a pastor are formative to their acceptance of the good news. Dr. Lloyd-Jones recalls the Ethiopian man who was reading the Old Testament but could not understand the writings. He needed Philip to come into his chariot and explain its meaning. This is the wonderful power of preaching. In addition to this truth, Dr. Lloyd-Jones explains how important it is for believers to gather in church to hear a message. Believers, he says, need to be present for those who need help. Perhaps it is a person has lost a family member, needs encouragement, or needs help understanding the sermon. Believers are there to also lean on each other. He concludes by saying that preaching can be the powerful spark of revival and that the gathering of Christians has the potential to glorify God in ways that didn’t seem possible.</description><pubDate>Mon, 02 Feb 2026 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.mljtrust.org/sermons/book-of-romans/why-preaching/</guid><enclosure length="90065895" type="audio/mpeg" url="https://media.blubrry.com/mljsermons/sermons.mljtrust.org/3255-why-preaching.mp3"/></item><item><itunes:image href="https://www.mljtrust.org/static/images/mlj-podcast-1404.jpg"/><title>Preaching and Salvation</title><link>https://www.mljtrust.org/sermons/book-of-romans/preaching-and-salvation/</link><description>Romans 10:14-17 — In this sermon on salvation from Romans 10:14–17 titled “Preaching and Salvation,” Dr. Lloyd-Jones dives into some of the fundamental questions of Christianity: How does one receive salvation? What is the eternal position of those who have not heard? How should the gospel be preached? These questions are important to faith and occur frequently in the mind of the believer. They may be a prevailing source of uncertainty or perhaps doubt. But Dr. Lloyd-Jones quenches these points of uncertainty by focusing on this passage and the interpretation of Paul’s discourse. He goes back to the basics, proclaiming that salvation comes to those who cry out to the Lord. Dr. Lloyd-Jones explains the dynamic role of preaching and says that it is important because, as Paul writes, believing comes through hearing the good news. The world today is filled with doubt regarding the path to heaven. Is Christ the only way? Dr. Lloyd Jones answers this by drawing upon Scripture and other Christian theologians and shedding light onto the unbeliever’s path, specifically those who have never heard the gospel. Are they beyond the reach of salvation? Listen as Dr. Lloyd-Jones returns to the Christian fundamentals. Hear the good news preached again and be reminded of God’s sovereign power and incredible love.</description><pubDate>Sun, 01 Feb 2026 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.mljtrust.org/sermons/book-of-romans/preaching-and-salvation/</guid><enclosure length="88980659" type="audio/mpeg" url="https://media.blubrry.com/mljsermons/sermons.mljtrust.org/3254-preaching-and-salvation.mp3"/></item><item><itunes:image href="https://www.mljtrust.org/static/images/mlj-podcast-1404.jpg"/><title>Jew and Gentile, No Difference</title><link>https://www.mljtrust.org/sermons/book-of-romans/jew-and-gentile-no-difference/</link><description>Romans 10:11-13 — People love to make distinctions between themselves and others, between their tribe and other tribes. Fallen hearts tend to make these distinctions so as to elevate themselves above others, especially in religious matters. The apostle Paul has tirelessly labored in Romans to emphasize that there is no distinction between Jew and Gentile –– all sin falls short of the glory of God. If one does not follow the apostle here, they will construct different ways of salvation that appeal to the flesh. One may think being moral, good or kind is the way of salvation. But God’s way of salvation has always been the same — those who call upon the name of the Lord shall be saved. There is no distinction between Jew or Gentile in any sense, whether in sin or salvation. In this sermon on Romans 10:11–13 titled “Jew or Gentle, No Difference,” Dr. Martyn Lloyd-Jones expounds Paul’s teaching and brings contemporary application. Specifically, he applies Paul’s teaching here to dispensationalism and its teaching that makes a distinction between salvation for Jews and salvation for the church. In an amicable spirit, Dr. Lloyd-Jones challenges the popular movement by rightly connecting the Old Testament teaching on salvation with the New Testament. He emphasizes that there is only one way with one gospel and no distinctions.</description><pubDate>Sat, 31 Jan 2026 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.mljtrust.org/sermons/book-of-romans/jew-and-gentile-no-difference/</guid><enclosure length="108485503" type="audio/mpeg" url="https://media.blubrry.com/mljsermons/sermons.mljtrust.org/3253-jew-and-gentile-no-difference.mp3"/></item><item><itunes:image href="https://www.mljtrust.org/static/images/mlj-podcast-1404.jpg"/><title>The Riches of His Grace</title><link>https://www.mljtrust.org/sermons/book-of-romans/the-riches-of-his-grace-2/</link><description>Romans 10:11-13 — In this sermon on “The Riches of His Grace” from Romans 10:11–13 Dr. Martyn Lloyd-Jones continues unfolding the apostle Paul’s argument for the inclusion of Gentiles in salvation. Working from this passage, his second point in the series draws from the glorious fact that the same Lord Jesus Christ, who is Lord over all, is rich in grace to all who call upon Him. Since salvation depends entirely upon God and His power to forgive, there is hope for anyone. It’s the great central theme of the Scripture foretold by the prophets, brought about by Jesus in the gospel, and proclaimed by the apostles and the early church. What does this mean for today? It doesn't matter how much one has sinned or how profound their ignorance is, the riches of God’s grace are endless and He is sufficient to give to all. There is no work or effort one can add to their salvation because His riches in salvation are all-sufficient. All worldly distinctions and prejudices are foolish because God is rich to all, without distinction, and there is nothing one can ever need that cannot be found in this endlessly rich savior.</description><pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.mljtrust.org/sermons/book-of-romans/the-riches-of-his-grace-2/</guid><enclosure length="95745791" type="audio/mpeg" url="https://media.blubrry.com/mljsermons/sermons.mljtrust.org/3252-the-riches-of-his-grace-2.mp3"/></item><item><itunes:image href="https://www.mljtrust.org/static/images/mlj-podcast-1404.jpg"/><title>God of Jew and Gentile</title><link>https://www.mljtrust.org/sermons/book-of-romans/god-of-jew-and-gentile/</link><description>Romans 10:11-13 — How does someone receive salvation? Paul says in Romans 10:11–13 that the first principle of salvation is belief and more specifically, belief in Christ Jesus. Paul just told the church in Rome that they must confess with their mouth that Jesus is Lord and now he says that they must believe in Him. All who believe will never be put to shame. Although the law and the devil may work against the Christian, the Lord has conquered all these things so that nothing in the whole cosmos could shame His people. In this sermon on Romans 10:11–13 titled “God of Jew and Gentile,” Dr. Martyn Lloyd-Jones points out that this specific passage thoroughly and completely emphasizes that salvation and belief are open to whoever calls on Christ, meaning that it equally applies to the Jews and the Gentiles. All are born under Adam, which means that all people groups are under the same condemnation. Paul is sharing that despite what they previously thought, the Jews have no special standing in regard to salvation. The hope is that all people are saved by believing in Christ. Once that is done, God’s salvation is perfect and secure for all eternity.</description><pubDate>Thu, 29 Jan 2026 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.mljtrust.org/sermons/book-of-romans/god-of-jew-and-gentile/</guid><enclosure length="92043235" type="audio/mpeg" url="https://media.blubrry.com/mljsermons/sermons.mljtrust.org/3251-god-of-jew-and-gentile.mp3"/></item><item><itunes:image href="https://www.mljtrust.org/static/images/mlj-podcast-1404.jpg"/><title>This Great Salvation</title><link>https://www.mljtrust.org/sermons/book-of-romans/this-great-salvation/</link><description>Romans 10:11-13 — What is Scripture all about? What makes the writings of the Old and New Testaments unique? In this sermon on salvation from Romans 10:11–13 titled “This Great Salvation,” Dr. Martyn Lloyd-Jones preaches on how Paul appeals to the Old Testament prophet Isaiah to show that salvation is for all who believe, both Jew and Gentile. Scripture reveals the one unified plan of salvation brought to pass in Jesus Christ. It speaks as one voice to humanity and declares that God has acted in Jesus Christ so that sinners can be saved. Those who want to do away with the Old Testament are in great danger of not only disregarding God’s holy Word, but they are also in danger of perverting the message of salvation. The whole Old Testament looks forward to when Jesus would come and die to save Jews and Gentiles. The message of Scripture is not an irrelevant one; it is the only message of salvation and forgiveness of sins.</description><pubDate>Wed, 28 Jan 2026 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.mljtrust.org/sermons/book-of-romans/this-great-salvation/</guid><enclosure length="80024835" type="audio/mpeg" url="https://media.blubrry.com/mljsermons/sermons.mljtrust.org/3250-this-great-salvation.mp3"/></item><item><itunes:image href="https://www.mljtrust.org/static/images/mlj-podcast-1404.jpg"/><title>Confessing the Lord Jesus Christ</title><link>https://www.mljtrust.org/sermons/book-of-romans/confessing-the-lord-jesus-christ/</link><description>Romans 10:9-10 — What does it mean to confess Jesus as Lord? Talk is cheap and when dealing with matters of life and death, one should think carefully about what it means to profess that Jesus is Lord. In this sermon on Romans 10:9–10 tiled “Confessing the Lord Jesus Christ,” Dr. Martyn Lloyd-Jones gives a practical list of what a true profession of faith will look like. If Jesus is Lord, it means that He is over everything. If He is the Lord of one’s life, then every part of their life should be changed when they encounter Jesus. If one is not sure if they have encountered Christ, they can ask themselves these five questions: “do you have a changed attitude towards sin? Do you love being with other Christians? Are you concerned with God’s glory? Are you able to give a reason for your hope when asked? Are you not ashamed of Christ, regardless of the consequences?” The answer to these questions reveal the truth about one’s heart. These are marks that can only come from God Himself through salvation. Dr. Lloyd-Jones will help the listener see that following Jesus is the greatest thing that they can ever do. It is more than an intellectual commitment; it transforms everything about the Christian.</description><pubDate>Tue, 27 Jan 2026 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.mljtrust.org/sermons/book-of-romans/confessing-the-lord-jesus-christ/</guid><enclosure length="91859994" type="audio/mpeg" url="https://media.blubrry.com/mljsermons/sermons.mljtrust.org/3249-confessing-the-lord-jesus-christ.mp3"/></item><item><itunes:image href="https://www.mljtrust.org/static/images/mlj-podcast-1404.jpg"/><title>A Right Confession</title><link>https://www.mljtrust.org/sermons/book-of-romans/a-right-confession/</link><description>Romans 10:9-10 — What are the evidences of salvation? Some say that confessing belief in Jesus is what saves but in this sermon on Romans 10:9–10 titled “A Right Confession,” Dr. Martyn Lloyd-Jones shows that confession only comes after a heart has been changed. This sermon shows that confessing Jesus as Lord is the confirmation of salvation but it is not what saves the person from their sin. The church in Acts gives an example that true salvation has evidence: one confesses that Jesus is Lord, turns away from their sin, follows the teaching of the Bible, and continues in fellowship with other believers. If one does not have these as marks in their life, confession is pointless because the heart has not been changed. By applying Paul’s letter, one sees that the work of a Christian is to proclaim Jesus as Lord by words and lives, not by parading Him around as a bumper sticker or Christian T-shirt. The work of God is much deeper than just outward signs and He works on the person in their entirety.</description><pubDate>Mon, 26 Jan 2026 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.mljtrust.org/sermons/book-of-romans/a-right-confession/</guid><enclosure length="86410888" type="audio/mpeg" url="https://media.blubrry.com/mljsermons/sermons.mljtrust.org/3248-a-right-confession.mp3"/></item><item><itunes:image href="https://www.mljtrust.org/static/images/mlj-podcast-1404.jpg"/><title>Assurance of Salvation</title><link>https://www.mljtrust.org/sermons/book-of-romans/assurance-of-salvation/</link><description>Romans 10:9-10 — Can a person be assured that they are saved or is salvation something that only God can know? In his sermon on Romans 10:9–10 titled “Assurance of Salvation,” Dr. Martyn Lloyd-Jones answers these questions by bringing the listener to Scripture. In the Bible, the answer is much more gracious and loving than the answers given commonly by people. Salvation is a work of God, not of humans, and how wonderful this truth is. If salvation was dependent on works, no one should have assurance of salvation. Think about how often people fail on the simplest of tasks and how often they let down those who love them most. Yet saving faith is given by God and because this is the case, they can rest in the assurance that God is the author of their salvation. Dr. Lloyd-Jones will show in this sermon on the assurance of salvation that it is the object of the Christian’s faith that gives assurance and it is God’s desire for every Christian to be assured of their salvation. Thank God He does not leave His children in the dark but has given a way to be bold in their salvation.</description><pubDate>Sun, 25 Jan 2026 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.mljtrust.org/sermons/book-of-romans/assurance-of-salvation/</guid><enclosure length="92321062" type="audio/mpeg" url="https://media.blubrry.com/mljsermons/sermons.mljtrust.org/3247-assurance-of-salvation.mp3"/></item><item><itunes:image href="https://www.mljtrust.org/static/images/mlj-podcast-1404.jpg"/><title>Saving Faith</title><link>https://www.mljtrust.org/sermons/book-of-romans/saving-faith/</link><description>Romans 10:9-10 — In this sermon on Romans 10:9–10 titled “Saving Faith,” Dr. Martyn Lloyd-Jones gives a roadmap through the Christian life as they experience God. Encountering God means that salvation is not only an intellectual decision or that God can be made known through reasonable thinking. Scripture demands that the Christian have faith in God and a faith that includes all of their being. But how can one possess such faith when they are full of fear and doubt? It is hard enough for a person to keep small commitments to themselves. Dr. Lloyd-Jones shows that it is precisely through encountering God that the Christian is given this faith by Him. God initiates this relationship that leads to Godly sorrow over sin, turning from them and putting faith in Jesus Christ. These are the very beginning steps in the Christian life and without them, one cannot be called a Christian. If one has been convicted of their sins, repented, changed their thoughts about God, and grieved over their sinfulness, they have shown the true marks of one who has encountered God and believed in the Lord Jesus Christ.</description><pubDate>Sat, 24 Jan 2026 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.mljtrust.org/sermons/book-of-romans/saving-faith/</guid><enclosure length="92174668" type="audio/mpeg" url="https://media.blubrry.com/mljsermons/sermons.mljtrust.org/3246-saving-faith.mp3"/></item><item><itunes:image href="https://www.mljtrust.org/static/images/mlj-podcast-1404.jpg"/><title>A Change of Heart</title><link>https://www.mljtrust.org/sermons/book-of-romans/a-change-of-heart/</link><description>Romans 10:9-10 — Is salvation merely an intellectual endeavor that begins and ends with the mind or does it include the heart? In this sermon on Romans 10:9–10 titled “A Change of Heart,” Dr. Martyn Lloyd-Jones examines what the apostles preached in their missionary journeys and what true salvation looks like. Throughout the New Testament, the apostles preach that saving faith is not only in the mind, but that it must include a change of heart. In the Old Testament, God promises to change the heart of stone into a heart of flesh. The question now is not whether or not the mind believes, but if the heart believes that Jesus is Lord. In today’s age many believe that one must only make a decision in order to be saved. Yet if this decision does not stem from a heart burdened by sin and seeking repentance from God, then it is not saving faith. Dr. Lloyd-Jones shows the hope of salvation that can only be given by God through the Son, a salvation that is so miraculous it changes a wicked heart into one that loves God.</description><pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.mljtrust.org/sermons/book-of-romans/a-change-of-heart/</guid><enclosure length="91811425" type="audio/mpeg" url="https://media.blubrry.com/mljsermons/sermons.mljtrust.org/3245-a-change-of-heart.mp3"/></item><item><itunes:image href="https://www.mljtrust.org/static/images/mlj-podcast-1404.jpg"/><title>The Condition of The Heart</title><link>https://www.mljtrust.org/sermons/book-of-romans/the-condition-of-the-heart/</link><description>Romans 10:9-10 — Why do some people demand that society must be more tolerant while simultaneously being intolerant of Christianity? Some even say that they believe in Jesus, yet scoff at the doctrine of repentance, saying that modern humanity needs a more intellectual message for today’s world. In this sermon on Romans 10:9–10 titled “The Condition of the Heart,” Dr. Martyn Lloyd-Jones confronts the notion that confessing Jesus as Lord is only an intellectual action and shows that true belief in Christ is one that affects the whole personality. By analyzing the book of Romans, one is able to see that the unbelief of a person cannot be broken by intellectual argument because the intellect has been darkened by the condition of the heart. Dr. Lloyd-Jones reminds that one’s condition before salvation hated God and that hatred controlled their thoughts towards God. One’s words reveal the condition of the heart, and out of the mouth is what reveals whether or not one truly believes in Christ. If  the listener is struggling to know what true belief is, this sermon will help them analyze Scripture and apply it to their life.</description><pubDate>Thu, 22 Jan 2026 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.mljtrust.org/sermons/book-of-romans/the-condition-of-the-heart/</guid><enclosure length="89841747" type="audio/mpeg" url="https://media.blubrry.com/mljsermons/sermons.mljtrust.org/3244-the-condition-of-the-heart.mp3"/></item><item><itunes:image href="https://www.mljtrust.org/static/images/mlj-podcast-1404.jpg"/><title>Essential for Salvation</title><link>https://www.mljtrust.org/sermons/book-of-romans/essential-for-salvation/</link><description>Romans 10:9-10 — What are the essential truths that must be made known for a person to be saved? Many say that the Bible teaches that one must only believe on the name of Jesus Christ to be saved. Others preach that one must believe in the person of Mary or that they must have extraordinary knowledge in order to be saved. In this sermon on Romans 10:9–10 titled “Essential for Salvation,” Dr. Martyn Lloyd-Jones shows the fallacy of both extremes. One temptation is to take away essential doctrines of the gospel in order to make it less offensive and more inclusive. The other temptation is to add more to the gospel than what is necessary, making it impossible for anyone to come to God and creating a works-based salvation. Dr. Lloyd-Jones shows through Scripture that the gospel message must include an explanation of who Jesus is, why He is needed, and why He is sufficient. This sermon will remind the listener of the biblical truth that a true evangelistic message must include repentance towards God and faith in Jesus Christ. In light of the truths presented in this sermon, the listener will be challenged to analyze their own beliefs and practices to see if they line up with the message of the apostles. Listeners will be encouraged to be bold in the proclamation of the gospel because it is the only true hope for the world.</description><pubDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2026 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.mljtrust.org/sermons/book-of-romans/essential-for-salvation/</guid><enclosure length="107562521" type="audio/mpeg" url="https://media.blubrry.com/mljsermons/sermons.mljtrust.org/3243-essential-for-salvation.mp3"/></item><item><itunes:image href="https://www.mljtrust.org/static/images/mlj-podcast-1404.jpg"/><title>Results of the Resurrection</title><link>https://www.mljtrust.org/sermons/book-of-romans/results-of-the-resurrection/</link><description>Romans 10:9-10 — What is at the center of history? In this sermon on Romans 10:9–10 titled “Results of the Resurrection,” Dr. Martyn Lloyd-Jones proclaims that it is Jesus Christ, the crucified Messiah. His sacrificial death on the cross of Calvary is the means by which God conquered sin, Satan, and the power of death. All the blessings that Christ gives are procured by His suffering and rising from the grave. He then ascended into heaven, where He lives and intercedes for His people. After ascending into heaven, He sent the Holy Spirit just as He promised, to empower and comfort believers and the church. Jesus will return to bring His Kingdom to completion by finally destroying death and evil once and for all. These glorious truths should lead all believers to trust and hope in God that He is faithful to bring the work of redemption to completion. Christians ought to live in light of this hope and never look to themselves for wisdom and strength, but rely wholly on Him who has conquered the grave and defeated death.</description><pubDate>Tue, 20 Jan 2026 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.mljtrust.org/sermons/book-of-romans/results-of-the-resurrection/</guid><enclosure length="104896696" type="audio/mpeg" url="https://media.blubrry.com/mljsermons/sermons.mljtrust.org/3242-results-of-the-resurrection.mp3"/></item><item><itunes:image href="https://www.mljtrust.org/static/images/mlj-podcast-1404.jpg"/><title>Why Christ Died</title><link>https://www.mljtrust.org/sermons/book-of-romans/why-christ-died/</link><description>Romans 10:9-10 — What is the content of saving faith? Why is the death and resurrection of the Lord Jesus Christ significant? In this sermon on Romans 10:9–10 titled “Why Christ Died,” Dr. Martyn Lloyd-Jones addresses these vital questions.  The belief in the death, burial, and resurrection of the Lord Jesus Christ is central to the Christian faith. It is these beliefs that form the heart of the Christian faith because only through Jesus becoming a man and dying for the sins of fallen people can God forgive sinners. Jesus came to this earth in the form of a servant in order to die and the resurrection declared not only that Christ had died for sinners, but it declared His victory over death, sin, and Satan. Christians have a living Savior who, after atoning for sin, ascended into heaven where He now rules over the whole earth and from where He will come to judge the living and the dead. The resurrection, explains Dr. Lloyd-Jones, is God’s public proclamation to the whole universe that he is satisfied with His son who has honored the law completely. God is proclaiming that He and His law are completely satisfied.</description><pubDate>Mon, 19 Jan 2026 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.mljtrust.org/sermons/book-of-romans/why-christ-died/</guid><enclosure length="88555627" type="audio/mpeg" url="https://media.blubrry.com/mljsermons/sermons.mljtrust.org/3241-why-christ-died.mp3"/></item><item><itunes:image href="https://www.mljtrust.org/static/images/mlj-podcast-1404.jpg"/><title>Jesus is Lord, Part 2</title><link>https://www.mljtrust.org/sermons/book-of-romans/jesus-is-lord-2/</link><description>Romans 10:9-10 — In this sermon on Romans 10:9–10 titled “Jesus is Lord (2),” the question is asked: who is Jesus? The answer in Scripture is that Jesus is Lord. The writers of holy Scripture tell that Jesus is far more than a human teacher; He is God’s anointed and the long-awaited Messiah that has been promised in the Old Testament. What does it mean that Jesus is Lord? As Lord, Jesus is worthy of all praise and trust. Jesus has come to fulfill all that God promised and He is God’s Son. The Christian must believe that Jesus is who He says He is, not simply who they want Him to be. This is important today because many say that Jesus is nothing more than a mere man who teaches people how to live and others say that Jesus is simply a man of faith. But Scripture is clear that Jesus was a real man, God in the flesh, who had come to die for the sins of the world. What does it matter if one says that Jesus is Lord or not? According to God’s Word, everything depends on who one says that Jesus is. If one confesses that Jesus is Lord they will be saved, but if they reject Him, they reject the only way of salvation.</description><pubDate>Sun, 18 Jan 2026 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.mljtrust.org/sermons/book-of-romans/jesus-is-lord-2/</guid><enclosure length="94445539" type="audio/mpeg" url="https://media.blubrry.com/mljsermons/sermons.mljtrust.org/3240-jesus-is-lord-2.mp3"/></item><item><itunes:image href="https://www.mljtrust.org/static/images/mlj-podcast-1404.jpg"/><title>Jesus is Lord, Part 1</title><link>https://www.mljtrust.org/sermons/book-of-romans/jesus-is-lord-1/</link><description>Romans 10:9-10 — Paul has finally laid to rest the theory of salvation through the law. Salvation is through faith alone and Paul tells the church in Rome that they must first declare “Jesus is Lord” in order to be saved. This is one of the great statements of the Christian gospel. The only way to be righteous before God is to believe God and his word by faith. In this sermon on Romans 10:9–10 titled “Jesus is Lord (1),” Dr. Martyn Lloyd-Jones says that the Christian must first consider the content of this saving faith. Salvation is all about Jesus and the fact that He is Lord. Christ is the firstborn of all creation and it is through Him that all was created. It is also through God that all of the cosmos will be restored once again. The second point is that God raised Christ from the dead. Without being completely clear of those two points, there is no salvation.</description><pubDate>Sat, 17 Jan 2026 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.mljtrust.org/sermons/book-of-romans/jesus-is-lord-1/</guid><enclosure length="97901124" type="audio/mpeg" url="https://media.blubrry.com/mljsermons/sermons.mljtrust.org/3239-jesus-is-lord-1.mp3"/></item><item><itunes:image href="https://www.mljtrust.org/static/images/mlj-podcast-1404.jpg"/><title>Righteousness by Faith</title><link>https://www.mljtrust.org/sermons/book-of-romans/righteousness-by-faith/</link><description>Romans 10:5-8 — How far away is the truth? What quest or journey must be traversed in order to find God? Is there some kind of special act one must perform in order to make their way to God? Many people teach that God is so far away that the gap is unspeakably difficult to cross. Others teach that one must cross the gap to God by their own efforts. Whether it is Roman Catholicism, the mystical way, or Protestant intellectualism, Dr. Martyn Lloyd-Jones finds the answer to such false systems in the apostle Paul’s words in Romans 10:5–8. The apostle invokes the great preacher of the law – Moses – in order to show that God has revealed Himself perfectly clearly. There is no need to ascend to heaven or descend into the deep. God, through Christ, has revealed Himself fully in the gospel and the gospel way is not about human efforts. It is not about their assent or justification by works. Salvation is about justification by faith alone in Christ Jesus alone. In this sermon on Romans 10:5–8 titled “Righteousness by Faith,” listen as Dr. Lloyd-Jones applies Paul’s gospel message to contemporary ears and encourages with the grace-filled message of our savior.</description><pubDate>Fri, 16 Jan 2026 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.mljtrust.org/sermons/book-of-romans/righteousness-by-faith/</guid><enclosure length="95902378" type="audio/mpeg" url="https://media.blubrry.com/mljsermons/sermons.mljtrust.org/3238-righteousness-by-faith.mp3"/></item><item><itunes:image href="https://www.mljtrust.org/static/images/mlj-podcast-1404.jpg"/><title>Righteousness by Law</title><link>https://www.mljtrust.org/sermons/book-of-romans/righteousness-by-law/</link><description>Romans 10:5 — The Jews have continued to believe that their actions, mainly their dedication to keeping the law, is what justifies them. The Jews have misunderstood the law and its purpose. Because of this, Paul is laying to rest this foolish thinking once again. In this sermon on Romans 10:5 titled “Righteousness by Law,” Dr. Martyn Lloyd-Jones shares how Paul is essentially saying that even Moses said that those who attempt to live by their actions will also be judged by their actions. He points out that the Jews were ignorant of God’s righteousness, ignorant of their own abilities, and thus have not submitted themselves to the righteousness of God. Paul continues to emphasize the doctrine of justification by faith only. There is not one thing in the process of salvation that has to do with a person; it is entirely a matter of God’s free sovereign choice. If the Jews want to live by their actions to the law, then Paul says they must keep the whole law. One is not able to only keep certain laws. If even one law is broken, they have failed completely. Dr. Lloyd-Jones reminds that no one wants to live under that kind of rule and reign and Christians should be thankful of the Lord’s work in them, breaking them free from the law.</description><pubDate>Thu, 15 Jan 2026 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.mljtrust.org/sermons/book-of-romans/righteousness-by-law/</guid><enclosure length="93279834" type="audio/mpeg" url="https://media.blubrry.com/mljsermons/sermons.mljtrust.org/3237-righteousness-by-law.mp3"/></item><item><itunes:image href="https://www.mljtrust.org/static/images/mlj-podcast-1404.jpg"/><title>Christ, the End of the Law</title><link>https://www.mljtrust.org/sermons/book-of-romans/christ-the-end-of-the-law/</link><description>Romans 10:4 — In this sermon on Romans 10:4 titled “Christ, the End of the Law,” Dr. Martyn Lloyd-Jones says that this Scripture is the charter for all Christians and it sets them free. In this verse, Paul proclaims that Christ is the fulfillment of the law for righteousness. He means that the law was not temporary but it is eternal. God is not doing away with the law but rather upholding the law. It is an expression of God’s holy character and what He expects of the human race. So how is Christ the end of the law? Christ has fulfilled the law and done this for all who believe in Him. He came into the world as a God-man born under the law, lived a life of perfect obedience to the law, and died to satisfy the punishment of the law. The fulfillment is true because God raised Him from the dead. No one else was able to do this. Christ is the end of the law for all who believe. The moment a Christian believes in Christ, all that Christ has done for them becomes true of them since they have been united with Christ.</description><pubDate>Wed, 14 Jan 2026 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.mljtrust.org/sermons/book-of-romans/christ-the-end-of-the-law/</guid><enclosure length="95447883" type="audio/mpeg" url="https://media.blubrry.com/mljsermons/sermons.mljtrust.org/3236-christ-the-end-of-the-law.mp3"/></item><item><itunes:image href="https://www.mljtrust.org/static/images/mlj-podcast-1404.jpg"/><title>Submit to God's Righteousness</title><link>https://www.mljtrust.org/sermons/book-of-romans/submit-to-gods-righteousness/</link><description>Romans 10:1-3 — Since the inception of the church, Christianity has battled the false belief of justification by works. In its modern Western form, many wrongly understand the gospel to mean going to church, doing good, or being a “nice” person. In this sermon on Romans 10:1–3 titled “Submit to God’s Righteousness,” Dr. Martyn Lloyd-Jones proclaims that the current Christian culture continues to preach self-righteousness, self-reliance, and self-dependence. In its primitive form, the apostle Paul holds up the Pharisees as the prime example of those who are zealous for doing good works and yet are ignorant of what God’s righteousness requires in the gospel. Their lack of knowledge has set them against the God they claim to serve. They would rather construct their own righteousness than submit to the righteousness of God found in the gospel of Christ. The Pharisees, and many today as well, are trapped in believing they can save themselves. The problem, says Dr. Lloyd-Jones, is that the last people to believe the gospel and be saved are always those who think that they can save themselves. What is needed is the gospel of grace. What needs to be known and heard is the truth of what the Scriptures say God’s righteousness requires. Listen as Dr. Lloyd-Jones speaks of the tendency towards justification by works and the remedy, submitting to the gospel of grace.</description><pubDate>Tue, 13 Jan 2026 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.mljtrust.org/sermons/book-of-romans/submit-to-gods-righteousness/</guid><enclosure length="114606259" type="audio/mpeg" url="https://media.blubrry.com/mljsermons/sermons.mljtrust.org/3235-submit-to-gods-righteousness.mp3"/></item><item><itunes:image href="https://www.mljtrust.org/static/images/mlj-podcast-1404.jpg"/><title>Knowledge of the Truth</title><link>https://www.mljtrust.org/sermons/book-of-romans/knowledge-of-the-truth-2/</link><description>Romans 10:3 — What was the main trouble with the Jews that Paul is speaking about in Romans 10:3? It is that they did not have a complete and full knowledge of the truth of God. In this sermon on Romans 10:3 titled “Knowledge of the Truth,” Dr. Martyn Lloyd-Jones says that a precise knowledge of the truth is essential to salvation and Paul is praying and longing for the salvation of the Jews because they lack this knowledge. The Jews may have been nice people and very zealous, but this cannot be mistaken for true Christian faith. Truth cannot be based in subjective terms because the gospel is truly objective. The Pharisees had misinterpreted the Old Testament teaching about the righteousness of God and the righteousness that He demands. This was ignorance on their part. Ignorance means that there is not full knowledge and the Jews were ignorant of the full knowledge of God. This stood in between them and their salvation. Dr. Lloyd-Jones urges the listener to have a precise knowledge because ignorant knowledge is the enemy. Without true knowledge, one will be lost, damned, and outside the kingdom of God.</description><pubDate>Mon, 12 Jan 2026 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.mljtrust.org/sermons/book-of-romans/knowledge-of-the-truth-2/</guid><enclosure length="97287150" type="audio/mpeg" url="https://media.blubrry.com/mljsermons/sermons.mljtrust.org/3234-knowledge-of-the-truth-2.mp3"/></item><item><itunes:image href="https://www.mljtrust.org/static/images/mlj-podcast-1404.jpg"/><title>True and False Zeal</title><link>https://www.mljtrust.org/sermons/book-of-romans/true-and-false-zeal-2/</link><description>Romans 10:1-2 — Is the Christian zealous for God? If so, is it a true or false sense of zeal? Paul points out that the church does have a zeal for God, but that it is not based on knowledge. In a sermon on Romans 10:1–2 titled “Trust and Zeal,” Dr. Martyn Lloyd-Jones outlines the differences between true and false zeal in the Christian life. First, he outlines several tests that can apply to a person’s zeal to determine if it is a false sense of zeal. A few of these arguments include a zeal that has been imposed rather than genuine; a focus on actions rather than just being oneself; a likeness to frivolity and the flesh; and a focus on self and one’s own power rather than the Lord’s. On the other hand, a few arguments for true zeal include a zeal that is put on by the Lord;  a result of true knowledge; zeal that is not showy but deep; and a result of genuine behavior. At the end, Dr. Lloyd-Jones charges believers to ensure they have true zeal for the sake of those who are lost. He challenges those who have heard the gospel and know the truth to be zealous and concerned for those who have not heard.</description><pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.mljtrust.org/sermons/book-of-romans/true-and-false-zeal-2/</guid><enclosure length="109523824" type="audio/mpeg" url="https://media.blubrry.com/mljsermons/sermons.mljtrust.org/3233-true-and-false-zeal-2.mp3"/></item></channel></rss>