<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="rssfeed.xsl" ?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/css" href="rssfeed.css" ?>
<rss xmlns:itunes="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">

<channel>
<title>Preach The Word - David Legge</title>
<atom:link href="https://www.preachtheword.com/preachtheword.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
<link>https://www.preachtheword.com</link>
<description>Providing sound Bible teaching through the ministry of David Legge, an evangelist, preacher and Bible teacher from Northern Ireland. Watch or listen to David's sermons on the subjects of revival, evangelism and more!</description>
<itunes:author>David Legge</itunes:author>
<itunes:subtitle>Providing sound Bible teaching through the ministry of David Legge, an evangelist, preacher and Bible teacher from Belfast, Northern Ireland.</itunes:subtitle>
<itunes:keywords>sermons,david legge,christian,gospel,bible study,preach the word,preachtheword,preaching,evangelical,biblical,christianity,revival,religion,ireland,belfast,irish,podcast,godcast</itunes:keywords>
<itunes:summary>Bible study sermon podcast from the Christian ministry Preach The Word - sharing the preaching and teaching ministry of David Legge, an evangelist, preacher and Bible teacher from Belfast, Northern Ireland. Our site contains archives of previous Podcasts in MP3 audio and word-for-word transcripts.</itunes:summary>
<language>en-gb</language>
<copyright>Copyright 2026 preachtheword.com</copyright>
<itunes:category text="Religion &amp; Spirituality">
<itunes:category text="Christianity"/>
</itunes:category>
<itunes:image href="http://www.preachtheword.com/images/albumart2025.jpg" />
<itunes:owner>
<itunes:name>Preach The Word</itunes:name>
<itunes:email>info@preachtheword.com</itunes:email>
</itunes:owner>
<itunes:explicit>false</itunes:explicit>
<lastBuildDate>Sat, 28 Feb 2026 10:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
<webMaster>info@preachtheword.com (Preach The Word)</webMaster>
<ttl>800</ttl>

<image>
<title>Preach The Word - Audio Sermons</title>
<link>https://www.preachtheword.com</link>
<url>http://www.preachtheword.com/images/albumart2025.jpg</url>
<description>Providing sound Bible teaching through the ministry of David Legge, an evangelist, preacher and Bible teacher from Belfast, Northern Ireland.</description>
</image>

<item>
<title>To Believe, Or Not Believe: That Is The Question</title>
<link>https://www.preachtheword.com/sermon/misc0207-to-believe-or-not.shtml</link>
<guid>https://www.preachtheword.com/sermon/misc0207-to-believe-or-not.shtml</guid>
<author>info@preachtheword.com (Preach The Word)</author>
<category>Religion &amp; Spirituality</category>
<description>Doubt and unbelief are not the same. Doubt can be a struggle to faith or in faith, but unbelief is a decision not to believe. In John 20:24-31, Thomas, perhaps, seems to have struggled with both. This may likely have been out of a fear of being devastated by disappointment again. His hopes were dashed when Jesus died. He needed to know if this resurrection business was true. In 'To Believe, Or Not Believe: That Is The Question', David explores how doubt is not necessarily a problem, but can be a conversation-starter with God that may lead to the miraculous. This message is available at https://www.preachtheword.com now in MP3 audio format...</description>
<pubDate>Sat, 28 Feb 2026 10:01:01 GMT</pubDate>
<itunes:duration>37:16</itunes:duration>
<itunes:explicit>false</itunes:explicit>
<enclosure url="https://audio.preachtheword.com/topical/misc0207.mp3" length="36073771" type="audio/mpeg"/>
</item>

<item>
<title>One Thing I Know</title>
<link>https://www.preachtheword.com/sermon/misc0206-one-thing-i-know.shtml</link>
<guid>https://www.preachtheword.com/sermon/misc0206-one-thing-i-know.shtml</guid>
<author>info@preachtheword.com (Preach The Word)</author>
<category>Religion &amp; Spirituality</category>
<description>Chapter 9 of John's Gospel is filled with so many questions. A man who was born blind is healed on the Sabbath by Jesus and a furore of religious questions and debate erupts. In 'One Thing I Know', we explore the contrast between mere religious knowledge and the pride that can result; and the seeming lack of knowledge of the healed man, yet his authentic experience with the power of God through his healing. Let us not simply seek information, lacking revelation and transformation. Even if we don't have all the information, transformation is more desirable. This message is available at https://www.preachtheword.com now in MP3 audio format...</description>
<pubDate>Sat, 14 Feb 2026 10:01:01 GMT</pubDate>
<itunes:duration>36:57</itunes:duration>
<itunes:explicit>false</itunes:explicit>
<enclosure url="https://audio.preachtheword.com/topical/misc0206.mp3" length="35771926" type="audio/mpeg"/>
</item>	

<item>
<title>The Ultimate Secret To Overcoming Sin</title>
<link>https://www.preachtheword.com/sermon/misc0205-overcoming-sin.shtml</link>
<guid>https://www.preachtheword.com/sermon/misc0205-overcoming-sin.shtml</guid>
<author>info@preachtheword.com (Preach The Word)</author>
<category>Religion &amp; Spirituality</category>
<description>All of us struggle with temptation and sin, if we're honest. One of the main reasons for this is that it can be so pleasurable. We were wired for pleasure - so that makes it even harder to resist. However, once we discover that God created pleasure so we could have our greatest pleasure in Him, a shift can take place in our understanding and experience. The only way to eclipse our most dominant sinful attractions is to become overwhelmed by a greater attraction - the beauty of the Lord! If you have tried everything to overcome temptation but cannot - here is a message for you: 'The Ultimate Secret To Overcoming Sin' found in Matthew 17:1-8 and 2 Corinthians 3:17-18. This message is available at https://www.preachtheword.com now in MP3 audio format...</description>
<pubDate>Sat, 31 Jan 2026 14:01:01 GMT</pubDate>
<itunes:duration>40:27</itunes:duration>
<itunes:explicit>false</itunes:explicit>
<enclosure url="https://audio.preachtheword.com/topical/misc0205.mp3" length="39126363" type="audio/mpeg"/>
</item>	

<item>
<title>Fools For Christ</title>
<link>https://www.preachtheword.com/sermon/misc0204-fools-for-christ.shtml</link>
<guid>https://www.preachtheword.com/sermon/misc0204-fools-for-christ.shtml</guid>
<author>info@preachtheword.com (Preach The Word)</author>
<category>Religion &amp; Spirituality</category>
<description>We should not be idiots for the sake of it! The church has had enough bad press over the years. But in 2 Corinthians 5:13-15 we are called to be 'Fools For Christ'. To die to reputation and other's opinion of us. This message is a call to arms, like Christian soldiers, to count the cost and join the battle. We will be a fool for something - will it be the love of God? Or are we fools for the love of self or this world? This is a challenging message that calls us back to the claims of Christ upon our lives. This message is available at https://www.preachtheword.com now in MP3 audio format...</description>
<pubDate>Thu, 15 Jan 2026 10:01:01 GMT</pubDate>
<itunes:duration>30:06</itunes:duration>
<itunes:explicit>false</itunes:explicit>
<enclosure url="https://audio.preachtheword.com/topical/misc0204.mp3" length="29184340" type="audio/mpeg"/>
</item>	

<item>
<title>Getting God Wrong</title>
<link>https://www.preachtheword.com/sermon/misc0203-getting-god-wrong.shtml</link>
<guid>https://www.preachtheword.com/sermon/misc0203-getting-god-wrong.shtml</guid>
<author>info@preachtheword.com (Preach The Word)</author>
<category>Religion &amp; Spirituality</category>
<description>A.W. Tozer said the most important thing about us is what we think of when we think about God. Many Christians have a wrong concept of what God is like and how He is toward them and all sinners. In this message from the heart, David expresses how near God is to each and every one of us and how His heart is one of love toward us and not judgement. Be encouraged that God is not far from you and is FOR you! This message is available at https://www.preachtheword.com now in MP3 audio format...</description>
<pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 2025 10:01:01 GMT</pubDate>
<itunes:duration>28:01</itunes:duration>
<itunes:explicit>false</itunes:explicit>
<enclosure url="https://audio.preachtheword.com/topical/misc0203.mp3" length="27182733" type="audio/mpeg"/>
</item>	

<item>
<title>The God Who Is And Is Love</title>
<link>https://www.preachtheword.com/sermon/gospel106-god-is-love.shtml</link>
<guid>https://www.preachtheword.com/sermon/gospel106-god-is-love.shtml</guid>
<author>info@preachtheword.com (Preach The Word)</author>
<category>Religion &amp; Spirituality</category>
<description>In this informative and topical message David explains the most famous verse in the Bible, John 3:16, and shows how God is real and more people in the West are opening to His reality. He also shows how God is a God of love who is at pains to communicate His great love to the whole world. This is a cultural moment when so many people are hopeless - the greatest hope is in this Good News - 'The God Who Is And Is Love'. This message is available at https://www.preachtheword.com now in MP3 audio format...</description>
<pubDate>Sun, 30 Nov 2025 10:01:01 GMT</pubDate>
<itunes:duration>28:05</itunes:duration>
<itunes:explicit>false</itunes:explicit>
<enclosure url="https://audio.preachtheword.com/gospel/gospel106.mp3" length="27255040" type="audio/mpeg"/>
</item>	

<item>
<title>The Wind Of The Spirit</title>
<link>https://www.preachtheword.com/sermon/gospel105-wind-spirit.shtml</link>
<guid>https://www.preachtheword.com/sermon/gospel105-wind-spirit.shtml</guid>
<author>info@preachtheword.com (Preach The Word)</author>
<category>Religion &amp; Spirituality</category>
<description>This message on John 3:1-8 on 'The Wind of the Spirit' was preached on Pentecost Sunday. David explores the image of the Spirit being like wind and breath and how that impacts our lives. The need to be 'born again of the Spirit' and be 'filled with the Spirit' of God. The Christian message is about God's breath living in us, possessing us so that we can live His life. This message is available at https://www.preachtheword.com now in MP3 audio format...</description>
<pubDate>Sat, 15 Nov 2025 10:01:01 GMT</pubDate>
<itunes:duration>34:14</itunes:duration>
<itunes:explicit>false</itunes:explicit>
<enclosure url="https://audio.preachtheword.com/gospel/gospel105.mp3" length="33150354" type="audio/mpeg"/>
</item>	

<item>
<title>Saul's Suddenly</title>
<link>https://www.preachtheword.com/sermon/misc0202-saul-suddenly.shtml</link>
<guid>https://www.preachtheword.com/sermon/misc0202-saul-suddenly.shtml</guid>
<author>info@preachtheword.com (Preach The Word)</author>
<category>Religion &amp; Spirituality</category>
<description>Here is a fresh perspective on probably the most famous conversion of them all, recorded in Acts 9:1-19, Saul of Tarsus. This was a man who had an experience of religion, but needed a personal experience with God - and we all need this! We need to have an ongoing experience of encounters with the Lord. This is how Saul's started - but though it was sudden, it was the beginning of a life-long journey. There's also an interesting healing that takes place, when Saul receives his sight again through the hands of an ordinary disciple named Ananias. Join us for some wonderful lessons here on God's kingdom! This message is available at https://www.preachtheword.com now in MP3 audio format...</description>
<pubDate>Sat, 01 Nov 2025 10:01:01 GMT</pubDate>
<itunes:duration>42:50</itunes:duration>
<itunes:explicit>false</itunes:explicit>
<enclosure url="https://audio.preachtheword.com/topical/misc0202.mp3" length="41411904" type="audio/mpeg"/>
</item>	

<item>
<title>The Stiller Of Storms</title>
<link>https://www.preachtheword.com/sermon/misc0201-stiller-of-storms.shtml</link>
<guid>https://www.preachtheword.com/sermon/misc0201-stiller-of-storms.shtml</guid>
<author>info@preachtheword.com (Preach The Word)</author>
<category>Religion &amp; Spirituality</category>
<description>The Lord Jesus Christ is the man of miracles, and 'The Stiller Of Storms'. Here in Mark 4:35-41 we see one of four significant miracles that demonstrate His power. Here the force of nature; a devil-inspired storm is tamed and defeated by a word from God's Son. However, prior to the miracle the disciples were doubting and wondering if Jesus cared. Life's storms can cause us to doubt God's goodness toward us. This is what Satan wants, but even in the most diabolical storms God can reveal His love and power to His children. This message is available at https://www.preachtheword.com now in MP3 audio format...</description>
<pubDate>Wed, 15 Oct 2025 10:01:01 GMT</pubDate>
<itunes:duration>43:20</itunes:duration>
<itunes:explicit>false</itunes:explicit>
<enclosure url="https://audio.preachtheword.com/topical/misc0201.mp3" length="41891222" type="audio/mpeg"/>
</item>	

<item>
<title>The God Of Rescue</title>
<link>https://www.preachtheword.com/sermon/misc0200-god-of-rescue.shtml</link>
<guid>https://www.preachtheword.com/sermon/misc0200-god-of-rescue.shtml</guid>
<author>info@preachtheword.com (Preach The Word)</author>
<category>Religion &amp; Spirituality</category>
<description>We believe David penned Psalm 34 as he reflected upon his flight from King Saul. He was filled with fear and had made mistakes to try to get out of the situation. But even in his error, when he cried to God, he was heard and delivered by the God of rescue. Listen to this message and be encouraged that what David needed freedom from is often what we face: fears, shame and troubles - and we can get the freedom the same way he did - through seeking 'The God Of Rescue' and looking to Him. This message is available at https://www.preachtheword.com now in MP3 audio format...</description>
<pubDate>Tue, 30 Sept 2025 15:01:00 GMT</pubDate>
<itunes:duration>36:36</itunes:duration>
<itunes:explicit>false</itunes:explicit>
<enclosure url="https://audio.preachtheword.com/topical/misc0200.mp3" length="35421616" type="audio/mpeg"/>
</item>	

<item>
<title>When The Kingdom Comes</title>
<link>https://www.preachtheword.com/sermon/misc0199-when-kingdom-comes.shtml</link>
<guid>https://www.preachtheword.com/sermon/misc0199-when-kingdom-comes.shtml</guid>
<author>info@preachtheword.com (Preach The Word)</author>
<category>Religion &amp; Spirituality</category>
<description>Jesus came to bring the Kingdom of God – God's rule and reign. It did not come as everyone expected. People had to change their mind (repent) and believe in Jesus the King. In this panoramic look at the acts of Jesus after He announced the Kingdom we see the nature of His Kingdom and what happens 'When The Kingdom Comes' among us. As you listen, expect God's Kingdom to invade your life. Allow Him to change your thinking and embrace His Lordship in your heart. This message is available at https://www.preachtheword.com now in MP3 audio format...</description>
<pubDate>Fri, 12 Sep 2025 10:01:01 GMT</pubDate>
<itunes:duration>39:07</itunes:duration>
<itunes:explicit>false</itunes:explicit>
<enclosure url="https://audio.preachtheword.com/topical/misc0199.mp3" length="37837024" type="audio/mpeg"/>
</item>	

<item>
<title>The Power Of The Word Of Christ</title>
<link>https://www.preachtheword.com/sermon/misc0198-power-word-christ.shtml</link>
<guid>https://www.preachtheword.com/sermon/misc0198-power-word-christ.shtml</guid>
<author>info@preachtheword.com (Preach The Word)</author>
<category>Religion &amp; Spirituality</category>
<description>In 'The Power Of The Word Of Christ' from Matthew 8:1-13, 16-17, 23-34, we are taught how powerful Christ's word is in saving, healing, and delivering. Psalm 107:20 says, 'He sent His word and healed them, and delivered them from their destructions'. Listen and be encouraged to trust Christ's word to transform your difficult situations. This is a message to uplift your heart! This message is available at https://www.preachtheword.com now in MP3 audio format...</description>
<pubDate>Sun, 31 Aug 2025 10:01:01 GMT</pubDate>
<itunes:duration>35:21</itunes:duration>
<itunes:explicit>false</itunes:explicit>
<enclosure url="https://audio.preachtheword.com/topical/misc0198.mp3" length="34223807" type="audio/mpeg"/>
</item>	

<item>
<title>Overwhelmed</title>
<link>https://www.preachtheword.com/sermon/misc0197-overwhelmed.shtml</link>
<guid>https://www.preachtheword.com/sermon/misc0197-overwhelmed.shtml</guid>
<author>info@preachtheword.com (Preach The Word)</author>
<category>Religion &amp; Spirituality</category>
<description>'Overwhelmed' is how many would describe how they feel right now, especially Gen Z. In the Bible, David revealed that's how he once felt. Many Bible characters like Jonah, Elijah, and Jeremiah despaired of their lives. Even Jesus said, 'My soul is overwhelmed with sorrow to the point of death' in Matthew 26:38. If you feel overwhelmed, you are in good company. Learn from David's strategy for overcoming overwhelming here in Psalm 61. This message is available at https://www.preachtheword.com now in MP3 audio format...</description>
<pubDate>Fri, 15 Aug 2025 10:01:01 GMT</pubDate>
<itunes:duration>36:51</itunes:duration>
<itunes:explicit>false</itunes:explicit>
<enclosure url="https://audio.preachtheword.com/topical/misc0197.mp3" length="35669039" type="audio/mpeg"/>
</item>	

<item>
<title>Tongue-Tied</title>
<link>https://www.preachtheword.com/sermon/misc0196-tongue-tied.shtml</link>
<guid>https://www.preachtheword.com/sermon/misc0196-tongue-tied.shtml</guid>
<author>info@preachtheword.com (Preach The Word)</author>
<category>Religion &amp; Spirituality</category>
<description>There is a power in our words that is more than we imagine. Power to bless or curse. Power to bring life or death. In 'Tongue-Tied', David explores how not only our words affect others whom we speak against, but our words can bind us. Our words carry spiritual import. Our words project the condition of our hearts. Learn how to have victory in your speech and be loosed from spiritual ties originating from the tongue. This message is available at https://www.preachtheword.com now in MP3 audio format...</description>
<pubDate>Fri, 01 Aug 2025 10:01:01 GMT</pubDate>
<itunes:duration>49:07</itunes:duration>
<itunes:explicit>false</itunes:explicit>
<enclosure url="https://audio.preachtheword.com/topical/misc0196.mp3" length="47438360" type="audio/mpeg"/>
</item>	

<item>
<title>Rescued To Safety</title>
<link>https://www.preachtheword.com/sermon/misc0195-rescued-safety.shtml</link>
<guid>https://www.preachtheword.com/sermon/misc0195-rescued-safety.shtml</guid>
<author>info@preachtheword.com (Preach The Word)</author>
<category>Religion &amp; Spirituality</category>
<description>XXDESCXX In this story from John 5:1-17 of the healing of the man at the pool of Bethesda, Jesus is recorded as asking the paralysed man what appears to be a silly - if not cruel - question: 'Do you want to be healed?' We see in this story that Jesus the Great Physician had diagnosed a loss of hope in this man. He'd given up. Many feel they have been overlooked by God, not just in the area of healing but also salvation. People can even become ill through despair and disappointment. There are many lessons in this story about the healing and saving ways of our Lord, come and learn them with us. This message is available at https://www.preachtheword.com now in MP3 audio format...</description>
<pubDate>Mon, 30 Jun 2025 10:01:01 GMT</pubDate>
<itunes:duration>40:29</itunes:duration>
<itunes:explicit>false</itunes:explicit>
<enclosure url="https://audio.preachtheword.com/topical/misc0195.mp3" length="39155681" type="audio/mpeg"/>
</item>	

<item>
<title>A New Dawn</title>
<link>https://www.preachtheword.com/sermon/misc0194-new-dawn.shtml</link>
<guid>https://www.preachtheword.com/sermon/misc0194-new-dawn.shtml</guid>
<author>info@preachtheword.com (Preach The Word)</author>
<category>Religion &amp; Spirituality</category>
<description>After the darkness of centuries, Malachi promises a Messiah would come to will heal the hurts of His people - 'the Sun of Righteousness with healing in His wings'. In 'A New Dawn', we see some of the heart-warming parallels between the natural Sun and the Son of God, the Saviour and healer of humanity. May your horizon be shifted as you listen to this message; may your darkness be dispelled and may you take shelter underneath the wings of Almighty God. This message is available at https://www.preachtheword.com now in MP3 audio format...</description>
<pubDate>Sat, 14 Jun 2025 10:01:01 GMT</pubDate>
<itunes:duration>37:47</itunes:duration>
<itunes:explicit>false</itunes:explicit>
<enclosure url="https://audio.preachtheword.com/topical/misc0194.mp3" length="36567234" type="audio/mpeg"/>
</item>	

<item>
<title>Is Your Gospel Too Small?</title>
<link>https://www.preachtheword.com/sermon/misc0193-gospel-too-small.shtml</link>
<guid>https://www.preachtheword.com/sermon/misc0193-gospel-too-small.shtml</guid>
<author>info@preachtheword.com (Preach The Word)</author>
<category>Religion &amp; Spirituality</category>
<description>We are so blessed to be forgiven and saved from our sins as Christians - but many of us have underestimated the scope of the Gospel. There is also the healing of the heart and the setting free from the powers of darkness. In 'Is Your Gospel Too Small?', David explores the mission statement or mandate of Messiah from Isaiah 61, which Jesus quoted in His home synagogue in Nazareth. It outlines what the Messiah of the Jews and the Saviour of the world would come to earth to do. Be encouraged and liberated as you listen to these life-changing truths! This message is available at https://www.preachtheword.com now in MP3 audio format and in HD video on our YouTube Channel (https://youtube.com/PreachTheWord)...</description>
<pubDate>Sat, 31 May 2025 10:01:01 GMT</pubDate>
<itunes:duration>45:45</itunes:duration>
<itunes:explicit>false</itunes:explicit>
<enclosure url="https://audio.preachtheword.com/topical/misc0193.mp3" length="44209296" type="audio/mpeg"/>
</item>	

<item>
<title>The Benefits Of Belonging</title>
<link>https://www.preachtheword.com/sermon/misc0192-benefits-belonging.shtml</link>
<guid>https://www.preachtheword.com/sermon/misc0192-benefits-belonging.shtml</guid>
<author>info@preachtheword.com (Preach The Word)</author>
<category>Religion &amp; Spirituality</category>
<description>Often we have a transactional rather than a relational connection to God. We're in it for what we get out of it. However, rather than a clinical or legal association with God, through Christ, we have a relationship of belonging to God's family. That involves inheritance and many blessings of belonging. In 'The Benefits Of Belonging', David explores some of these blessings of belonging from Psalm 103. This message is available at https://www.preachtheword.com now in MP3 audio format...</description>
<pubDate>Thu, 15 May 2025 10:01:01 GMT</pubDate>
<itunes:duration>43:22</itunes:duration>
<itunes:explicit>false</itunes:explicit>
<enclosure url="https://audio.preachtheword.com/topical/misc0192.mp3" length="41926726" type="audio/mpeg"/>
</item>	

<item>
<title>Hope For The Hopeless and Life For The Lifeless</title>
<link>https://www.preachtheword.com/sermon/misc0184-hope-hopeless.shtml</link>
<guid>https://www.preachtheword.com/sermon/misc0184-hope-hopeless.shtml</guid>
<author>info@preachtheword.com (Preach The Word)</author>
<category>Religion &amp; Spirituality</category>
<description>Luke 7:11-17 depicts such tragedy for a widowed woman, who has now lost her only son. Jesus brings a resurrection miracle and shows how He gives 'Hope To The Hopeless and Life To The Lifeless'. If you are in need of hope today, listen to this message and encounter Jesus the compassionate and fully human Saviour! This message is available at https://www.preachtheword.com now in MP3 audio format...</description>
<pubDate>Thu, 01 May 2025 10:01:01 GMT</pubDate>
<itunes:duration>36:36</itunes:duration>
<itunes:explicit>false</itunes:explicit>
<enclosure url="https://audio.preachtheword.com/topical/misc0184.mp3" length="35429595" type="audio/mpeg"/>
</item>	

<item>
<title>One Body, One Voice</title>
<link>https://www.preachtheword.com/sermon/misc0190-unity.shtml</link>
<guid>https://www.preachtheword.com/sermon/misc0190-unity.shtml</guid>
<author>info@preachtheword.com (Preach The Word)</author>
<category>Religion &amp; Spirituality</category>
<description>Unity was a mark of the early church, but divisions over centuries of church history have obscured it. Divisions have hindered our witness in the world. We need to forge authentic unity with all Christians in our modern age who truly love our Lord Jesus Christ - 'One Body, One Voice'. This message is available at https://www.preachtheword.com now in MP3 audio format...</description>
<pubDate>Tue, 01 Apr 2025 10:01:01 GMT</pubDate>
<itunes:duration>59:49</itunes:duration>
<itunes:explicit>false</itunes:explicit>
<enclosure url="https://audio.preachtheword.com/topical/misc0190.mp3" length="57722236" type="audio/mpeg"/>
</item>	

<item>
<title>A Healing Of Two Halves</title>
<link>https://www.preachtheword.com/sermon/misc0189-healing-two-halves.shtml</link>
<guid>https://www.preachtheword.com/sermon/misc0189-healing-two-halves.shtml</guid>
<author>info@preachtheword.com (Preach The Word)</author>
<category>Religion &amp; Spirituality</category>
<description>The healing of the blind man in Mark 8:22-26 is the only gradual healing recorded in the gospels. There must be something that the Holy Spirit wants to teach us in this. Certainly, there was no deficiency on Jesus' part or weakness in the miracle power of God. So what was going on? In this message you will learn how environments and company can affect spiritual power – unbelief impedes the supernatural. Also, David spends some time considering that not all healing is instant but a process, and we need to have much faith and submit to God's ways and timing. God's power is the same, but not everyone receives it the same way. This message is available at https://www.preachtheword.com now in MP3 audio format...</description>
<pubDate>Sat, 15 Mar 2025 10:01:01 GMT</pubDate>
<itunes:duration>34:52</itunes:duration>
<itunes:explicit>false</itunes:explicit>
<enclosure url="https://audio.preachtheword.com/topical/misc0189.mp3" length="33757740" type="audio/mpeg"/>
</item>	

<item>
<title>A Not So Silly Question</title>
<link>https://www.preachtheword.com/sermon/misc0188-not-silly-question.shtml</link>
<guid>https://www.preachtheword.com/sermon/misc0188-not-silly-question.shtml</guid>
<author>info@preachtheword.com (Preach The Word)</author>
<category>Religion &amp; Spirituality</category>
<description>In this story from John 5:1-17 of the healing of the man at the pool of Bethesda, Jesus is recorded as asking the paralysed man what appears to be a silly - if not cruel - question: 'Do you want to be healed?' We see in this story that Jesus the Great Physician had diagnosed a loss of hope in this man. He'd given up. Many feel they have been overlooked by God, not just in the area of healing but also salvation. People can even become ill through despair and disappointment. There are many lessons in this story about the healing and saving ways of our Lord, come and learn them with us. This message is available at https://www.preachtheword.com now in MP3 audio format...</description>
<pubDate>Sat, 01 Mar 2025 10:01:01 GMT</pubDate>
<itunes:duration>38:29</itunes:duration>
<itunes:explicit>false</itunes:explicit>
<enclosure url="https://audio.preachtheword.com/topical/misc0188.mp3" length="37232651" type="audio/mpeg"/>
</item>	

<item>
<title>The Unchanging Christ</title>
<link>https://www.preachtheword.com/sermon/misc0187-unchanging-christ.shtml</link>
<guid>https://www.preachtheword.com/sermon/misc0187-unchanging-christ.shtml</guid>
<author>info@preachtheword.com (Preach The Word)</author>
<category>Religion &amp; Spirituality</category>
<description>Jesus is our unchanging Lord in a world where change is the norm. Even the godliest leaders pass away but Jesus remains 'the same yesterday, today and forever'. In this message from Hebrews 13:5-9, David presents Jesus as the ONLY answer to all our problems; specifically, loneliness, turbulent times, the assault on truth and unbelief. Listen in and be encouraged that Jesus Christ is the same as He always was and can still do today what we see Him do in Matthew, Mark, Luke and John - and He is the hope of our future! This message is available at https://www.preachtheword.com now in MP3 audio format...</description>
<pubDate>Sat, 15 Feb 2025 10:01:01 GMT</pubDate>
<itunes:duration>44:31</itunes:duration>
<itunes:explicit>false</itunes:explicit>
<enclosure url="https://audio.preachtheword.com/topical/misc0187.mp3" length="43030967" type="audio/mpeg"/>
</item>	

<item>
<title>The Greatest Invitation (to Divine Conversation)</title>
<link>https://www.preachtheword.com/sermon/misc0186-greatest-invitation.shtml</link>
<guid>https://www.preachtheword.com/sermon/misc0186-greatest-invitation.shtml</guid>
<author>info@preachtheword.com (Preach The Word)</author>
<category>Religion &amp; Spirituality</category>
<description>God has always wanted to dwell with humanity; but He wants a conversational relationship with us. Essentially, we're all looking for this meaningful relationship with our Creator, but usually we look in all the wrong places for false substitutes! Our inner longing to be loved and truly known is only satisfied through a deepening walk with God that is more than the casual or superficial. In this teaching from Revelation 3:14-22, David shows us the intimacy that is possible with God, what that practically means and how we might embark on that path. Can you hear Jesus knocking at your heart with 'The Greatest Invitation', drawing you into such communion? This message is available at https://www.preachtheword.com now in MP3 audio format...</description>
<pubDate>Sat, 01 Feb 2025 10:01:01 GMT</pubDate>
<itunes:duration>46:03</itunes:duration>
<itunes:explicit>false</itunes:explicit>
<enclosure url="https://audio.preachtheword.com/topical/misc0186.mp3" length="44495967" type="audio/mpeg"/>
</item>	

<item>
<title>Jesus Wants You To Know He's Alive!</title>
<link>https://www.preachtheword.com/sermon/misc0185-jesus-alive.shtml</link>
<guid>https://www.preachtheword.com/sermon/misc0185-jesus-alive.shtml</guid>
<author>info@preachtheword.com (Preach The Word)</author>
<category>Religion &amp; Spirituality</category>
<description>In Luke 24:36-43, after His resurrection, Jesus wanted to demonstrate His presence to His followers. He desired to help them to believe. Like the disciples, we all need an encounter with the risen Lord Jesus. Our God is a God of the supernatural, but often we don't recognise His presence or even attribute it to something else. This encouraging message will inspire you to engage with the risen Christ by His Spirit, for 'Jesus Wants You To Know He's Alive!'. This message is available at https://www.preachtheword.com now in MP3 audio format...</description>
<pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2025 10:01:01 GMT</pubDate>
<itunes:duration>40:01</itunes:duration>
<itunes:explicit>false</itunes:explicit>
<enclosure url="https://audio.preachtheword.com/topical/misc0185.mp3" length="38711804" type="audio/mpeg"/>
</item>	

<item>
<title>A New Ireland</title>
<link>https://www.preachtheword.com/sermon/misc0191-a-new-ireland.shtml</link>
<guid>https://www.preachtheword.com/sermon/misc0191-a-new-ireland.shtml</guid>
<author>info@preachtheword.com (Preach The Word)</author>
<category>Religion &amp; Spirituality</category>
<description>What could a New Ireland look like through 'Kingdom eyes'? So many have political visions of 'A New Ireland', but what does God want? In this message, David encourages Irish Christians to have a healthy appreciation of their history and appropriate the spiritual inheritance they have. He also calls for the church in Ireland to renounce the political and religious spirit that has been a historic problem on the island and is in ascendancy again across the Western world. David also briefly addresses the issue of Christian nationalism in our world today. This message is available at https://www.preachtheword.com now in MP3 audio format...</description>
<pubDate>Tue, 31 Dec 2024 15:01:01 GMT</pubDate>
<itunes:duration>45:10</itunes:duration>
<itunes:explicit>false</itunes:explicit>
<enclosure url="https://audio.preachtheword.com/topical/misc0191.mp3" length="35238538" type="audio/mpeg"/>
</item>	

<item>
<title>His Wonderful Name</title>
<link>https://www.preachtheword.com/sermon/misc0180-wonderful-name.shtml</link>
<guid>https://www.preachtheword.com/sermon/misc0180-wonderful-name.shtml</guid>
<author>info@preachtheword.com (Preach The Word)</author>
<category>Religion &amp; Spirituality</category>
<description>Isaiah 9 is a scripture often read at Christmas time. To a land distressed and under the shadow of death's darkness the great light of the world has shone. Christ's coming into the world has brought joy, liberty and forgiveness. 'Every name that He bears is a blessing He shares'. Be encouraged as we consider 'the Wonderful Counsellor, the Mighty God, the Everlasting Father, the Prince of Peace' - Immanuel, God with us. This message is available at https://www.preachtheword.com now in MP3 audio format...</description>
<pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2024 10:01:01 GMT</pubDate>
<itunes:duration>41:17</itunes:duration>
<itunes:explicit>false</itunes:explicit>
<enclosure url="https://audio.preachtheword.com/topical/misc0180.mp3" length="39932160" type="audio/mpeg"/>
</item>	

<item>
<title>Power Over Mind And Matter</title>
<link>https://www.preachtheword.com/sermon/misc0183-mind-matter.shtml</link>
<guid>https://www.preachtheword.com/sermon/misc0183-mind-matter.shtml</guid>
<author>info@preachtheword.com (Preach The Word)</author>
<category>Religion &amp; Spirituality</category>
<description>Generally, in the western world, we value the physical realm and ignore the spiritual. But whilst the Bible calls us to value the body as holy, it also points us to the superior nature of the spiritual and, indeed, how it can influence and determine the material world. We are spiritual beings as well as physical. We are in a spiritual war, so we must use the spiritual weapons that God has given us, which are very powerful. In 'Power Over Mind And Matter', you will learn from 2 Corinthians 10:2-5 what those spiritual weapons are and how to effectively use them for victory in your life. This message is available at https://www.preachtheword.com now in MP3 audio format...</description>
<pubDate>Fri, 15 Nov 2024 10:01:01 GMT</pubDate>
<itunes:duration>45:11</itunes:duration>
<itunes:explicit>false</itunes:explicit>
<enclosure url="https://audio.preachtheword.com/topical/misc0183.mp3" length="43672962" type="audio/mpeg"/>
</item>

<item>
<title>God's Holy Kingdom</title>
<link>https://www.preachtheword.com/sermon/misc0182-holy-kingdom.shtml</link>
<guid>https://www.preachtheword.com/sermon/misc0182-holy-kingdom.shtml</guid>
<author>info@preachtheword.com (Preach The Word)</author>
<category>Religion &amp; Spirituality</category>
<description>In 1 Corinthians 6:9-20, Paul gives a list of the sinful lifestyles that will not inherit 'God's Holy Kingdom' - we are not to be deceived! However, every 'type' of sinner can enter the kingdom of God through repentance and faith. Paul exhorts us to live up to our identity as citizens of the kingdom of God. He challenges us as to our behaviours, what influences we are under or bound by and whether or not we are filled with the Holy Spirit as God's holy temples. This message is available at https://www.preachtheword.com now in MP3 audio format...</description>
<pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2024 10:01:01 GMT</pubDate>
<itunes:duration>52:53</itunes:duration>
<itunes:explicit>false</itunes:explicit>
<enclosure url="https://audio.preachtheword.com/topical/misc0182.mp3" length="51061210" type="audio/mpeg"/>
</item>

<item>
<title>The Lord's Prayer</title>
<link>https://www.preachtheword.com/sermon/misc0181-lords-prayer.shtml</link>
<guid>https://www.preachtheword.com/sermon/misc0181-lords-prayer.shtml</guid>
<author>info@preachtheword.com (Preach The Word)</author>
<category>Religion &amp; Spirituality</category>
<description>This prayer that Jesus taught His disciples in Luke 11:1-4 also teaches us how to be 'kingdom people'. This prayer can be prayed with our lives, as we become the prayer and the answer to it. 'The Lord's Prayer' would warrant a whole series of teaching, and even that could never exhaust its depths - but here in one message, David seeks to highlight the kingdom principles that are in the will of God for us to pray for, and live out. This message is available at https://www.preachtheword.com now in MP3 audio format and in HD video on our YouTube Channel (https://youtube.com/PreachTheWord)...</description>
<pubDate>Tue, 15 Oct 2024 10:01:01 GMT</pubDate>
<itunes:duration>42:07</itunes:duration>
<itunes:explicit>false</itunes:explicit>
<enclosure url="https://audio.preachtheword.com/topical/misc0181.mp3" length="40728672" type="audio/mpeg"/>
</item>

<item>
<title>Lessons From Lepers</title>
<link>https://www.preachtheword.com/sermon/misc0179-lepers.shtml</link>
<guid>https://www.preachtheword.com/sermon/misc0179-lepers.shtml</guid>
<author>info@preachtheword.com (Preach The Word)</author>
<category>Religion &amp; Spirituality</category>
<description>This well known gospel story in Luke 17:11-19 brings many 'Lessons From Lepers' on how we can know God's healing in our lives. Join us as David outlines ten lessons from these ten lepers, and how Jesus interacts with them. Will you be one of the grateful 10% who receive the greatest blessings from God? This message is available at https://www.preachtheword.com now in MP3 audio format...</description>
<pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2024 10:01:01 GMT</pubDate>
<itunes:duration>40:00</itunes:duration>
<itunes:explicit>false</itunes:explicit>
<enclosure url="https://audio.preachtheword.com/topical/misc0179.mp3" length="38697980" type="audio/mpeg"/>
</item>

<item>
<title>Help My Unbelief</title>
<link>https://www.preachtheword.com/sermon/misc0178-help-unbelief.shtml</link>
<guid>https://www.preachtheword.com/sermon/misc0178-help-unbelief.shtml</guid>
<author>info@preachtheword.com (Preach The Word)</author>
<category>Religion &amp; Spirituality</category>
<description>Mark's record of this miracle in Mark 9:14-29 is different in some ways to Matthew's account. One very significant difference is how the father of the afflicted boy confessed his faith in Jesus' ability to heal; but he also admitted that he had unbelief in his heart too. There are many lessons to learn in this story concerning what demonic affliction can do to someone, even from childhood, and how Jesus ultimately set the boy free. However, we see one very encouraging truth in particular: though the boy's father's faith was imperfect, Jesus still honoured it and healed the boy. God answers even imperfect faith. This message is available at https://www.preachtheword.com now in MP3 audio format...</description>
<pubDate>Sun, 15 Sep 2024 10:01:01 GMT</pubDate>
<itunes:duration>37:00</itunes:duration>
<itunes:explicit>false</itunes:explicit>
<enclosure url="https://audio.preachtheword.com/topical/misc0178.mp3" length="35814473" type="audio/mpeg"/>
</item>

<item>
<title>Great Faith Of A Gentile Woman</title>
<link>https://www.preachtheword.com/sermon/misc0177-great-faith-gentile.shtml</link>
<guid>https://www.preachtheword.com/sermon/misc0177-great-faith-gentile.shtml</guid>
<author>info@preachtheword.com (Preach The Word)</author>
<category>Religion &amp; Spirituality</category>
<description>This intriguing story of the Syrophoenician woman in Matthew 15:21-31 raises many questions for us, not least how incongruent Jesus' words and behaviour seem, in contrast to what we know and love about His character and personality. Like Jesus did with the woman, this story invites us to probe deeper into its not so obvious meaning.  What is Jesus up to in this rather atypical behaviour? There are actually some precious lessons here on the nature of God revealed in Christ, the wideness of God's grace to the whole world and the type of faith that Jesus encourages us to have and responds to. This message is available at https://www.preachtheword.com now in MP3 audio format...</description>
<pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2024 10:01:01 GMT</pubDate>
<itunes:duration>35:04</itunes:duration>
<itunes:explicit>false</itunes:explicit>
<enclosure url="https://audio.preachtheword.com/topical/misc0177.mp3" length="33963360" type="audio/mpeg"/>
</item>

<item>
<title>How The Devil Gets In</title>
<link>https://www.preachtheword.com/sermon/misc0176-how-devil-gets-in.shtml</link>
<guid>https://www.preachtheword.com/sermon/misc0176-how-devil-gets-in.shtml</guid>
<author>info@preachtheword.com (Preach The Word)</author>
<category>Religion &amp; Spirituality</category>
<description>In Matthew 12:28-29, 43-45, Jesus gives us some dynamics of how the demonic realm gains influence over our lives. We need to understand this if we are to be protected. Of course, the Gospel gives us the means of freedom to get the devil out! We'll learn about that too. We see in this teaching that Jesus was talking about more than just a person's individual problems with sin and Satan, but also how whole nations and populations let the devil in. This message is available at https://www.preachtheword.com now in MP3 audio format...</description>
<pubDate>Thu, 15 Aug 2024 10:01:01 GMT</pubDate>
<itunes:duration>44:26</itunes:duration>
<itunes:explicit>false</itunes:explicit>
<enclosure url="https://audio.preachtheword.com/topical/misc0176.mp3" length="42954114" type="audio/mpeg"/>
</item>

<item>
<title>A Woman With A Spirit Of Infirmity</title>
<link>https://www.preachtheword.com/sermon/misc0172-spirit-infirmity.shtml</link>
<guid>https://www.preachtheword.com/sermon/misc0172-spirit-infirmity.shtml</guid>
<author>info@preachtheword.com (Preach The Word)</author>
<category>Religion &amp; Spirituality</category>
<description>In this miracle in Luke 13:10-17, we learn that some physical illnesses can have spiritual causes behind them. The woman in this story had to be loosed from a spirit of infirmity that she had because of something that took place in her life 18 years previously. Healing and deliverance often must come together for people to be made whole. We need to understand how the demonic can sometimes affect our health. The good news is that Jesus can still loose people from the bondage of evil spirits that bind them and debilitate their health and well-being. This message is available at https://www.preachtheword.com now in MP3 audio format...</description>
<pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2024 10:01:01 GMT</pubDate>
<itunes:duration>34:17</itunes:duration>
<itunes:explicit>false</itunes:explicit>
<enclosure url="https://audio.preachtheword.com/topical/misc0172.mp3" length="33210541" type="audio/mpeg"/>
</item>

<item>
<title>Which Report Have You Believed?</title>
<link>https://www.preachtheword.com/sermon/misc0171-report-believed.shtml</link>
<guid>https://www.preachtheword.com/sermon/misc0171-report-believed.shtml</guid>
<author>info@preachtheword.com (Preach The Word)</author>
<category>Religion &amp; Spirituality</category>
<description>Whose message are we listening to? Whose report are we believing? The press, social media, medicine, or Gods Word? What voices are we allowing to influence us, and are those voices faith-inducing or faith-reducing? Isaiah 53 is such a well-known scripture about the death of Jesus and the salvation He has purchased for us. But many have neglected that this core prophetic scripture is explicit that healing has been purchased for us at the cross of Jesus. Learn what Isaiah 53 truly teaches and then ask, 'Do you believe this report?' or, whose report are you believing? This message is available at https://www.preachtheword.com now in MP3 audio format...</description>
<pubDate>Sun, 30 Jun 2024 10:01:01 GMT</pubDate>
<itunes:duration>33:59</itunes:duration>
<itunes:explicit>false</itunes:explicit>
<enclosure url="https://audio.preachtheword.com/topical/misc0171.mp3" length="32909960" type="audio/mpeg"/>
</item>

<item>
<title>The Healing Of A Deaf And Mute Man</title>
<link>https://www.preachtheword.com/sermon/misc0170-deaf-mute.shtml</link>
<guid>https://www.preachtheword.com/sermon/misc0170-deaf-mute.shtml</guid>
<author>info@preachtheword.com (Preach The Word)</author>
<category>Religion &amp; Spirituality</category>
<description>What a predicament to be both deaf and mute - cut off from communication and the community. Here was a man who exemplified not only those with similar physical impediments but also the spiritual condition of humanity. Yet a physical healing took place for this man in a rather unconventional manner. Here, we learn how God's methods are not always reasonable to us. There is a beautiful revelation in this 'Healing Of A Deaf And Mute Man' of the unique ways God moves with each of us and how compassionate and considerate He is to us as individuals. This message is available at https://www.preachtheword.com now in MP3 audio format...</description>
<pubDate>Sat, 15 Jun 2024 10:01:01 GMT</pubDate>
<itunes:duration>35:47</itunes:duration>
<itunes:explicit>false</itunes:explicit>
<enclosure url="https://audio.preachtheword.com/topical/misc0170.mp3" length="34647902" type="audio/mpeg"/>
</item>

<item>
<title>Don't Fear, Only Believe</title>
<link>https://www.preachtheword.com/sermon/misc0169-only-believe.shtml</link>
<guid>https://www.preachtheword.com/sermon/misc0169-only-believe.shtml</guid>
<author>info@preachtheword.com (Preach The Word)</author>
<category>Religion &amp; Spirituality</category>
<description>In this story of two overlapping healings - the woman with the issue of blood and the raising of Jairus' daughter - we learn some principles of how God heals. Sometimes, we can be confused about how God does His healing work. In this account, Jesus emphasises the importance of saying 'No' to fear and only believing what God has said. Don't fear, only believe! This message is available at https://www.preachtheword.com now in MP3 audio format...</description>
<pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2024 10:01:01 GMT</pubDate>
<itunes:duration>35:47</itunes:duration>
<itunes:explicit>false</itunes:explicit>
<enclosure url="https://audio.preachtheword.com/topical/misc0169.mp3" length="34647902" type="audio/mpeg"/>
</item>

<item>
<title>The Healing Presence</title>
<link>https://www.preachtheword.com/sermon/misc0168-healing-presence.shtml</link>
<guid>https://www.preachtheword.com/sermon/misc0168-healing-presence.shtml</guid>
<author>info@preachtheword.com (Preach The Word)</author>
<category>Religion &amp; Spirituality</category>
<description>The power to save, heal and set free is God's power. In this healing story from Luke 5:17, we see God's power was present with Jesus to heal. We need to practice God's healing presence rather than the presence of sickness, darkness, Satan or sin. So often, when we face such obstacles, we focus on the problem, but the answer to our problems is never in the problem. The healing presence is where we must abide. This message is available at https://www.preachtheword.com now in MP3 audio format...</description>
<pubDate>Wed, 15 May 2024 10:01:01 GMT</pubDate>
<itunes:duration>35:19</itunes:duration>
<itunes:explicit>false</itunes:explicit>
<enclosure url="https://audio.preachtheword.com/topical/misc0168.mp3" length="34190237" type="audio/mpeg"/>
</item>

<item>
<title>God's Plan For Mental Health</title>
<link>https://www.preachtheword.com/sermon/misc0167-mental-health.shtml</link>
<guid>https://www.preachtheword.com/sermon/misc0167-mental-health.shtml</guid>
<author>info@preachtheword.com (Preach The Word)</author>
<category>Religion &amp; Spirituality</category>
<description>Mental health problems, it appears, have escalated dramatically in recent times. Does the Bible have anything to say about our minds, how we can protect them and solutions to mental ill-health? The answer is 'Yes!'. There is power in the gospel and the Word of God to heal our minds. God has given us a plan of wholeness and healing for our minds. Join us for valuable guidance from Philippians 4:6-9. This message is available at https://www.preachtheword.com now in MP3 audio format...</description>
<pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 10:01:01 GMT</pubDate>
<itunes:duration>29:24</itunes:duration>
<itunes:explicit>false</itunes:explicit>
<enclosure url="https://audio.preachtheword.com/topical/misc0167.mp3" length="28520203" type="audio/mpeg"/>
</item>

<item>
<title>Questions About Healing, Faith And Unbelief</title>
<link>https://www.preachtheword.com/sermon/misc0175-healing-faith-unbelief.shtml</link>
<guid>https://www.preachtheword.com/sermon/misc0175-healing-faith-unbelief.shtml</guid>
<author>info@preachtheword.com (Preach The Word)</author>
<category>Religion &amp; Spirituality</category>
<description>In this message on Matthew 17:14-21, David addresses some critical questions about healing and what the Bible says. Some may object to any emphasis on healing as a distraction from the gospel's central message. However, the record of the Gospels and the Acts is that healing was intrinsic to Jesus' revelation of the Father to humanity. In this teaching, learn how faith affects healing and how our unbelief can affect our faith. This message is available at https://www.preachtheword.com now in MP3 audio format...</description>
<pubDate>Sun, 14 Apr 2024 15:01:01 GMT</pubDate>
<itunes:duration>46:54</itunes:duration>
<itunes:explicit>false</itunes:explicit>
<enclosure url="https://audio.preachtheword.com/topical/misc0175.mp3" length="45319654" type="audio/mpeg"/>
</item>

<item>
<title>God's Voice And Spiritual Warfare</title>
<link>https://www.preachtheword.com/sermon/misc0174-gods-voice-warfare.shtml</link>
<guid>https://www.preachtheword.com/sermon/misc0174-gods-voice-warfare.shtml</guid>
<author>info@preachtheword.com (Preach The Word)</author>
<category>Religion &amp; Spirituality</category>
<description>Hearing the voice of God is vital for success in spiritual warfare. It is essential to learn to use the sword of the Spirit, the rhema of God, to overcome the temptations and attacks of the devil. This message from Ephesians 6:17 will teach you the importance of using the sword of the Spirit and some practical pointers on receiving words from God to take into the battle against the enemy. This message is available at https://www.preachtheword.com now in MP3 audio format...</description>
<pubDate>Fri, 15 Mar 2024 10:01:01 GMT</pubDate>
<itunes:duration>59:34</itunes:duration>
<itunes:explicit>false</itunes:explicit>
<enclosure url="https://audio.preachtheword.com/topical/misc0174.mp3" length="57474743" type="audio/mpeg"/>
</item>

<item>
<title>Elijah And The Voice Of God</title>
<link>https://www.preachtheword.com/sermon/misc0173-elijah-voice.shtml</link>
<guid>https://www.preachtheword.com/sermon/misc0173-elijah-voice.shtml</guid>
<author>info@preachtheword.com (Preach The Word)</author>
<category>Religion &amp; Spirituality</category>
<description>Elijah, the greatest of prophets, came to a personal and spiritual crisis. It may be that though he was hearing the voice of God for the nation, he hadn't been hearing it for himself. God had to take him on a journey of rehabilitation, physically, mentally, emotionally and spiritually, before he could even receive God's voice. Here is a practical message from 1 Kings 19:1-18 relevant to those experiencing burnout or a wilderness in their Christian life and service. God often has to condition us to eliminate distractions and blocks to clearly hear His still, small voice. This message is available at https://www.preachtheword.com now in MP3 audio format...</description>
<pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2024 10:01:01 GMT</pubDate>
<itunes:duration>54:21</itunes:duration>
<itunes:explicit>false</itunes:explicit>
<enclosure url="https://audio.preachtheword.com/topical/misc0173.mp3" length="52464248" type="audio/mpeg"/>
</item>

<item>
<title>The Prayer Of Jabez</title>
<link>https://www.preachtheword.com/sermon/misc0166-prayer-jabez.shtml</link>
<guid>https://www.preachtheword.com/sermon/misc0166-prayer-jabez.shtml</guid>
<author>info@preachtheword.com (Preach The Word)</author>
<category>Religion &amp; Spirituality</category>
<description>The short but direct 'Prayer Of Jabez' has been a blessing to many who have plumbed its spiritual depths and excavated its potential. Explore with us how God wants to bless us, deliver us from everything holding us in the past, enlarge our Kingdom influence and grant our petitions for His glory. This message is available at https://www.preachtheword.com now in MP3 audio format...</description>
<pubDate>Thu, 15 Feb 2024 10:01:01 GMT</pubDate>
<itunes:duration>31:20</itunes:duration>
<itunes:explicit>false</itunes:explicit>
<enclosure url="https://audio.preachtheword.com/topical/misc0166.mp3" length="30371859" type="audio/mpeg"/>
</item>

<item>
<title>Practicalities Of Prayer</title>
<link>https://www.preachtheword.com/sermon/misc0163-practicalities-prayer.shtml</link>
<guid>https://www.preachtheword.com/sermon/misc0163-practicalities-prayer.shtml</guid>
<author>info@preachtheword.com (Preach The Word)</author>
<category>Religion &amp; Spirituality</category>
<description>All of us are learners when it comes to prayer and praying better. So whilst we must beware of gimmicks and quick-fix formulae, we also must recognise some helpful disciplines of prayer - ingredients that can help us 'arrange' our prayers better. Here in 'Practicalities Of Prayer', David shares some valuable and practical pointers to refresh our prayer lives. This message is available at https://www.preachtheword.com now in MP3 audio format and in HD video on our YouTube Channel (https://youtube.com/PreachTheWord)...</description>
<pubDate>Thu, 01 Feb 2024 10:01:01 GMT</pubDate>
<itunes:duration>45:46</itunes:duration>
<itunes:explicit>false</itunes:explicit>
<enclosure url="https://audio.preachtheword.com/topical/misc0163.mp3" length="44225556" type="audio/mpeg"/>
</item>

<item>
<title>Confident Prayer</title>
<link>https://www.preachtheword.com/sermon/misc0164-confident-prayer.shtml</link>
<guid>https://www.preachtheword.com/sermon/misc0164-confident-prayer.shtml</guid>
<author>info@preachtheword.com (Preach The Word)</author>
<category>Religion &amp; Spirituality</category>
<description>Many of us struggle with the lack of answers to our prayers - but is there such a thing as praying confidently in a way that gets answers? David explores three vital ingredients to sure-to-be-answered prayer. Come and learn the importance of praying from identity, with authority and certainty as we consider 'Confident Prayer'. This message is available at https://www.preachtheword.com now in MP3 audio format and in HD video on our YouTube Channel (https://youtube.com/PreachTheWord)...</description>
<pubDate>Sun, 14 Jan 2024 18:01:01 GMT</pubDate>
<itunes:duration>38:39</itunes:duration>
<itunes:explicit>false</itunes:explicit>
<enclosure url="https://audio.preachtheword.com/topical/misc0164.mp3" length="35181895" type="audio/mpeg"/>
</item>

<item>
<title>The Shaking Of The Heavens</title>
<link>https://www.preachtheword.com/sermon/misc0165-shaking-heavens.shtml</link>
<guid>https://www.preachtheword.com/sermon/misc0165-shaking-heavens.shtml</guid>
<author>info@preachtheword.com (Preach The Word)</author>
<category>Religion &amp; Spirituality</category>
<description>In this topical message on revival, David relays some visions and dreams from God, indicating the shaking in the heavenly realm at this time in history and the need for us to be 'ready' in the day of God's power (Psalm 110:3). This message is available now from https://www.preachtheword.com in MP3 audio format...</description>
<pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 10:01:01 GMT</pubDate>
<itunes:duration>42:05</itunes:duration>
<itunes:explicit>false</itunes:explicit>
<enclosure url="https://audio.preachtheword.com/topical/misc0165.mp3" length="40690469" type="audio/mpeg"/>
</item>

<item>
<title>Jesus' Preparation For Ministry Pt3: The School Of Suffering</title>
<link>https://www.preachtheword.com/studies/ssministry.html#part3</link>
<guid>https://www.preachtheword.com/studies/ssministry.html#part3</guid>
<author>info@preachtheword.com (Preach The Word)</author>
<category>Religion &amp; Spirituality</category>
<description>The Bible tells us that Jesus learned obedience through what He suffered. Even for the perfect Son of God, there was 'The School Of Suffering' that prepared Him for ministry. As His disciples, we are called to take up our cross and suffer for Christ. We will experience the test of the wilderness and face the enemy's taunts attacking our belovedness to God. Suffering cannot be avoided as Christians. Discernment is needed to know what can be resisted and what is part of God's plan for us. One thing is sure: if we are to inherit as God's sons and daughters, we must suffer for His name. This message is available at https://www.preachtheword.com now in MP3 audio format and in HD video on our YouTube Channel (https://youtube.com/PreachTheWord)...</description>
<pubDate>Fri, 01 Dec 2023 10:10:02 GMT</pubDate>
<itunes:duration>58:52</itunes:duration>
<itunes:explicit>clean</itunes:explicit>
<enclosure url="https://audio.preachtheword.com/ministry03.mp3" length="56807375" type="audio/mpeg"/>
</item>

<item>
<title>Jesus' Preparation For Ministry Pt2: Learning To Minister From Identity</title>
<link>https://www.preachtheword.com/studies/ssministry.html#part2</link>
<guid>https://www.preachtheword.com/studies/ssministry.html#part2</guid>
<author>info@preachtheword.com (Preach The Word)</author>
<category>Religion &amp; Spirituality</category>
<description>Many of us have been conditioned by life and culture to serve to obtain identity rather than ministering from our identity in Christ. Jesus knew who He was and what the Father thought of Him; this impacted how He served God. However, many of us behave as orphans in ministry, which often ends in our own hurt and that of others. In this message on 'Learning To Minister From Identity', David teaches us to minister from identity as children of God rather than ministering from identity like orphans. This message is available at https://www.preachtheword.com now in MP3 audio format and in HD video on our YouTube Channel (https://youtube.com/PreachTheWord)...</description>
<pubDate>Wed, 15 Nov 2023 10:10:02 GMT</pubDate>
<itunes:duration>41:59</itunes:duration>
<itunes:explicit>clean</itunes:explicit>
<enclosure url="https://audio.preachtheword.com/ministry02.mp3" length="40595178" type="audio/mpeg"/>
</item>

<item>
<title>Jesus' Preparation For Ministry Pt1: From Obscurity To Prominence</title>
<link>https://www.preachtheword.com/studies/ssministry.html#1</link>
<guid>https://www.preachtheword.com/studies/ssministry.html#1</guid>
<author>info@preachtheword.com (Preach The Word)</author>
<category>Religion &amp; Spirituality</category>
<description>There is much of Jesus' early life we don't know about. We know He didn't begin His earthly ministry until around the age of 30. What did He do in those preceding years? Those years in obscurity were a vital part of 'Jesus' Preparation For Ministry'. What lessons can we learn from such obscurity and silent years? Follow Him 'From Obscurity To Prominence', as we consider this question and also the importance of Christ's baptism, holiness, obedience and His empowerment by the Spirit. This message is available at https://www.preachtheword.com now in MP3 audio format and in HD video on our YouTube Channel (https://youtube.com/PreachTheWord)...</description>
<pubDate>Wed, 01 Nov 2023 10:10:02 GMT</pubDate>
<itunes:duration>49:33</itunes:duration>
<itunes:explicit>clean</itunes:explicit>
<enclosure url="https://audio.preachtheword.com/ministry01.mp3" length="47853864" type="audio/mpeg"/>
</item>

<item>
<title>The Glorious Presence Of God Pt5: The Passionate Pursuit Of God's Glory</title>
<link>https://www.preachtheword.com/studies/ss-glorious-presence.html#5</link>
<guid>https://www.preachtheword.com/studies/ss-glorious-presence.html#5</guid>
<author>info@preachtheword.com (Preach The Word)</author>
<category>Religion &amp; Spirituality</category>
<description>We need to pursue Him passionately to experience more of 'The Glorious Presence Of God'. King David reflects this in Psalm 63, and others like Moses and Isaiah show us what it is like to hunger after and interact with God's presence. In this message, you'll hear how we must turn away from other distractions and sins to gain a greater passion for God's presence. This concluding message is available at https://www.preachtheword.com now in MP3 audio format...</description>
<pubDate>Sun, 15 Oct 2023 10:10:02 GMT</pubDate>
<itunes:duration>38:27</itunes:duration>
<itunes:explicit>clean</itunes:explicit>
<enclosure url="https://audio.preachtheword.com/glorious-presence05.mp3" length="37210168" type="audio/mpeg"/>
</item>

<item>
<title>The Glorious Presence Of God Pt4: In Immanuel</title>
<link>https://www.preachtheword.com/studies/ss-glorious-presence.html#4</link>
<guid>https://www.preachtheword.com/studies/ss-glorious-presence.html#4</guid>
<author>info@preachtheword.com (Preach The Word)</author>
<category>Religion &amp; Spirituality</category>
<description>The greatest presentation of 'The Glorious Presence Of God' was in His Son who came to this world, Immanuel, 'God with us'. We will learn how the glory of God shone through Jesus' life and how the disciples witnessed that glory on the Mount of Transfiguration. Find out how we can experience the glory of God in the face of Jesus Christ. This message is available at https://www.preachtheword.com now in MP3 audio format...</description>
<pubDate>Sun, 01 Oct 2023 10:10:02 GMT</pubDate>
<itunes:duration>48:50</itunes:duration>
<itunes:explicit>clean</itunes:explicit>
<enclosure url="https://audio.preachtheword.com/glorious-presence04.mp3" length="47178520" type="audio/mpeg"/>
</item>

<item>
<title>The Glorious Presence Of God Pt3: Its Departure</title>
<link>https://www.preachtheword.com/studies/ss-glorious-presence.html#3</link>
<guid>https://www.preachtheword.com/studies/ss-glorious-presence.html#3</guid>
<author>info@preachtheword.com (Preach The Word)</author>
<category>Religion &amp; Spirituality</category>
<description>Ezekiel tells us how 'The Glorious Presence Of God' reluctantly withdrew from the Temple in stages and eventually from the whole nation. The sins of the people had driven Him from them. This is a sobering message highlighting the need for holiness but also giving us great hope in the Saviour we have in Jesus, who brings God's presence to us through His cross. This message is available at https://www.preachtheword.com now in MP3 audio format...</description>
<pubDate>Fri, 15 Sep 2023 10:10:02 GMT</pubDate>
<itunes:duration>35:39</itunes:duration>
<itunes:explicit>clean</itunes:explicit>
<enclosure url="https://audio.preachtheword.com/glorious-presence03.mp3" length="34520180" type="audio/mpeg"/>
</item>

<item>
<title>The Glorious Presence Of God Pt2: With The Ark Of The Covenant</title>
<link>https://www.preachtheword.com/studies/ss-glorious-presence.html#2</link>
<guid>https://www.preachtheword.com/studies/ss-glorious-presence.html#2</guid>
<author>info@preachtheword.com (Preach The Word)</author>
<category>Religion &amp; Spirituality</category>
<description>The primary way 'The Glorious Presence Of God' rested among God's people in the Old Testament was in the Tabernacle and the Temple, particularly over the Ark of the Covenant. Unfortunately, the people of God came to the point in their history of taking God's presence for granted, and consequently, they lost it. Listen along as David shares some principles around reverencing the presence of God and how God's work must be done God's way to experience the power of His presence. This message is available at https://www.preachtheword.com now in MP3 audio format...</description>
<pubDate>Fri, 01 Sep 2023 10:10:02 GMT</pubDate>
<itunes:duration>56:52</itunes:duration>
<itunes:explicit>clean</itunes:explicit>
<enclosure url="https://audio.preachtheword.com/glorious-presence02.mp3" length="55230228" type="audio/mpeg"/>
</item>

<item>
<title>The Glorious Presence Of God, Part 1: In The Garden Of Eden</title>
<link>https://www.preachtheword.com/studies/ss-glorious-presence.html#1</link>
<guid>https://www.preachtheword.com/studies/ss-glorious-presence.html#1</guid>
<author>info@preachtheword.com (Preach The Word)</author>
<category>Religion &amp; Spirituality</category>
<description>In this introductory message on 'The Glorious Presence Of God', we look at the different 'kinds' of God's presence and how at times, God manifests His presence to us, particularly in times of revival. Then David focuses on God's relationship with Adam and Eve before sin entered humanity and how our sin impacts the presence of God in our lives. This message is available now from https://www.preachtheword.com in MP3 audio format...</description>
<pubDate>Tue, 15 Aug 2023 10:01:01 GMT</pubDate>
<itunes:duration>54:59</itunes:duration>
<itunes:explicit>false</itunes:explicit>
<enclosure url="https://audio.preachtheword.com/glorious-presence01.mp3" length="52918333" type="audio/mpeg"/>
</item>

<item>
<title>Risk-Takers For God</title>
<link>https://www.preachtheword.com/sermon/misc0162-risk-takers-for-god.shtml</link>
<guid>https://www.preachtheword.com/sermon/misc0162-risk-takers-for-god.shtml</guid>
<author>info@preachtheword.com (Preach The Word)</author>
<category>Religion &amp; Spirituality</category>
<description>In 1 Samuel 13:23-14:15, the story of Jonathan and his armour-bearer's daring attack against the Philistines offers us many lessons in how we can audaciously take risks for God and His Kingdom. It's this kind of boldness for God that sends shockwaves in the camp of the enemy. Join us and learn how we can become 'Risk-Takers for God'! This message is available now from https://www.preachtheword.com in MP3 audio format...</description>
<pubDate>Tue, 01 Aug 2023 10:01:01 GMT</pubDate>
<itunes:duration>40:45</itunes:duration>
<itunes:explicit>false</itunes:explicit>
<enclosure url="https://audio.preachtheword.com/topical/misc0162.mp3" length="39181895" type="audio/mpeg"/>
</item>

<item>
<title>Overcoming Adversity, Part 2: What You Need To Know</title>
<link>https://www.preachtheword.com/sermon/misc0161-overcoming-adversity.shtml</link>
<guid>https://www.preachtheword.com/sermon/misc0161-overcoming-adversity.shtml</guid>
<author>info@preachtheword.com (Preach The Word)</author>
<category>Religion &amp; Spirituality</category>
<description>In our second study in 'Overcoming Adversity', we learn 'What You Need To Know'. From the amazing Romans 8, David explains how God has given us the tools to overcome adversity. There is a special understanding that we have when we are 'in Christ' that causes us to triumph even in the worst afflictions. This comes from knowing who we are and what we have in Christ - knowing what is ahead of us in Christ; what God has purposed for us in Christ and how secure we are in Him. These keys to overcoming are available to all generations of believers whatever the current global challenges or personal trials we face. This is a message of encouragement that we all need in these days. This message is available now from https://www.preachtheword.com in MP3 audio format...</description>
<pubDate>Sat, 01 Jul 2023 10:01:01 GMT</pubDate>
<itunes:duration>59:16</itunes:duration>
<itunes:explicit>false</itunes:explicit>
<enclosure url="https://audio.preachtheword.com/topical/misc0161.mp3" length="57181895" type="audio/mpeg"/>
</item>

<item>
<title>Overcoming Adversity, Part 1: Facing Facts</title>
<link>https://www.preachtheword.com/sermon/misc0160-overcoming-adversity.shtml</link>
<guid>https://www.preachtheword.com/sermon/misc0160-overcoming-adversity.shtml</guid>
<author>info@preachtheword.com (Preach The Word)</author>
<category>Religion &amp; Spirituality</category>
<description>There is such diversity of opinion among Christians regarding suffering. This confusion often distresses people who are enduring suffering.  What is the truth then? In this message David talks candidly about the importance of 'Facing Facts' and coming to terms with the inevitability of adversity in our lives. Also, he emphasises that we need to understand how God uses adversity in our lives. Many people wonder, 'How do I know if this is something from the Devil that I need to resist or is something God is wanting me to submit to?'. David practically teaches us how to discern in our suffering and how to react appropriately to adversity. This message is available now from https://www.preachtheword.com in MP3 audio format...</description>
<pubDate>Thu, 15 Jun 2023 10:01:01 GMT</pubDate>
<itunes:duration>65:18</itunes:duration>
<itunes:explicit>false</itunes:explicit>
<enclosure url="https://audio.preachtheword.com/topical/misc0160.mp3" length="62973113" type="audio/mpeg"/>
</item>

<item>
<title>Helping Others To Freedom Pt10: Revival And Deliverance - The Bigger Picture</title>
<link>https://www.preachtheword.com/sermon/freedom10.shtml</link>
<guid>https://www.preachtheword.com/sermon/freedom10.shtml</guid>
<author>info@preachtheword.com (Preach The Word)</author>
<category>Religion &amp; Spirituality</category>
<description>In the concluding session of 'Helping Others To Freedom', we look at how the principles of personal healing and deliverance apply to whole regions, and are essentially the same principles that can prepare a region for revival awakening. This is 'Revival And Deliverance - The Bigger Picture' - God sets individuals free in order to heal and deliver the world. This session is available at https://www.preachtheword.com now in MP3 audio format and in HD video on our YouTube Channel (https://youtube.com/PreachTheWord)...</description>
<pubDate>Thu, 01 Jun 2023 10:10:02 GMT</pubDate>
<itunes:duration>21:56</itunes:duration>
<itunes:explicit>clean</itunes:explicit>
<enclosure url="https://audio.preachtheword.com/freedom10.mp3" length="21355499" type="audio/mpeg"/>
</item>

<item>
<title>Helping Others To Freedom Pt9: Practicalities And Mysteries Of Healing And Deliverance</title>
<link>https://www.preachtheword.com/sermon/freedom09.shtml</link>
<guid>https://www.preachtheword.com/sermon/freedom09.shtml</guid>
<author>info@preachtheword.com (Preach The Word)</author>
<category>Religion &amp; Spirituality</category>
<description>In Session 9 of 'Helping Others To Freedom', David addresses many practical questions that often arise around healing and deliverance, also considering some of the mysterious matters that can confuse people. This episode on 'Practicalities And Mysteries Of Healing And Deliverance' should be extremely useful for anyone engaging in prayer ministry. This session is available at https://www.preachtheword.com now in MP3 audio format and in HD video on our YouTube Channel (https://youtube.com/PreachTheWord)...</description>
<pubDate>Mon, 15 May 2023 10:10:02 GMT</pubDate>
<itunes:duration>27:55</itunes:duration>
<itunes:explicit>clean</itunes:explicit>
<enclosure url="https://audio.preachtheword.com/freedom09.mp3" length="27096169" type="audio/mpeg"/>
</item>

<item>
<title>Helping Others To Freedom Pt8: Occult, Idolatry And Freemasonry</title>
<link>https://www.preachtheword.com/sermon/freedom08.shtml</link>
<guid>https://www.preachtheword.com/sermon/freedom08.shtml</guid>
<author>info@preachtheword.com (Preach The Word)</author>
<category>Religion &amp; Spirituality</category>
<description>In Part 8 of 'Helping Others To Freedom', we learn that the demonic is an area that needs to be handled sensitively and cautiously. Yet we must also acknowledge that the demonic realm is very real and often an area of blockage to blessing in people's lives. Through this study on 'Occult, Idolatry And Freemasonry' we find out: how people can be affected by the demonic; whether or not Christians can be demonically influenced; how the enemy can get power in our lives; and how to get the freedom promised in the gospel of the Kingdom of Jesus Christ. This session is available at https://www.preachtheword.com now in MP3 audio format and in HD video on our YouTube Channel (https://youtube.com/PreachTheWord)...</description>
<pubDate>Mon, 01 May 2023 10:10:02 GMT</pubDate>
<itunes:duration>31:46</itunes:duration>
<itunes:explicit>clean</itunes:explicit>
<enclosure url="https://audio.preachtheword.com/freedom08.mp3" length="30781175" type="audio/mpeg"/>
</item>

<item>
<title>Topical Sermon: The Sunday After Easter</title>
<link>https://www.preachtheword.com/sermon/misc0159-sunday-after-easter.shtml</link>
<guid>https://www.preachtheword.com/sermon/misc0159-sunday-after-easter.shtml</guid>
<author>info@preachtheword.com (Preach The Word)</author>
<category>Religion &amp; Spirituality</category>
<description>For 'The Sunday After Easter', we visit the scenes depicted in John 20, when the risen Lord Jesus Christ appeared to His disciples. On the first occasion, Thomas is missing from the gathering and this causes doubt to rise in his heart and mind. But when Jesus appears again and speaks directly to Thomas, countering his doubts and fears, his faith is embolded to declare 'My Lord and my God!'. Join us as David Legge draws lessons from this encounter for 'The Sunday After Easter'. This message is available now from https://www.preachtheword.com in MP3 audio and on our YouTube Channel (https://youtube.com/PreachTheWord) in HD video...</description>
<pubDate>Fri, 14 Apr 2023 16:01:01 GMT</pubDate>
<itunes:duration>42:02</itunes:duration>
<itunes:explicit>false</itunes:explicit>
<enclosure url="https://audio.preachtheword.com/topical/misc0159.mp3" length="40650824" type="audio/mpeg"/>
</item>

<item>
<title>Helping Others To Freedom Pt7: Generational Iniquity And Curse</title>
<link>https://www.preachtheword.com/sermon/freedom07.shtml</link>
<guid>https://www.preachtheword.com/sermon/freedom07.shtml</guid>
<author>info@preachtheword.com (Preach The Word)</author>
<category>Religion &amp; Spirituality</category>
<description>In Part 7 of our 'Helping Others To Freedom' series, we come to the issue of 'Generational Iniquity and Curse'. Can the sins of our ancestors affect us today? Is this concept biblical? In this session, we consider what scripture teaches about the matter of generational iniquity and curse and how the death of Jesus Christ on the cross sets us free from these influences. This study is available at https://www.preachtheword.com now in MP3 audio format and in HD video on our YouTube Channel (https://youtube.com/PreachTheWord)...</description>
<pubDate>Sat, 01 Apr 2023 10:10:02 GMT</pubDate>
<itunes:duration>24:09</itunes:duration>
<itunes:explicit>clean</itunes:explicit>
<enclosure url="https://audio.preachtheword.com/freedom07.mp3" length="23474655" type="audio/mpeg"/>
</item>

<item>
<title>Helping Others To Freedom Pt6: A Case Study - Frank's Story</title>
<link>https://www.preachtheword.com/sermon/freedom06.shtml</link>
<guid>https://www.preachtheword.com/sermon/freedom06.shtml</guid>
<author>info@preachtheword.com (Preach The Word)</author>
<category>Religion &amp; Spirituality</category>
<description>In this very practical session, we look at a fictional case study, which you can do as an individual or as a group if you are following this course with others.  As 'Frank' comes to you to receive prayer for his problems, from his story, you must assess the underlying root causes of his issues and how he can receive healing and freedom. David will allow you to pause in this session and take time to consider some helpful questions which are provided for you. Then David will continue, giving some suggested answers to those questions. This exercise helps us contemplate how the principles we have been learning might be outworked in a hypothetical 'real-life' scenario. This session is available at https://www.preachtheword.com now in MP3 audio format and in HD video on our YouTube Channel (https://youtube.com/PreachTheWord)...</description>
<pubDate>Wed, 15 Mar 2023 10:10:02 GMT</pubDate>
<itunes:duration>24:32</itunes:duration>
<itunes:explicit>clean</itunes:explicit>
<enclosure url="https://audio.preachtheword.com/freedom06.mp3" length="23841600" type="audio/mpeg"/>
</item>

<item>
<title>Helping Others To Freedom Pt5: Wounds And The Healing Of The Heart</title>
<link>https://www.preachtheword.com/sermon/freedom05.shtml</link>
<guid>https://www.preachtheword.com/sermon/freedom05.shtml</guid>
<author>info@preachtheword.com (Preach The Word)</author>
<category>Religion &amp; Spirituality</category>
<description>In the fifth session of our 'Helping Others To Freedom' series, we explore 'Wounds And The Healing Of The Heart'. How do our hearts get hurt? How do these wounds set us up for both habitual sin and demonic bondage? We discuss the various sources of our woundedness and, most importantly, how we can get healing for these wounds. It is vital to distinguish wounds that need healed, from sins that need repented of, and demons that must be expelled. This session is available at https://www.preachtheword.com now in MP3 audio format and in HD video on our YouTube Channel (https://youtube.com/PreachTheWord)...</description>
<pubDate>Wed, 01 Mar 2023 10:10:02 GMT</pubDate>
<itunes:duration>31:11</itunes:duration>
<itunes:explicit>clean</itunes:explicit>
<enclosure url="https://audio.preachtheword.com/freedom05.mp3" length="30222205" type="audio/mpeg"/>
</item>

<item>
<title>Helping Others To Freedom Pt4: Soul-Ties</title>
<link>https://www.preachtheword.com/sermon/freedom04.shtml</link>
<guid>https://www.preachtheword.com/sermon/freedom04.shtml</guid>
<author>info@preachtheword.com (Preach The Word)</author>
<category>Religion &amp; Spirituality</category>
<description>In the fourth episode of our video series on 'Helping Others To Freedom', we take time to consider 'Soul-Ties' - a term that describes a heart tie in any relationship, good or bad. When these ties are bad they can exert a negative influence upon our lives, hindering us moving forward to maturity in Christ. In this session we talk about what soul-ties look like in the positive and the negative, and how to break free from such spiritual bondage in order to experience release and any healing necessary. This message is available at https://www.preachtheword.com now in MP3 audio format and in HD video on our YouTube Channel (https://youtube.com/PreachTheWord)...</description>
<pubDate>Wed, 15 Feb 2023 10:10:02 GMT</pubDate>
<itunes:duration>21:05</itunes:duration>
<itunes:explicit>clean</itunes:explicit>
<enclosure url="https://audio.preachtheword.com/freedom04.mp3" length="20536414" type="audio/mpeg"/>
</item>

<item>
<title>Helping Others To Freedom Pt3: Forgiveness</title>
<link>https://www.preachtheword.com/sermon/freedom03.shtml</link>
<guid>https://www.preachtheword.com/sermon/freedom03.shtml</guid>
<author>info@preachtheword.com (Preach The Word)</author>
<category>Religion &amp; Spirituality</category>
<description>In the third instalment of 'Helping Others To Freedom', we explore together one of the major blockages to blessing and freedom – unforgiveness. Resentment, bitterness and offense are obstacles that prevent many moving into the liberty and healing God intends for their lives. In this session we will see how unforgiveness imprisons us and can give the enemy rights to torture and torment us. We will also learn what true 'Forgiveness' is and some of the common misconceptions. Most importantly we'll give some helpful steps to move into the freedom of God's forgiveness for ourselves and toward others. This episode is available at https://www.preachtheword.com now in MP3 audio format and in HD video on our YouTube Channel (https://youtube.com/PreachTheWord)...</description>
<pubDate>Wed, 01 Feb 2023 10:10:02 GMT</pubDate>
<itunes:duration>29:16</itunes:duration>
<itunes:explicit>clean</itunes:explicit>
<enclosure url="https://audio.preachtheword.com/freedom03.mp3" length="28382402" type="audio/mpeg"/>
</item>

<item>
<title>Helping Others To Freedom Pt2: The Necessity Of Confession And Repentance</title>
<link>https://www.preachtheword.com/sermon/freedom02.shtml</link>
<guid>https://www.preachtheword.com/sermon/freedom02.shtml</guid>
<author>info@preachtheword.com (Preach The Word)</author>
<category>Religion &amp; Spirituality</category>
<description>In this series based on David Legge's book, 'Breaking Through Barriers to Blessing', we continue exploring how we can be set free from bondages of Satan and healed from wounds of the heart. This series is for people who need set free themselves, or for those who want to be used to help others into freedom. In this second session, 'The Necessity Of Confession And Repentance', David looks at the issues of sin and how confession and repentance is a necessary step toward freedom in Christ. We need to own our ungodly behaviours. If we are going to get help ourselves or help others we've got to be real with ourselves and see sin the way God sees it. This message is available at https://www.preachtheword.com now in MP3 audio format and in HD video on our YouTube Channel (https://youtube.com/PreachTheWord)...</description>
<pubDate>Sun, 15 Jan 2023 10:10:02 GMT</pubDate>
<itunes:duration>31:52</itunes:duration>
<itunes:explicit>clean</itunes:explicit>
<enclosure url="https://audio.preachtheword.com/freedom02.mp3" length="30888512" type="audio/mpeg"/>
</item>

<item>
<title>Helping Others To Freedom Pt1: Foundations And Considerations</title>
<link>https://www.preachtheword.com/sermon/freedom01.shtml</link>
<guid>https://www.preachtheword.com/sermon/freedom01.shtml</guid>
<author>info@preachtheword.com (Preach The Word)</author>
<category>Religion &amp; Spirituality</category>
<description>Join us for 'Helping Others To Freedom', a series based on David Legge's book, 'Breaking Through Barriers to Blessing'. We will explore how we can be set free from bondages of Satan and healed from wounds of the heart. This study is for people who need set free themselves, or for those who want to be used to help others into freedom. In this introductory episode, David lays down some biblical foundations and considers how freedom ministry is something the church is commissioned by Jesus to engage in today. This message is available at https://www.preachtheword.com now in MP3 audio format and in HD video on our YouTube Channel (https://youtube.com/PreachTheWord)...</description>
<pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2023 10:10:02 GMT</pubDate>
<itunes:duration>24:21</itunes:duration>
<itunes:explicit>clean</itunes:explicit>
<enclosure url="https://audio.preachtheword.com/freedom01.mp3" length="23673309" type="audio/mpeg"/>
</item>

<item>
<title>Redeeming Eve</title>
<link>https://www.preachtheword.com/sermon/misc0158-redeeming-eve.shtml</link>
<guid>https://www.preachtheword.com/sermon/misc0158-redeeming-eve.shtml</guid>
<author>info@preachtheword.com (Preach The Word)</author>
<category>Religion &amp; Spirituality</category>
<description>If the account in Judges 19 was made into a movie, it probably would have an R-18 rating or worse! It is a horrendous story of the Levite and his concubine, which displays the dire spiritual and moral state God’s people had fallen into at that time. But, what is often overlooked amid this carnage is the total and utter disregard for the humanity of the woman in the story. In this Topical message entitled 'Redeeming Eve', David looks at how Eve and womenhood has been redeemed in the New Covenant, and the place of honour that a woman - Mary - had in bearing God in flesh into our world. This radically speaks of the great value women have as God's daughters, irrespective of how culture, society or religion views them. This is a liberating message especially for women, but also carries a great challenge to men and the church in general regarding how they have treated women down through the centuries, and even to this very day. This message is available at https://www.preachtheword.com now in MP3 audio format...</description>
<pubDate>Thu, 01 Dec 2022 10:10:02 GMT</pubDate>
<itunes:duration>43:24</itunes:duration>
<itunes:explicit>clean</itunes:explicit>
<enclosure url="https://audio.preachtheword.com/topical/misc0158.mp3" length="41955600" type="audio/mpeg"/>
</item>

<item>
<title>Revival Now Pt9: A New Revival And Reform Movement</title>
<link>https://www.preachtheword.com/studies/ss-revival-now.html#part9</link>
<guid>https://www.preachtheword.com/studies/ss-revival-now.html#part9</guid>
<author>info@preachtheword.com (Preach The Word)</author>
<category>Religion &amp; Spirituality</category>
<description>In this concluding message of 'Revival Now' we see the need for 'A New Revival And Reform Movement', as David considers the difference between revival and reformation. From Matthew 9, he shares how revival is like the new wine God pours out from heaven, but the wineskins need to be fit for purpose to preserve and distribute the wine, otherwise the wine is spilled and wasted and the wineskins are ruined. God is wanting to reform the church again so that she is fit for purpose for the 'new thing' He wants to do among us. God is calling the church back to original New Testament Christianity, so therefore we must remove all obstacles in the way of this move of God. Perhaps that's part of what this current shaking in the church is all about? This message is available at https://www.preachtheword.com now in MP3 audio format...</description>
<pubDate>Tue, 15 Nov 2022 10:10:02 GMT</pubDate>
<itunes:duration>39:00</itunes:duration>
<itunes:explicit>clean</itunes:explicit>
<enclosure url="https://audio.preachtheword.com/revival-now09.mp3" length="37728354" type="audio/mpeg"/>
</item>

<item>
<title>Revival Now Pt8: A New Disciple-Making Movement</title>
<link>https://www.preachtheword.com/studies/ss-revival-now.html#part8</link>
<guid>https://www.preachtheword.com/studies/ss-revival-now.html#part8</guid>
<author>info@preachtheword.com (Preach The Word)</author>
<category>Religion &amp; Spirituality</category>
<description>Along with preceding prayer, the next most common external feature of historic revivals is probably the preaching of the gospel.  Renewal in the church may not necessarily feature many souls being saved but revival certainly does.  In Part 8 of his 'Revival Now' series, David Legge emphasises the need for the preaching of the gospel of the kingdom in Holy Spirit power.  We need to get back to preaching the good news of Jesus with passion and urgency.  However, public preaching is only a part of what it means to spread the gospel; David also exhorts that we must be making disciples. He shares how simple disciple-making movements are spreading the flame of revival in some of the most persecuted countries on the planet and how this might well be a divine blueprint for us in the West to follow. This message is available at https://www.preachtheword.com now in MP3 audio format...</description>
<pubDate>Tue, 01 Nov 2022 10:10:02 GMT</pubDate>
<itunes:duration>38:35</itunes:duration>
<itunes:explicit>clean</itunes:explicit>
<enclosure url="https://audio.preachtheword.com/revival-now08.mp3" length="37330869" type="audio/mpeg"/>
</item>

<item>
<title>Revival Now Pt7: A New Christlike Movement</title>
<link>https://www.preachtheword.com/studies/ss-revival-now.html#part7</link>
<guid>https://www.preachtheword.com/studies/ss-revival-now.html#part7</guid>
<author>info@preachtheword.com (Preach The Word)</author>
<category>Religion &amp; Spirituality</category>
<description>Can we have a move of God that doesn't resemble Christ? Obviously not, but is Christ-likeness our emphasis in the church and as individuals? Do we look like Jesus? Do we sound like Jesus? In Part 7 of 'Revival Now', David Legge, using two fruit of the Spirit - Gentleness and Kindness - shows that what the church and the world most needs are Christians that look like Christ and exhibit His attributes to all, even our enemies. We will see real change in the church and society when people see Jesus in us through 'A New Christlike Movement'. This message is available at https://www.preachtheword.com now in MP3 audio format...</description>
<pubDate>Sat, 15 Oct 2022 10:10:02 GMT</pubDate>
<itunes:duration>42:10</itunes:duration>
<itunes:explicit>clean</itunes:explicit>
<enclosure url="https://audio.preachtheword.com/revival-now07.mp3" length="40775261" type="audio/mpeg"/>
</item>

<item>
<title>Revival Now Pt6: A New Unity Movement</title>
<link>https://www.preachtheword.com/studies/ss-revival-now.html#part6</link>
<guid>https://www.preachtheword.com/studies/ss-revival-now.html#part6</guid>
<author>info@preachtheword.com (Preach The Word)</author>
<category>Religion &amp; Spirituality</category>
<description>In Part 6 of 'Revival Now' we see our need for 'A New Unity Movement'. If scriptures like Psalm 133 and the High Priestly prayer of Jesus in John 17 put such a high value on unity as a key to blessing, why is it so elusive in Christianity? David suggests two reasons for this: first, the devil's agenda at all costs to divide and conquer, and second, our fear of false unity. In this message, David considers what false unity is and also why we should not be afraid of true unity in Spirit and in truth. One thing is certain, God wants the body of Christ everywhere to be united for His Kingdom cause. If that much is clear, what difference should that make to our attitudes to others and our behaviours? This message is available at https://www.preachtheword.com now in MP3 audio format...</description>
<pubDate>Sat, 01 Oct 2022 10:10:02 GMT</pubDate>
<itunes:duration>47:20</itunes:duration>
<itunes:explicit>clean</itunes:explicit>
<enclosure url="https://audio.preachtheword.com/revival-now06.mp3" length="45736446" type="audio/mpeg"/>
</item>

<item>
<title>Revival Now Pt5: A New Word and Spirit Movement</title>
<link>https://www.preachtheword.com/studies/ss-revival-now.html#part5</link>
<guid>https://www.preachtheword.com/studies/ss-revival-now.html#part5</guid>
<author>info@preachtheword.com (Preach The Word)</author>
<category>Religion &amp; Spirituality</category>
<description>Very often in some streams of Christianity there is an emphasis upon the Word of God, as opposed to the Spirit of God, or vice versa. At times these strands are even in contention with each other. This is not the way New Testament Christianity is meant to be.  It should not be a case of 'either or' but 'both and' as regards the Word and the Holy Spirit. In Part 5 of our 'Revival Now' series, David explores this disparity and how we desperately need a new movement of the Word and the Spirit: The Word with the Spirit - not the Word without the Spirit; and the Spirit with the Word - not the Spirit without the Word. There is great power when the Word and the Spirit are together. Join us for this challenging exhortation, which is available at https://www.preachtheword.com now in MP3 audio format...</description>
<pubDate>Thu, 15 Sep 2022 10:10:02 GMT</pubDate>
<itunes:duration>43:07</itunes:duration>
<itunes:explicit>clean</itunes:explicit>
<enclosure url="https://audio.preachtheword.com/revival-now05.mp3" length="41705244" type="audio/mpeg"/>
</item>

<item>
<title>Revival Now Pt4: A New Freedom Movement</title>
<link>https://www.preachtheword.com/studies/ss-revival-now.html#part4</link>
<guid>https://www.preachtheword.com/studies/ss-revival-now.html#part4</guid>
<author>info@preachtheword.com (Preach The Word)</author>
<category>Religion &amp; Spirituality</category>
<description>The church very often cannot receive the message of revival because it is so bound. Like Lazarus, the church may be 'alive', but spiritually bound. Many Christians as individuals are in this position and need deliverance and freedom. In Part 4 of 'Revival Now', David talks about how we can be set free as individuals, and the incredible impact that one soul saved and set free can have, even on a whole community.  We need to rediscover the message of freedom in the Gospel of the Kingdom.  We need 'A New Freedom Movement'! This message is available at https://www.preachtheword.com now in MP3 audio format...</description>
<pubDate>Thu, 01 Sep 2022 10:10:02 GMT</pubDate>
<itunes:duration>51:27</itunes:duration>
<itunes:explicit>clean</itunes:explicit>
<enclosure url="https://audio.preachtheword.com/revival-now04.mp3" length="49679474" type="audio/mpeg"/>
</item>

<item>
<title>Revival Now Pt3: A New Holiness Movement</title>
<link>https://www.preachtheword.com/studies/ss-revival-now.html#part3</link>
<guid>https://www.preachtheword.com/studies/ss-revival-now.html#part3</guid>
<author>info@preachtheword.com (Preach The Word)</author>
<category>Religion &amp; Spirituality</category>
<description>In Part 3 of 'Revival Now', we ask: what is the holiness that we are called to as Christians? It has been misrepresented and misunderstood by many in the church. In this message, David first establishes what holiness is not and then goes on to consider what is this holiness and most importantly how do we get it? In a day when sin and compromise is rampant in the church, we need 'A New Holiness Movement'. In 2021 we need a revival in true holiness. This message is available at https://www.preachtheword.com now in MP3 audio format...</description>
<pubDate>Mon, 15 Aug 2022 10:10:02 GMT</pubDate>
<itunes:duration>48:27</itunes:duration>
<itunes:explicit>clean</itunes:explicit>
<enclosure url="https://audio.preachtheword.com/revival-now03.mp3" length="46804992" type="audio/mpeg"/>
</item>

<item>
<title>Revival Now Pt2: A New Prayer Movement</title>
<link>https://www.preachtheword.com/studies/ss-revival-now.html#part2</link>
<guid>https://www.preachtheword.com/studies/ss-revival-now.html#part2</guid>
<author>info@preachtheword.com (Preach The Word)</author>
<category>Religion &amp; Spirituality</category>
<description>In Part 2 of 'Revival Now' as we contemplate the type of revival we might need in our day, David now considers how we need 'A New Prayer Movement'. What kind of praying is needed for revival? In this age of innovation, what 'old paths' of prayer might we need to rediscover in what God is doing anew? Be inspired to pray for revival through this message! This message is available at https://www.preachtheword.com now in MP3 audio format...</description>
<pubDate>Sun, 31 Jul 2022 17:10:02 GMT</pubDate>
<itunes:duration>50:25</itunes:duration>
<itunes:explicit>clean</itunes:explicit>
<enclosure url="https://audio.preachtheword.com/revival-now02.mp3" length="48696866" type="audio/mpeg"/>
</item>

<item>
<title>Revival Now Pt1: A New Jesus Movement</title>
<link>https://www.preachtheword.com/studies/ss-revival-now.html#part1</link>
<guid>https://www.preachtheword.com/studies/ss-revival-now.html#part1</guid>
<author>info@preachtheword.com (Preach The Word)</author>
<category>Religion &amp; Spirituality</category>
<description>In 'Revival Now', David Legge asks and seeks to answer the question: What might revival look like in the 2020s? Or, to consider it another way: What is the revival we need for today? Of course, there are common features to every revival, and yet there are always distinctives to every one. We can never second guess God in how He will move again - yet we do have desperate needs in our age that only God can meet. In this series, David looks at how we need a new move of God's Spirit to meet the contemporary needs in the church and our world in this present moment. In Part 1, we explore how the church and we as Christians need to get our focus back on Jesus. He must be the pre-eminent one and the centre of all we do and are. What idols have distracted us from the centrality of Christ? How can we give our Lord His rightful place in our lives and churches? This message is available at https://www.preachtheword.com now in MP3 audio format...</description>
<pubDate>Fri, 01 Jul 2022 10:10:02 GMT</pubDate>
<itunes:duration>32:47</itunes:duration>
<itunes:explicit>clean</itunes:explicit>
<enclosure url="https://audio.preachtheword.com/revival-now01.mp3" length="31756958" type="audio/mpeg"/>
</item>

</channel>
</rss>
